<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://kaufie.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://kaufie.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-05T11:13:31+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/feed.xml</id><subtitle>Sasha Kaufmann's profile website and article archive.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Power Broker by Robert A. Caro</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/the-power-broker-by-robert-a-caro" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Power Broker by Robert A. Caro" /><published>2021-04-05T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-04-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/the-power-broker-by-robert-a-caro</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/the-power-broker-by-robert-a-caro">&lt;p&gt;How the unelected Robert Moses built an empire of public authorities that gave him the power to defy Mayors, Governors and a President. The power to shape New York to his own will, which became the end unto itself. This book is a masterpiece; it speaks to Caro’s genius that pages and pages on politics, the passing of bills and construction can read ‘almost’ like a thriller. It’s heavy going but provides an outstanding insight into how Moses began to appreciate the need for power in order to get things done, and how that power corrupts.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-idealist&quot;&gt;The idealist&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After losing his job, having not made his dreams a reality “… idealism was gone from the stage.  In its place was an understanding that ideas – dreams – were useless without power to transform them into reality.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-reformer&quot;&gt;The reformer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working to reform the civil service, encounters subversive but not open opposition from the authorities. Delay tactics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rise-to-power&quot;&gt;Rise to power&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving from being theoretical (forward thinking ideas) to practical (getting things done, compromise). Under Mrs Moskowitz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relationship with Al Smith, another remarkable character. Coming from poverty, becoming a champion of reform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He became a creature of the machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Misleading and underestimating, in fact, might be the only way to get a project started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Systems Thinking example. Moses’ bridges were intended to alleviate traffic problems but saw increased traffic and led to new congestion. New bridges were built but it continued to get worse. p519.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“By dumping a tremendous new load on the long island parkways, the Bronx Whitestone bridge made the traffic tie-ups on the noticeably worse.“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quotes&quot;&gt;Quotes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“One must wait until the evening, to see how beautiful the day has been” - Sophocles&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As long as you’re on the side of parks, you’re on the side of the angels. You can’t lose.“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Once you sync that first stake, they’ll never make you pull it up“.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hospitality has always been a potent political weapon. Moses used it like a master. Coupled with his overpowering personality, a buffet often did as much for a proposal as a bribe.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Science, knowledge, logic and brilliance might be useful tools but they didn’t build highways or civil service systems. Power built highways and civil service systems. Power was what dreams needed, not power in the hand of the dreamer himself necessarily but power put behind the dreamer’s dream by the man who it to put there, power that he termed “executive support”.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Used in Albany “You can get an awful lot done in the world if you’re willing to let someone else take the credit for it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Politics is a thieves game. Those who stay in it long enough are invariably robbed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bob Moses had learned what was needed to make dreams become realities. He had learned the lesson of power. And now he grabbed for power with both hands. To free his hands for the grab, he shook impatiently from them the last crumbs of the principles with which he had entered public service and for which, during his years of idealism, he had fought so hard.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“…his success in public relations had been due primarily to his masterful utilization of a single public relations technique: identifying himself with a popular cause. This technique was especially advantageous to him because his philosophy–that accomplishment, Getting Things Done, is the only thing that matters, that the end justifies any means, however ruthless–might not be universally popular. By keeping the public eye focused on the cause, the end, the ultimate benefit to be obtained, the technique kept the public eye from focusing on the methods by which the method was to be obtained.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="politics" /><category term="biography" /><summary type="html">How the unelected Robert Moses built an empire of public authorities that gave him the power to defy Mayors, Governors and a President. The power to shape New York to his own will, which became the end unto itself. This book is a masterpiece; it speaks to Caro’s genius that pages and pages on politics, the passing of bills and construction can read ‘almost’ like a thriller. It’s heavy going but provides an outstanding insight into how Moses began to appreciate the need for power in order to get things done, and how that power corrupts.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-power-broker.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-power-broker.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The picture of Dorian Grey by Oscar Wilde</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/picture-of-dorian-grey-by-oscar-wilde" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The picture of Dorian Grey by Oscar Wilde" /><published>2021-04-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-04-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/picture-of-dorian-grey-by-oscar-wilde</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/picture-of-dorian-grey-by-oscar-wilde">&lt;p&gt;This wasn’t for me. The first half was tedious. Rich 19th century men swanning about, bitching and fawning. It only starts to get interesting around the middle with Sibyl Vane’s suicide and Dorian’s callousness. The book seems to improve just as Dorian’s soul and painting deteriorates. Not enough for me to give this much of a recommendation though.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="fiction" /><category term="classic" /><summary type="html">This wasn’t for me. The first half was tedious. Rich 19th century men swanning about, bitching and fawning. It only starts to get interesting around the middle with Sibyl Vane’s suicide and Dorian’s callousness. The book seems to improve just as Dorian’s soul and painting deteriorates. Not enough for me to give this much of a recommendation though.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-dorian-grey.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-dorian-grey.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Chesterton’s fence</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/chestertons-fence" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chesterton’s fence" /><published>2021-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/chestertons-fence</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/chestertons-fence">&lt;p&gt;The Chesterton’s Fence principle is: &lt;b&gt;Before you make any rash reforms, understand why decisions were made in the first place.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve slipped into this trap before. When helping organisations develop new ways of working, it’s tempting to jump right in with improvements and experiments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chesterton’s Fence is a reminder to look deeper first. I’ve never found anything to prevent change, but understanding past decisions provides a firm foundation for the work to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term comes from Gilbert Chesterton, an English writer and philosopher. In his 1929 work ‘&lt;i&gt;The Thing&lt;/i&gt;’ he describes a reformer coming up against an institution or law and compares it to a fence or gate erected across a road: &lt;i&gt;“The more modern type of reformer goes gaily up to it and says, “I don’t see the use of this; let us clear it away.” To which the more intelligent type of reformer will do well to answer: “If you don’t see the use of it, I certainly won’t let you clear it away. Go away and think. Then, when you can comeback and tell me that you do see the use of it, I may allow you to destroy it.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point is that if you don’t understand why something was put in place and only look superficially, you may miss second or third order effects. Of course this sounds obvious but it’s often ignored as we rush ahead, assume we know better or don’t look before we leap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example. You’re starting a new job. Eager and capable of spotting things that can be improved, you want to prove yourself. As tempting as it is to jump in, it’s wise to observe and seek to understand the whole system &lt;i&gt;before&lt;/i&gt; making changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Management structures are a typical example of Chesterton’s fence. Without doubt they can be convoluted and unnecessary, but many organisations that get flattened go on to re-create them. It turns out they’re useful; for decision making, to provide clear and manageable communication channels and for supporting employees. Examples of lessons come from Google, Zappos, Medium and Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As systems get more complex, so do the effects of changes we make. The environment provides a couple of examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the American West’s prevention of small wildfires leading to less frequent but much bigger more damaging fires.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a Chinese campaign to kill Sparrows to increase grain yields that actually decreased them since Sparrows eat a large amount of insects as well as the grains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Failure to spot second order effects can be catastrophic. So what can we do to improve our own decision making? Remember to avoid assumptions, to observe more, ask more questions and really understand past decisions before moving ahead. Returning to my own experience, even things that are seemingly just plain wrong warrant time to ensure you know why they’re being done. Either you’ll be justified in the reform, discover and avert a hidden consequence, or simply learn something that lends weight to what you’re proposing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should applaud challengers, reformers and innovators. Chesterton’s fence isn’t about halting change, it’s about learning. We should all take the time to understand previous decisions and the implications of reversing them before making new ones.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="agile" /><category term="agility" /><category term="agile" /><category term="improvement" /><category term="leadership" /><summary type="html">Understand second order effects and strengthen your proposals.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/post-chestertons-fence.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/post-chestertons-fence.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Pale Fire by Vladimir Nabokov</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/pale-fire-by-vladimir-nabokov" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pale Fire by Vladimir Nabokov" /><published>2021-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/pale-fire-by-vladimir-nabokov</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/pale-fire-by-vladimir-nabokov">&lt;p&gt;Extraordinary. The poet John Shade is dead. This book is a commentary on his last poem which has been edited and published by his friend(?), neighbour and fellow academic Charles Kinbote. Kinbote claims to be from a land called Zembla and progressively reveals more than he’d like. He weaves in a story of revolution and a King’s escape; he’s narcissistic, fantastical, but is he deranged? By the end you’re unsure what to believe. That’s the beauty of it; like an Escher painting as you get closer it doesn’t have a neat beginning and end. There are many layers and the genius of the writing frequently made me smile or laugh out loud; it’s funny, deadpan and descriptive in ingenious ways. An outstanding work.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few excerpts where the comedy and flair of writing made me smile:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“A comfortable burp told me he had a flask of brandy concealed about his warmly coated person.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Physically, he was a sickly baldheaded man resembling a pallid gland. His face was singularly featureless”.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Let no insurance firm or airline use this insigne on the glossy page of a magazine as an ad badge under the picture of a retired businessman stupefied and honoured by the sight of the technicolored snack that the air hostess offers him with everything else she can give“.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“..fairly panting with animal pleasure.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“His lips moving like wrestling worms.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="fiction" /><category term="poetry" /><category term="classic" /><summary type="html">Extraordinary. The poet John Shade is dead. This book is a commentary on his last poem which has been edited and published by his friend(?), neighbour and fellow academic Charles Kinbote. Kinbote claims to be from a land called Zembla and progressively reveals more than he’d like. He weaves in a story of revolution and a King’s escape; he’s narcissistic, fantastical, but is he deranged? By the end you’re unsure what to believe. That’s the beauty of it; like an Escher painting as you get closer it doesn’t have a neat beginning and end. There are many layers and the genius of the writing frequently made me smile or laugh out loud; it’s funny, deadpan and descriptive in ingenious ways. An outstanding work.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-pale-fire.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-pale-fire.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Flaw of Averages by Sam L. Savage</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/the-flaw-of-averages-by-sam-savage" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Flaw of Averages by Sam L. Savage" /><published>2021-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/the-flaw-of-averages-by-sam-savage</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/the-flaw-of-averages-by-sam-savage">&lt;p&gt;A book on assessing risk in the face of uncertainty, focussing as the title suggests on how not to assess it. The author is quirky and he makes up for the dryness of the subject by packing the chapters with examples and analogies; he’s funny (occasionally). I didn’t find anything drastically new but it was a good refresher; I took lots of notes.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;”The only certainty is that nothing is certain”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;foundations&quot;&gt;Foundations&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Flaw of averages: Plans based on average assumptions are wrong on average.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The statistician who drowned whilst fording a river that was, on average, only three feet deep. (cartoon by Jeff Danziger)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Towards the start of the book gives the example of people leaving work to get home, how often will we get home in time to leave by 6pm. That with even 1+ more people (dependencies) the chances rapidly decrease.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The phrase “Give me a number” is a dependable leading indicator of an encounter with the Flaw of Averages. &lt;strong&gt;You need a range!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Patrick Leach in a book called Why Can’t You Just Give Me a Number? points out that “once a value is generated, put down on paper, and incorporated into the business plan, it becomes gospel.”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Regression analysis with single data points are bound to mislead. Example, future growth of housing values.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Monte Carlo Simulation
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The thing you do before climbing a ladder to paint your house is to give it a good shake. By bombarding it with random physical forces, you simulate how stable the ladder will be when you climb it. You can then adjust accordingly so as to minimise the risk that it falls down with you on it.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Test stability of uncertain business plans etc.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Input probability distribution - the shaking forces applied to the ladder.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Output probability distribution - the movements of the ladder.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Developed as part of the Manhattan Project.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Simulation does for uncertainty what a lightbulb does for darkness.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Most managers have no idea how to generate Input probability distribution.
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;scenario libraries exist - repositories on corporate intelligence on uncertainty.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;You cannot add the results of simulations - you must simulate the whole thing together (eg. 2 ladders joined). You need collaboration internally in organisations to do this!&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Models
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The Wright Brothers’ first model was a bicycle inner tube box.
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Models were key to their success.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The most important models are like embryos that may not resemble the final product but nonetheless contain the developmental necessities of the application (DNA).&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“All Models are wrong, some models are useful” - George Box
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;e.g. Isaac Newton’s models of physical motion were superseded by relativistic models of Einstein. But Newton built the foundations from which Einstein started.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“You are allowed to lie a little, but you must never mislead” - Paul Halmos
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Models do not represent the entire truth, but they should lead to the truth.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“A successful model tells you things you didn’t tell it to tell you”. - Jerry P. Brashear
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;model the things you don’t understand rather than that which you do.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Knuth’s 5 stages of model development
            &lt;ol&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Decide what you want the model to do.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Decide how to build the model.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Build the model.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Debug the model.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Trash stages 1 through 4 and start again, now that you know what you really wanted in the first place.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ol&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;To get a large model to work, you must start with a small model that works, not a large model that doesn’t work.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“Far better an approximate answer to the right question, which is often vague, than the exact answer to the wrong question, which can always be made precise.” - John W. Tukey&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“The single biggest problem in communication is the illusion that it has taken place” - George Bernard Shaw&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;concepts-mindles-are-handles-for-uncertainty&quot;&gt;Concepts (mindles are ‘handles’ for uncertainty)&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mindle1: Uncertainty vs risk
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Risk is in the eye of the beholder. It’s relative.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Risk reflects how uncertain outcomes cause loss or injury to a particular individual or group.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Risk attitude (utility theory) is the willingness to incur risk in the quest of reward.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mindle 2: An uncertain number is a shape
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Random variable = uncertain number … a shape - a distribution.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;A histogram is a nice way to view probability distribution.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Bosses should be asking for distributions rather than numbers.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The cumulative distribution shows the probability that the number is less than a given value.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The average also known as the mean, or expected value, of the uncertain number is the balance point of the distribution.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Black Swans; events that 1) never had occurred before, 2) would have an extreme impact if it did occur and 3) is easy to explain after the fact are obviously not included in the distribution.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The median is the quantity that the uncertain number has a 50/50 chance of being greater than or less than. Not always the same as the average… Warren Buffet joining a room effect on average wealth example.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The mode is the place at which the histogram has its highest peak.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mindle 3: Combinations of uncertain numbers
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;A combination of uncertain numbers is a shape that goes up in the middle.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;This effect arises from diversification.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;When enough independent uncertain numbers are added together, the resulting distribution becomes bell-shaped.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Diversification reduces the chance of extreme outcomes. Dice example, Spinners, investment example.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;central limit theorem = diversification.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;normal distribution = bell-shaped distribution.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Use:
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Histogram&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Cumulative graph&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Percentiles&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Variation&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Don’t use:
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Sigma or standard deviation or variance measure how wide the distribution of an uncertain number is. Look at its shape, the wider the distribution the greater the possible variation and the higher the Sigma and the variance.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mindle 4: Terri Dial and the Drunk in the Road
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“Consider a drunk staggering down the middle of a busy highway and assume that his average position is the centreline. Then the state of the drunk at his average position is alive, but on average he’s dead”.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The strong form of the flaw of averages states that average or expected inputs don’t always result in average or expected outputs.
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;You can limit downside to making a loss by simply shutting.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mindle 5: Interrelated uncertainties
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Knee-jerk reaction is to reject petroleum and airlines because the elements are interrelated. The correct knee-jerk reaction is to reject portfolios whose interrelations are direct (or positive). Eg two airline stocks will be positively correlated, they will likely tank together. Whereas when petroleum goes down it’s good for airlines.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inverse&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;negative&lt;/strong&gt; interactions reduce uncertainty, and the name for an investment added to a portfolio for this purpose is a hedge.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Scatter plots are the best way to grasp the interrelationships between uncertain numbers.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Uncertain numbers may be related to themselves over time… e.g.
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Interest rates high over a period of time are more likely to go down.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;decisions-and-information&quot;&gt;Decisions and information&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If information can’t impact a decision, it’s worthless.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;People aren’t rational.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Decision trees
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;What chance of the uncertain event would make you change your decision? It is hard to arrive at a firm probability but easier to agree on whether it’s greater or less than a given probability.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The value of information&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;the-sins-of-averaging&quot;&gt;The sins of averaging&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The family with 1.5 children. &lt;strong&gt;Often the average scenario is nonexistent.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Why everything is behind schedule. Setting each task at its average results in project completion in 6 months, but the chance that all ten come in at their average or sooner is the same as flipping ten heads in a row, so the chance of finishing by 6 months is less than one in a thousand.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;**The egg basket. **diversification; ten eggs in the same basket as opposed to   one each in separate baskets. If there’s a 10 percent chance of dropping a basket the average of is coming away with 9 eggs, however in the first you’ve got 10 percent chance of loosing all your eggs whereas in the second you have a one in 10,000,000,000 of losing all the eggs.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The risk of ranking.&lt;/strong&gt; Portfolio theory is based on the interdependence of investments, so simply a best to worst ranking won’t do. Fire insurance seems a bad investment as on average it looses money. But it doesn’t look that way if you’ve got a house to go with it.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ignoring restrictions.&lt;/strong&gt; Beware of a downside without an associated upside. Average profit will be less than associated average demand.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ignoring optionality&lt;/strong&gt;. Find upside without associated downside. Gas production can stop if the price drops too low, limiting downside.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The double whammy&lt;/strong&gt;. The cost associated with average demand is zero, but average cost is positive because demand is never average.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The flaw of extremes&lt;/strong&gt;. In bottom up budgeting, reporting the 90th percentile of cash needs leads to ever thicker layers of unnecessary cash as the figures are rolled up to higher levels.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The smaller the sample size, the greater the variability of the average of that sample. Highest average ear lobe size and lowest average as found in small towns.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Sandbagging is when budgets are inflated to numbers that individuals are sure they won’t exceed (90th percentile). When independent uncertainties are added together, diversification causes the distribution to get relatively narrower. In the case of budgeting, this is a waste, the CEO doesn’t need that level of certainty.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simpson’s paradox&lt;/strong&gt;. Can you imagine a nutritional supplement that on average causes people to loose weight?
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Occurs when variables depend on hidden dimensions in the data.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Scholtes revenue fallacy&lt;/strong&gt;. Suppose you sell different quantities of various types of product, each with it’s own profit per unit. You might make a nice profit on your average product but a loss overall. You need to take account of statistical relationships.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taking credit for chance occurrences&lt;/strong&gt;. Some success may be due to dumb luck.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;applications&quot;&gt;Applications&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Finance
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Portfolio modelling&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Options&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;hot-button-issues&quot;&gt;Hot button issues&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Statistical Research Group of WW2&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Probability and the War On Terror&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Climate Change&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Health Care&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sex and the central limit theorem&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;probability-management&quot;&gt;Probability Management&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="probability" /><category term="statistics" /><category term="business" /><summary type="html">A book on assessing risk in the face of uncertainty, focussing as the title suggests on how not to assess it. The author is quirky and he makes up for the dryness of the subject by packing the chapters with examples and analogies; he’s funny (occasionally). I didn’t find anything drastically new but it was a good refresher; I took lots of notes.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-flaw-of-averages.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-flaw-of-averages.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Brave New World by Aldous Huxley</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/brave-new-world-by-aldous-huxley" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Brave New World by Aldous Huxley" /><published>2021-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/brave-new-world-by-aldous-huxley</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/brave-new-world-by-aldous-huxley">&lt;p&gt;A very different dystopia from the brutal totalitarianism of 1984. A civilisation where everything is stable and happiness is only a pill away. There’s little disease and hunger, pleasure is on tap yet there’s also no real intimacy. A ‘savage’ visits and learns that this world is empty and superficial. It’s an interesting future and despite feeling like the characters weren’t much developed it was a readable book. But I found it unsatisfying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this world either we’ve got savagery, pain and suffering or empty superficial lives of pleasure and consumerism. The book paints an ‘either-or’ picture which didn’t resonate with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huxley himself said more than a decade later that there should have been a middle ground. It’s insufficient to merely have the choice of embracing suffering or rejecting a life of meaning. The world is not that simple and clearly the more comfortable your position in life, the easier it is to decry the boredom of a stable society where all basic needs are met. He never clearly states that the ‘civilisation’ is worse than the savagery, but I felt it was implied weakly and if there was a philosophical point it wasn’t properly developed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huxley looks prophetic given the book’s echos of the consumerist society we live in today (it was just emerging at the time he wrote it) and the superficiality of our social media culture. People will see what they want to in this and make all sorts of comparisons (after all, it’s natural to see patterns); not a bad thing. Still a good book but if you’re only going to read one dystopian classic then make it 1984.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;World State’s motto: Community, Identity, Stability.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Barbaric things for the ‘collective good’.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hatcheries farm embryos. Depriving of foetuses of oxygen to lower intelligence. Epsilons, the lower caste. Manipulating embryos according to the job they’ll be doing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conditioning: making people grateful for their unescapable social destiny.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;God is “Our Ford”. Signing of the model “T”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Everybody belongs to everybody else”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No real intimacy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;John the Savage, disappointed with this Brave New World (Shakespeare).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bernard Marx enjoys superficial favour whilst he has his guest. He’s quite a pathetic character. Different, curious, intelligent but also vain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being sent to an island, such as Iceland, is the punishment. Yet it’s where all the interesting people are. Marx doesn’t appreciate this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People conditioned to hate solitude.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stability of civilisation is the reason for all these measures; hatcheries, breeding, conventions, soma (drug).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The savage; “But I don’t want comfort. I want God, I want poetry, I want real danger, I want freedom, I want goodness. I want sin.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="fiction" /><category term="classics" /><category term="dystopian" /><summary type="html">A very different dystopia from the brutal totalitarianism of 1984. A civilisation where everything is stable and happiness is only a pill away. There’s little disease and hunger, pleasure is on tap yet there’s also no real intimacy. A ‘savage’ visits and learns that this world is empty and superficial. It’s an interesting future and despite feeling like the characters weren’t much developed it was a readable book. But I found it unsatisfying.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-brave-new-world.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-brave-new-world.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Modern delivery principles for complex work</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/modern-delivery-principles-for-complex-work" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Modern delivery principles for complex work" /><published>2021-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/modern-delivery-principles-for-complex-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/modern-delivery-principles-for-complex-work">&lt;h2 id=&quot;values-guide-behaviours-we-choose-these&quot;&gt;Values guide behaviours. We choose these.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These values are correlated with successful delivery and motivated people in modern enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People&lt;/strong&gt; come first. Creating an environment where they have safety to be open, to be human and where communication between individuals and teams is effective is a moral obligation and leads to better business results.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning and improvement&lt;/strong&gt; should be part of daily work for people, process and product. It will bring innovation, continuous improvement and fulfilment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Constant &lt;strong&gt;connection to the customer&lt;/strong&gt; should be maintained for rapid, frequent feedback. External and internal. So we can understand their needs, respond to them and continually improve that response to move towards the best possible outcome.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flow&lt;/strong&gt; of customer value delivered continuously. When flow of value is accounted for in organisation design and the way work is broken down and delivered, it means faster value realisation, decreased risk, faster learning, lower stress and cognitive load, happier people and teams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;principles-are-universal-truths-and-observations-our-values-shape-the-principles-we-choose-to-follow&quot;&gt;Principles are universal truths and observations. Our values shape the Principles we choose to follow.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;flow-of-value&quot;&gt;Flow of value&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Handoffs and dependencies cause friction. The more friction, the more misunderstandings, rework, failure demand, greater cognitive load, wait times and work in progress. Small cross functional teams improve communication, ownership and reduce the aforementioned. Strive for autonomy; every dependency doubles your chance of being delayed or late.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where handoffs exist, explicit policies, events and working agreements improve their quality. Minimise rather than manage dependencies.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prioritisation and focus is vital. WIP increases cycle time of work and delays delivery of business value. Too much reduces flow, increases context switching, reduces quality and motivation. If everything is a priority, then nothing is. It’ll all be late.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;learning-and-improvement&quot;&gt;Learning and improvement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Embrace change; if we find out something needs to change it means we were heading in the wrong direction. Find out and act quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Small batches allow more frequent delivery of value, reduced risk and faster learning. Find the sweet spot between batch size and the tradeoffs of economies of scale.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Progress towards the desired outcome is the primary measure of progress. Working software is an inferior proxy, but better than any percentage complete type measure. We shouldn’t put confidence in anything until we can see it working.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For effective learning to happen, business areas, customers and development must be part of a tightly knit feedback loop.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To improve the Product, Process and People (relationships and working patterns) we must inspect these areas on a regular basis and adapt as necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pursue improvement through evolutionary change. In the complex context we discover the answers through inspection and incremental changes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transparency through visualisation improves collaboration.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collect, find and use data. Be data informed rather than data driven.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;environment&quot;&gt;Environment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stability and consistency produce more sustainable, predictable environments.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Psychological safety is essential for discovering issues early, which is a prerequisite for fixing them early.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People need purpose, autonomy and mastery in their work to be motivated. Connection to others produces a great working environment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Communication should be frequent and explicit. Where teams interact, working agreements and policies smooth interactions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;grappling-with-complex-contexts&quot;&gt;Grappling with complex contexts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aim for the simplest viable solution: minimise work, facilitate knowledge transfer and ease maintainability.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be effective first, efficient second. Only put your foot on the accelerator when you know you’re heading in the right direction..&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Commit at the ‘last responsible moment’; minimise the possibility of wasted effort, maximise the chance of learning something new before starting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="agile" /><category term="agility" /><category term="agile" /><summary type="html">What works.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">1984 by George Orwell</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/1984-by-george-orwell" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="1984 by George Orwell" /><published>2021-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/1984-by-george-orwell</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/1984-by-george-orwell">&lt;p&gt;Winston is a functionary in a totalitarian state. He begins to rebel, and meets a girl, but finds that he’s no match for the system. As Orwell wrote this the Allies were battling Fascism, Stalinism was showing its true colours, and it looked like no matter the ideology all roads led to authoritarianism and consolidation of power (to the disillusionment of many communists). There’s a fairly dull patch around the middle, but it’s a powerful book and it became a fixture of popular culture, influencing many other dystopian visions.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Side note:&lt;/strong&gt; I learned that much of the plot is very similar to Yevgeny Zamyatin’s novel ‘We’; which written in 1924 some 25 years prior to the publication of 1984, is in fact the first dystopian novel. Even so, there are many aspects of 1984 which are dystopian “classics” such as Thought Crime, Room 101 and Newspeak which all shaped the genre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Newspeak: exerting control by changing language.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Hate: enemy created to draw attention and anger.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The party
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;“ Who controls the past controls the future: who controls the present controls the past.“ &lt;/i&gt;- called “reality control”.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Slogans: War is peace, freedom is slavery, ignorance is strength&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Winston (protagonist) on the proles, the masses; &lt;i&gt;“Until they become conscious they will never rebel, and until after they have rebelled they cannot become conscious.“&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proles p76: &lt;i&gt;“All that was required of them was a primitive patriotism which could be appealed to whenever it was necessary to make them accept longer working hours or shorter rations.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The all-seeing Telescreen invites parallels between smart devices in homes. But it seems that all new technology or at least a great deal of it has the potential both for uses that improve peoples lives and the use by governments and organisations for nefarious purposes. Atomic energy provides clean power for millions but the science also brought the atomic bomb. The advent of motor transport and aviation allows people to travel and move around more freely but also agents of control to do so. Smart devices in homes enables easy communication, easy entertainment and connection to others but also the potential for monitoring and snooping. Same can be said with connectivity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“&lt;i&gt;All this marching up and down and cheering and waving flags is simply sex gone sour. If you’re happy inside yourself, why should you get excited about Big Brother and Three-Year-Plans and the Two-Minutes-Hate and all the rest of the bloody rot?“&lt;/i&gt;p142&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;“There was a direct intimate connection between chastity and political orthodoxy. For how could the fear, the hatred and the lunatic credulity which the party needed in its members be kept at the right pitch, except by bottling down some powerful instinct and using it as a driving force? The sex impulse was dangerous to the party, and the party had turned it to account.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Children… were systematically turned against the parents and taught to spy on them and report the deviations. ..the family had become in affect an extension of the Thought Police.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="fiction" /><category term="classics" /><category term="dystopian" /><summary type="html">Winston is a functionary in a totalitarian state. He begins to rebel, and meets a girl, but finds that he’s no match for the system. As Orwell wrote this the Allies were battling Fascism, Stalinism was showing its true colours, and it looked like no matter the ideology all roads led to authoritarianism and consolidation of power (to the disillusionment of many communists). There’s a fairly dull patch around the middle, but it’s a powerful book and it became a fixture of popular culture, influencing many other dystopian visions.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-1984.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-1984.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Candide and Other Stories by Voltaire</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/candide-and-other-stories-by-voltaire" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Candide and Other Stories by Voltaire" /><published>2021-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/candide-and-other-stories-by-voltaire</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/candide-and-other-stories-by-voltaire">&lt;p&gt;Candide is a philosophical tale with real events mixed in; a shocking and humorous satire on Voltaire’s times with problems that haven’t really gone away; greed, exploitation, corruption, debauchery and violence. Voltaire challenges the beliefs of Leibnitzian optimism and determinism, religion and the many churches of the time.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Candide is an innocent, naive chap who suffers many (many!) misfortunes whilst trying to reunite with his love, Cunégonde. He and other characters suffer floggings, beatings, sacking, rape, mutilation, inquisitors, selfishness, and thieving. Through all this suffering and injustice he very slowly comes to understand (barely) the ridiculousness of the view ingrained in him by his philosopher teacher Pangloss that all is for the best in the world and everything is well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still relevant to our times and never boring this rightly lives on as a classic. Aside from its attacks and satire, the morale is summed up near the end. The Turk states “Work keeps us from three great evils: boredom, vice, and need”. “We must cultivate our garden”. I take this to mean that work and conscious effort is needed to live well; in contrast to the Leibnitzian view of things being as they are for a reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;micromégas&quot;&gt;Micromégas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A philosophical tale about a giant being visiting our planet, who hears of the deeds men do to one another for a few small lumps of earth. “…deep down he was a trifle vexed to see that being so infinitesimally small should have a degree of pride that was almost infinitely great.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;zadig&quot;&gt;Zadig&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An asian tale of a clever, virtuous and courageous man who benefits from his attributes but also suffers for them. “ in this world things did not always turn out the way wisemen wanted.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-white-bull&quot;&gt;The White Bull&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A story of the Middle east based on the Greek mythological tale of Europa and the bull (where the white bull is the king of the Greek gods, Zeus, in disguise). A princess encounters an old woman with a beautiful white bull and other animals from scripture (the serpent, doves, a whale). It is in fact her love, a prince. She is entranced by it but her father wishes to have it sacrificed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Candide
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Philosophy (Leibnitzian). Everything works out for the best. Everything happens for a reason.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The nose is there for spectacles. Legs are created to wear trousers.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Dr Pangloss - “Individual misfortunes contribute to the general good with the result that the more individual misfortunes there are, the more all is well.”&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The bad things that happen to Candide he thinks good and inevitable once a good end is obtained.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Characters have little agency. When the good Anabaptist is drowning; it’s fine, thats why the harbour is there.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“It is impossible for things not to be where they are. For all is well.”&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Harsh world. Floggings, beatings, sacking, rape, inquisitors, selfishness, theiving.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Candide-“If this is the best of all possible worlds what must the others be like?“; he’d just had a flogging and seen his mentor being hanged by the inquisitors.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Encounters a sugar processing slave in Surinam with a missing hand and foot. Suffering so that the Europeans can enjoy their sugar. Not unlike the third world today.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After escaping the inquisitors in Portugal travels to Argentina, then Paraguay. Finds and kills Cunegonde’s brother a Jesuit, encounters natives, El Dorado, the pirate, return voyage to Venice.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;No-one is happy on closer inspection- the Theatine monk and Paquette. Even the Venetian nobleman who has everything is unhappy with it - bored. Only in the mythical land of El Dorado, which is unattainable, are people truly happy.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Yet eventually he finds and frees Cunégonde and lives on a farm with his small group. There they are bored and miserable.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Old woman: “I would like to know which is worse: being raped 100 times by negro pirates, having a buttock chopped off, running the gauntlet of the Bulgars, being flogged and hanged in an auto-da-fé, being dissected, rowing in a galley, in short suffering all the misfortunes we all suffered, or simply being stuck here and doing nothing? “That is a good question”, said Candide. This speech gave rise to renewed speculation, and Martin in particular came to the conclusion that man was born to spend his life ultimately a pray to the throes of anxiety and the lethargy of boredom.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Morals at the end:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The Turk: ‘Work keeps us from three great evils: boredom, vice, and need.”&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“We must cultivate our garden” - you make the best of the world.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zadig
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“..self-esteem is a balloon filled with wind, from which great tempests surge when it is pricked.”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hermes the doctor says Zadig will loose an eye. All Babylon marvelled at the depth of his knowledge…but it is cured. He writes a book proving it shouldn’t have got better. Zadig didn’t read it. = Iatrogenics&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Zadig is desperately trying to be happy.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“It is to Zadig that nations owe the great principle that it is better to risk sparing a guilty man than it is to condemn an innocent one.”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Woman who will throw herself on the funeral pyre: “..one has to do the done thing.” - compliance.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After getting his armour and emblem robbed, and his chances of becoming king of Babylon ruined by the cowardly Itobad, Zadig says there it is; ‘education, virtue, courage: they brought me nothing but disaster’.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It was agreed in the course of conversation that in this world things did not always turn out the way wisemen wanted.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Ingenu
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A foreigner in Brittany. Speaks to the ridiculousness of organised religion. The rules of men vs God. The Ingenu breaks and questions them. Eg why not marrying his godmother. Nothing in the scriptures.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For having learnt nothing at all in his childhood, he had not acquired any prejudices.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Iatrogenics the cause of the Ingenu’s love Saint-Yves’ death.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="fiction" /><category term="classics" /><summary type="html">Candide is a philosophical tale with real events mixed in; a shocking and humorous satire on Voltaire’s times with problems that haven’t really gone away; greed, exploitation, corruption, debauchery and violence. Voltaire challenges the beliefs of Leibnitzian optimism and determinism, religion and the many churches of the time.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-candide.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-candide.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Making Work Visible by Domenica DeGrandis</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/making-work-visible-by-Domenica-DeGrandis" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making Work Visible by Domenica DeGrandis" /><published>2021-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/making-work-visible-by-Domenica-DeGrandis</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/making-work-visible-by-Domenica-DeGrandis">&lt;p&gt;Accessible guide to making work visible; exposing time thieves and using Kanban practices to improve flow. So easy to read it’s great as a refresher for practitioners and a strong entry point for pretty much everyone else.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make work visible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Limit work-in-progress (WIP).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Measure and manage the flow of work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prioritise effectively.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make adjustments based on lessons from feedback and metrics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-5-thieves-of-time&quot;&gt;The 5 thieves of time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too much work in progress (WIP)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unknown dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unplanned work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conflicting priorities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Neglected work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-expose-time-theft-to-optimise-workflow&quot;&gt;How to expose time theft to optimise workflow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make work visible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make WIP visible and limit it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Expose dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unplanned work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prioritise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prevent negligence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;flow-metrics&quot;&gt;Flow metrics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flow time: a measure of how long something took to do from beginning to end.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cycle time: ambiguous - different meanings depending on who you ask.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WIP is a leading indicator.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little’s Law assumptions
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;All measure units are consistent.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Average arrival rate = average departure rate.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;All work that enters the system flows to competion and exists.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Average age of WIP is neither increasing or decreasing.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The total amount of WIP is roughly the same at the beginning and at the end.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Queuing Theory
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;There’s a direct correlation between WIP and capacity utilization.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Unpredictable events cause variability. The more variability, the more vulnerable we are to capacity overload.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The single biggest factor that affects queue size is capacity utilization.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kingman’s formula shows an approximation for the average wait time in a queue.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;As we move from 60%-80% utilization, the queue doubles. As we move from 80%-90% it doubles again.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;finding-out-where-waste-is-emerging&quot;&gt;Finding out where waste is emerging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consider measuring:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Unplanned work&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Unknown dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Conflicting priorities&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Neglacted work&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reporting
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Aging reports&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Card type distribution&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Failure load (value demand vs failure demand)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Flow efficiency&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="non-fiction" /><category term="kanban" /><category term="lean" /><category term="ways-of-working" /><summary type="html">Accessible guide to making work visible; exposing time thieves and using Kanban practices to improve flow. So easy to read it’s great as a refresher for practitioners and a strong entry point for pretty much everyone else.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-making-work-visible.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-making-work-visible.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>