<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://kaufie.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://kaufie.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-12-24T18:27:25+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/feed.xml</id><subtitle>Sasha Kaufmann's profile website and article archive.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Hard Boiled Wonderland and the End of the World</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/hard-boiled-wonderland-and-the-end-of-the-world-by-haruki-murakami" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hard Boiled Wonderland and the End of the World" /><published>2020-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/hard-boiled-wonderland-and-the-end-of-the-world-by-haruki-murakami</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/hard-boiled-wonderland-and-the-end-of-the-world-by-haruki-murakami">&lt;p&gt;This book delivers on a number of things you’d expect from Murakami; it’s surreal, has tonnes of references to 60/70/80s pop culture, plus detailed descriptions of cooking and characters getting on with life. There’s a lot to like, including a parallel story connected to the main narrative which felt similar to a Kafka novel. Alas, the sci-fi dystopian bent didn’t do anything for me. Talk about Semiotecs, shuffling and brain connections (etc.) I found more silly than surreal. It got pretty tedious. Ok but not one of his best books.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-notes&quot;&gt;My notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deep rivers run quiet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I love these descriptions of food (goes on for a few pages). “While I waited for her, I fixed supper. I mashed an umeboshi salt plum with mortar and pestle to make a sour-sweet dressing; I fried up a few sardines with abura-agé tofu-puffs in grated yama-imo taro batter; I sautéed a celery-beef side dish. Not a bad little meal.” p89&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Histories within stories. Characters reading books in a book. The discovery of a unicorn skull in Ukraine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="book" /><category term="fiction" /><category term="short-stories" /><summary type="html">This book delivers on a number of things you’d expect from Murakami; it’s surreal, has tonnes of references to 60/70/80s pop culture, plus detailed descriptions of cooking and characters getting on with life. There’s a lot to like, including a parallel story connected to the main narrative which felt similar to a Kafka novel. Alas, the sci-fi dystopian bent didn’t do anything for me. Talk about Semiotecs, shuffling and brain connections (etc.) I found more silly than surreal. It got pretty tedious. Ok but not one of his best books.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-hard-boiled.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-hard-boiled.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Navigating without a map</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/navigating-without-a-map" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Navigating without a map" /><published>2020-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/navigating-without-a-map</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/navigating-without-a-map">&lt;p&gt;What are the best things to have happened to you in life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you’re thinking of when you met your partner. Your kids. Starting a business. Lifelong friends. A career you love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suspect that some of these things were planned out. Others were the direct or indirect result of being in the right place, at the right time and of the decisions you made in the moment. Most of the time you only know that it’s the right place when you’re there. You can’t plan for it, which is why seeing every situation as having the potential for something amazing to happen and maximising that chance is a far better strategy than planning life out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are two approaches to life that aren’t mutually exclusive: We can focus on creating a plan, on drawing a map. We can also work on building the skills to get over the fact that we don’t have one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does a map give you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clarity of where to go, the route.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Comfort and security, you know the way and can see your progress.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A way to show others where you’re going and what you’re doing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your destination is specific and there’s only one route; if your journey is far and hard; if you don’t have time for any detours; then you need a map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focussing on having a map means spending a lot of time planning and waiting for the right moment for something to happen. If you do that, you’ll get on the route, and you’ll probably make it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we can obsess over having a map. That’s a mistake; again, life is often so uncertain that we don’t even know our destination, let alone what will happen along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the other strategy: rather than focussing on the map, build the skills to navigate without one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Knowing what’s important to you. The direction is more important than the route.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learning how to explore, read signs along the way, assess situations and make fast decisions based on the information available, your gut and their &lt;a href=&quot;/bold-decisions-reversible&quot;&gt;reversibility&lt;/a&gt;. Often this means learning by doing and making mistakes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Going on detours. Finding some dead ends. Discovering the hidden gems of life off the beaten track.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use a map, you’re efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can handle life without a map, you’re resilient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an unpredictable world be the latter.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="life" /><category term="decisions" /><category term="development" /><summary type="html">Go on detours. Find some dead ends. Discover the hidden gems of life off the beaten track.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/navi-without-a-map.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/navi-without-a-map.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Woman In The Dunes</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/the-woman-in-the-dunes-by-Kobo-Abe" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Woman In The Dunes" /><published>2020-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/the-woman-in-the-dunes-by-Kobo-Abe</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/the-woman-in-the-dunes-by-Kobo-Abe">&lt;p&gt;A man is held captive with a woman at the bottom of a vast sand pit in a seaside village. They must clear away sand every day in order to prevent the village being eaten up by the dunes. I can’t remember how I found this book; I enjoyed it though. The combination of bizarre situation and detailed descriptions has something almost Kafkaesque to it. He collects insects and now he’s trapped like an insect.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="book" /><category term="fiction" /><summary type="html">A man is held captive with a woman at the bottom of a vast sand pit in a seaside village. They must clear away sand every day in order to prevent the village being eaten up by the dunes. I can’t remember how I found this book; I enjoyed it though. The combination of bizarre situation and detailed descriptions has something almost Kafkaesque to it. He collects insects and now he’s trapped like an insect.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-the-woman-in-the-dunes.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-the-woman-in-the-dunes.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Touching the Void</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/touching-the-void-by-joe-simpson" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Touching the Void" /><published>2020-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/touching-the-void-by-joe-simpson</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/touching-the-void-by-joe-simpson">&lt;p&gt;Take heart from the fact that no matter what life throws at you, you’ll never have it worse than being stuck halfway up a mountain alone, with your knee smashed to pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two climbers in this book took a stupid risk and nearly paid the ultimate price. What they went through though makes for one hell of a survival story. The first third of the book is boring for someone who doesn’t climb as it takes us on their ascent. Once Joe breaks his leg things suddenly get very tense, ramping up each time the situation gets more desperate. The emotions he goes through, the guilt of Simon who cut Joe loose, the ebb and flow of determination and hopelessness that got him to camp. It’s powerful stuff.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-notes&quot;&gt;My notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Great quote:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“All men dream: but not all equally. Those who dream by night in the dusty recesses of their minds wake in the day to find that it was vanity: but the dreamers of the day are dangerous men, for they may act their dreams with open eyes, to make it possible. - &lt;i&gt;T.E.Lawrence, the seven pillars of Wisdom&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="book" /><category term="non-fiction" /><category term="adventure" /><category term="survival" /><summary type="html">Take heart from the fact that no matter what life throws at you, you’ll never have it worse than being stuck halfway up a mountain alone, with your knee smashed to pieces. The two climbers in this book took a stupid risk and nearly paid the ultimate price. What they went through though makes for one hell of a survival story. The first third of the book is boring for someone who doesn’t climb as it takes us on their ascent. Once Joe breaks his leg things suddenly get very tense, ramping up each time the situation gets more desperate. The emotions he goes through, the guilt of Simon who cut Joe loose, the ebb and flow of determination and hopelessness that got him to camp. It’s powerful stuff.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-touching-the-void.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-touching-the-void.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Men Without Women by Haruki Murakami</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/men-without-women-by-haruki-murakami" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Men Without Women by Haruki Murakami" /><published>2020-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/men-without-women-by-haruki-murakami</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/men-without-women-by-haruki-murakami">&lt;p&gt;These short stories are an exploration 7 men’s relationships with women; a thread of sadness and loneliness running through them. I enjoy Muarkami’s writing style and this book was no exception. It’s not one of my favorites and I wouldn’t recommend it to anyone looking for his best work, but for the most part I did find the stories interesting and unexpected.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-notes&quot;&gt;My notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An actor, his female driver and his dead wife’s lover.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A college student, a request, a dare with a friend’s girlfriend. Loneliness.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A plastic surgeon. Falling in love. A betrayal, lies and suicide.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A recluse. His middle aged carer. Sex. Stories of youth. Lamphreys, breaking and entering.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Betrayal. The bar with a stray cat. Cigarette burns. Pain and forgiveness.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Waking up human. A female hunchback. A locksmith.  Prague.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The suicide of an old girlfriend. Memories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="book" /><category term="fiction" /><category term="short-stories" /><summary type="html">These short stories are an exploration 7 men’s relationships with women; a thread of sadness and loneliness running through them. I enjoy Muarkami’s writing style and this book was no exception. It’s not one of my favorites and I wouldn’t recommend it to anyone looking for his best work, but for the most part I did find the stories interesting and unexpected.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-men-without-women.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-men-without-women.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Six Thinking Hats by Edward De Bono</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/six-thinking-hats-by-edward-de-bono" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Six Thinking Hats by Edward De Bono" /><published>2020-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/six-thinking-hats-by-edward-de-bono</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/six-thinking-hats-by-edward-de-bono">&lt;p&gt;This is a simple method for approaching decisions that forces everyone to look from different angles, one at a time. The concept is great and I’d highly recommend this book as a way to raise awareness of the different ways of looking at problems. The book is short and it could be shorter. In practice the approach can seem infantilising, although I’m sure as de Bono claims, for some groups the method has worked wonders. For me the value is in its use on a personal level; noticing the different perspectives and using them…without annoying everyone by talking about hats.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-notes&quot;&gt;My notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Use Parallel Thinking to arrive at faster, better decisions.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;the hats are different directions.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;at any moment everyone is looking in the same direction.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;the hats are not descriptions of people but modes of behaviour.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;everyone wears the same hat at an appointed time.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Results this provides:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;power, through focussing everyone’s energy in the same direction.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;time saving, less arguments and posturing.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;removal of ego from the equation.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;consider one thing at a time.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The neutrality of the hats allows them to be used without embarrassment.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;White hat&lt;/strong&gt;. White is neutral and objective. The White hat is concerned with objective facts and figures.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Red Hat&lt;/strong&gt;. Red suggests anger, rage and emotions. The Red hat gives the emotional view.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Black hat&lt;/strong&gt;. Black is sombre and serious. The black hat is cautious and careful. It points out the weaknesses in an idea.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yellow hat&lt;/strong&gt;. Yellow is sunny and positive. The yellow hat is optimistic and covers hope and positive thinking.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Green hat&lt;/strong&gt;. Green is grass, vegetation and abundant, fertile growth. The green hat indicates creativity and new ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blue hat&lt;/strong&gt;. Blue is cool and is also the colour of the sky, which is above everything else. The blue hat is concerned with control, the organisation of the thinking process and the use of other hats.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The hats can be used singly to request a type of thinking. Or, the hats can be used in sequence to explore a subject or solve a problem.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blue hat&lt;/strong&gt; should be used like two bookends
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Before
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;why we are here.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;what we are thinking about.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;the definition of the situation or problem.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;alternate definitions.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;what we want to achieve.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;where we want to end up.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;the background to the thinking and.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;a plan for the sequence of hats to be used.&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;After
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;what we have achieved.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;outcome.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;conclusion.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;design.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;solution.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;next steps.&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Red hat&lt;/strong&gt; may follow to get emotions on the table - but not the boss for want of making others follow&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;In an assessment situation put the &lt;strong&gt;Yellow hat&lt;/strong&gt; before the black hat because if you can’t find much value in an idea there’s no point in proceeding further&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;using-the-hats&quot;&gt;Using the hats&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;White hat&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Focus exclusively on information
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;what info do we have?&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;what do we need?&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;what’s missing?&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;what questions do we need to ask?&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;hard facts and soft, opinions and feelings (reporting someone else’s, your own is for red hat)&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;define the info that’s missing!&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Used at the beginning as background or end as assessment.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Neutral, reports on the world.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Separates fact from extrapolation or interpretation.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;There are believed facts and checked facts. the merely believed are second class. The important point is the use to which the facts are put. Before using it for the basis of a decision we need to check it.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;We need the belief tier because the tentative, the hypothetical and provocative are essential for thinking. They provide the frameworks which move ahead of the facts.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Your own opinion isn’t permissible- you can report the opinion of someone else.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Japanese style meetings. No one puts forward a ready-made idea. Information is offered in Whitehat fashion. The Japanese notion is that ideas emerge as seedlings, nurtured and allowed to grow into shape. in contrast with the western notion that ideas should be hammered into shape by argument.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The spectrum of [[likelihood]]may be expressed as follows: Always true. Usually true. Generally true. By and large. More often than not. About half the time. Often. Sometimes true. Occasionally true. Been known to happen. Never true. Cannot be true (contradictory).&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Who puts on the hat?
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Put on your own hat. Ask someone to put on the hat. Ask everyone to put on the white hat. Choose to answer with the hat on.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Red hat&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Gives you an opportunity to express feelings, emotions and intuition without any need to explain or to justify them.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Must relate to a specific idea. the thinker can’t change the idea.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Individuals should not be allowed to say “pass“ when they are asked for their Red Hat feelings. They can use terms like neutral, undecided, confused, doubtful or mixed. If feelings are defined as mixed then the facilitator may ask what goes into the mix. The purpose of the Red Hat is to express feelings as they exist not to force a judgement.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Emotions and feelings are the opposite of neutral, objective information. They’re hunches, intuitions, impressions. There is no need to justify. No need to give reasons or the basis.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If emotions and feelings aren’t permitted as inputs into the thinking process they will lurk in the background and affect all the thinking in a hidden way. Emotions, feelings, hunches and intuitions are strong and real. The Red Hat acknowledges this.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Opinions may be expressed under red, black or yellow hats. When the red hat is used, it is best to express an opinion as a feeling.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Used for reacting and getting upset. To show that this is what I feel about this meeting. Anyone who feels the need to be emotional has a defined way of doing so. Use this as a way to find out the feelings of others without guessing; you can ask them directly to put their red hat on and give you their opinion.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Black hat&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For caution. Stop us doing something illegal, dangerous, unprofitable etc.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The basis of critical thinking. Points out when something is contradictory or inconsistent.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Points out how something does not fit our resources, or policy, or strategy, or ethics, values, and so forth.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Always must be a logical basis for criticism.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;In its “design” role, the black hat points out the weaknesses in an idea so that those weaknesses can be put right.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Content and process; point out errors in thinking. Question the strength of the evidence. Does the conclusion follow? Is it the only possible conclusion?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To avoid interactions during the process the thinker should note and accumulate the main points of criticism and put them forward only when the black hat is in use.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;At the end there should be a clear map of possible problems, obstacles, difficulties and dangers. These can be clarified and elaborated. Under the green hat and attempt is made to overcome or cope with the difficulties suggested under the black hat.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The past and the future. What is likely to happen in the future? Does this fit past experience? What are the risks?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The problem of overuse; it’s easy to be critical. Some people enjoy being only critical. The need to contribute.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Black hat thinking is not about arguments and must not be allowed to generate into argument. The purpose of black hat thinking is to put the caution points on the map.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yellow hat&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Optimism. Positive thinking. Sunshine and brightness. Focus on benefit. Constructive thinking and making things happen. The thinker sets out to find whatever benefit there might be in a decision and how to put it into practice.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Harder to use than the black hat, people naturally think of dangers.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Should be logically based.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Self interest is a strong basis for positive thinking. The yellow hat does not have to await such motivations.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Optimistic suggestions should be noted and put on the map. No reason to assess them before doing so; but worth labelling with a rough estimate of [[likelihood]]. #probability
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Proven.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Very likely, based on experience and what we know.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Good chance - through a combination of different things.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Even chance.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;No better than possible.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Remote or long shot.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Having it on the map means we have a choice.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Reasons and logical support; what is your positive view based on? Why do you think it will happen this way? Background reasons for the optimism.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Constructive thinking. making things happen. Proposals and suggestions.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Speculation. Looking into the future. The value of “if”. The best possible scenario.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Opportunity thinking.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You start with the best possible scenario because if the benefits aren’t sufficient with that then the idea is not worth pursuing.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The speculative aspect of yellow hat thinking is also concerned with vision.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Difference between constructive and creative. Yellow hat thinking is not directly concerned with creativity which is green hat thinking. A person can be an excellent yellow hat thinker and never have a new idea. The effective application of old ideas is a proper exercise of yellow heart thinking.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Can define an opportunity and leave it to green hat thinking to come up with some novel way of exploiting that opportunity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Green hat&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Creativity, energy, growth.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Gives people that never thought of themselves as creative encouragement to start making a creative effort, increases their confidence and they therefore can contribute in a meaningful way.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It gives us possibilities. Without possibilities you cannot make progress. 2000 years ago, Chinese technology was way ahead of western technology. Then progress seemed to come to an end. The explanation often given is that the Chinese did not develop the hypothesis. Without this key piece of mental software it was impossible to make progress. Those that believe progress arises from the analysis of information and steps of logical deduction are totally wrong. Without the framework of possibilities we cannot see the information in new ways.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The green hat may be used to overcome some of the difficulties put forward under the black hat. It may suggest modifications to an idea to avoid the difficulties.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Creative thinking: new ideas, new concepts and new perceptions. The deliberate creation of new ideas. Alternatives and more alternatives. Change. New approaches to problems.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Lateral thinking in its relation to creativity. Humour and lateral thinking. Pattern switching in a self organising information system.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Movement instead of judgement. Using an idea is a stepping stone. Where does it take me? The forward effect of an idea. Movement as an active idiom. We use an idea for its movement value. With movement we use an idea for each forward effect. We use an idea to see where it will get us.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The need for provocation. Use of the word po. The logic of the absurd. Random provocation. We use provocations for their movement value. Po as an indicator that an idea was put forward as a provocation and for its movement value. The letters stand for provocative operation.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can use random words as a po. To many people it may seem unthinkable that a random word could be value in solving a problem. Random means the the word has no special relationship. In the logic of an asymmetric patterning system, it is easy to see why a random word works. It provides a different starting point. As we chase our way back from that new starting point, we increase the chance of arriving back along the track we would never have taken when thinking about the subject directly.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Alternatives. The first answer may not be the best; we acknowledge it and can always go back to it; then we look for alternatives. We create routes; different levels of alternatives. We can look at alternatives within a route (or different routes altogether). “You ask me for alternative ways of loading the trucks. I’m going to tell you that it would make more sense to send your product by train”.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Personality and skill: changing masks is is easier than changing faces - putting on a different hat changes the mask. People take pride in the exercise of a skill.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What happens to the ideas: shaping and tailoring ideas. The concept manager.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The shaping of an idea is done by bringing in constraints. They are brought in as shapers and not as a rejection screen. Part of the creative process is to shape the idea so that it better fits the need profile of those who are going to have to buy the idea.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Steps: Collect the output from green hat thinking. Next is the yellow hat stage; this includes the constructive development of the idea, the positive assessment and the search for support of benefits and values. Black hat thinking comes next. At any stage white hat thinking can be called upon to supply data required for evaluating whether the idea will work and will be valuable if it does. Final stage: red hat thinking; do we like the idea enough to proceed further?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Green hat thinking is a mix of attitudes, idioms and techniques including movement, provocation and po for cutting across patterns in a self organising asymmetric patterning system. It is used to generate new concepts and perceptions.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blue hat&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For thinking about thinking.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Control of thinking: thinking about thinking. Instructions for thinking. The organisation of thinking. Control of the other hats.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Focus: asking the right questions. Defining the problem. Setting the thinking tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Programme design: step-by-step. Software for thinking. Choreography.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The blue hat customises the programme to fit the situation, just as a carpenter plans how he’s going to make a chair or a cabinet.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Summaries and conclusions: observation and overview. Comment. Summaries, conclusions, harvesting and reports.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Control and monitoring: the chairperson. Discipline and focus. Who is in charge?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="book" /><category term="business" /><category term="decisions" /><summary type="html">This is a simple method for approaching decisions that forces everyone to look from different angles, one at a time. The concept is great and I’d highly recommend this book as a way to raise awareness of the different ways of looking at problems. The book is short and it could be shorter. In practice the approach can seem infantilising, although I’m sure as de Bono claims, for some groups the method has worked wonders. For me the value is in its use on a personal level; noticing the different perspectives and using them…without annoying everyone by talking about hats.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-six-thinking-hats.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-six-thinking-hats.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Buried Giant by Kazuo Ishiguro</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/the-buried-giant-by-kazuo-ishiguro" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Buried Giant by Kazuo Ishiguro" /><published>2020-10-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-10-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/the-buried-giant-by-kazuo-ishiguro</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/the-buried-giant-by-kazuo-ishiguro">&lt;p&gt;This novel is a tender fable about old age, marriage and past lives. In ancient Britain an elderly couple set off on a journey to find their son and on the way encounter a warrior, a knight and the source of their fading memory. I enjoyed the book; it’s original and I found it sad, sweet and memorable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-notes&quot;&gt;My notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Underlying messages are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forgetting helps mend old wounds. It’s not always a bad thing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No marriage is perfect, you have to accept one another’s faults and misdeeds.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People can change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="book" /><category term="fiction" /><category term="fable" /><summary type="html">This novel is a tender fable about old age, marriage and past lives. In ancient Britain an elderly couple set off on a journey to find their son and on the way encounter a warrior, a knight and the source of their fading memory. I enjoyed the book; it’s original and I found it sad, sweet and memorable.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/the-buried-giant.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/the-buried-giant.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bold decisions, reversible</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/bold-decisions-reversible" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bold decisions, reversible" /><published>2020-10-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-10-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/bold-decisions-reversible</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/bold-decisions-reversible">&lt;p&gt;Learning how to identify decisions that can be made quickly and making them decisively can make a huge difference in your personal and business life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t rush some decisions. Most people rightly wouldn’t buy a house on the spur of the moment. Likewise in business many decisions have huge implications and take time to fully consider. The problem is that sometimes we go too far; we slow ourselves down by failing to recognise the decisions that can be made quickly. We miss out on a first mover advantage, the learning from doing and any benefit we’d be getting from the change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeff Bezos frames decisions as either “one way doors” that require careful deliberation and consultation or “two way doors”; decisions that can be reversed. Most fall into the second category. Saying that he’s been wildly successful following the model is something of an understatement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A decision that pays off will make an enormous difference, but even the aggregation of small experiments builds up to something significant. In contrast, arduous processes and cycles that consume time and resources cost a fortune and land you with the cost of delay in carrying out a change as well the loss of any benefit from the knowledge a failed experiment imparts. There’s time for fast decision making, and there’s time for careful consideration; the advantage is in knowing which to utilise in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In business a simple effort vs reward matrix can be used to decide what to focus on. They typically look like the one below. Low effort, high reward activities are no brainers, cherish these. If something requires a lot of effort but pays off well then that’s usually next in priority. Low effort and low reward activities are left to do only if there’s time to spare. High effort low reward should be left to the suckers, forget it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lead-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/Effort_Reward.png&quot; alt=&quot;Effort vs reward matrix&quot; style=&quot;max-width:100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another dimension that we need to consider is potential upside (positive) vs downside (negative). Whilst the former is essentially the reward axis, there is no representation of the potential downside on the diagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High potential upside, limited potential downside means you can proceed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High potential upside and downside means you should proceed with caution. In the most extreme circumstance you could destroy your business and/or reputation - at which point too much damage has been done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can think about effort vs reversibility in the same way and equally we need to consider potential upside and downside. An effort vs reversibility matrix allows the separation of things you need to be cautious about from things that you should just get on with. Framing decisions in this way provides a rule of thumb for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how much information to collect;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the level of consensus you need to build before implementing a change;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how long to wait before doing it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lead-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/Effort_Reversible.png&quot; alt=&quot;Effort vs reward matrix&quot; style=&quot;max-width:100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For highly reversible, low effort changes: a hunch is enough to warrant just getting on with it. Spend the minimum viable time on gathering information and building consensus. The kind of changes you tend to see here are new practices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highly reversible, high effort changes need more consideration because of the opportunity cost of the invested effort. A strong hypothesis will be needed. New policies or significant changes to a delivery approach are examples of what you might find here.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not easily reversible, low effort changes should be approached with high caution. There’s a tendency for the ease at which the decision can be made to influence rash or careless decision makers into doing lasting damage to a company or wasting resources. An example here would be poor hiring. A hire can be made at the drop of a hat, but if it turns out badly then the effort in recruitment, the time of the people they’ve met and the onboarding has been wasted and will need to be repeated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Less reversible, high effort changes require extreme caution. Think of a company deciding on a new internal accounting system. Clearly high effort to implement and difficult to back out of.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In practice I’ve used this approach to make decisions quickly which on the surface may have seemed reckless. If the changes hadn’t worked it would have been relatively easy to reverse. As an example, working in telecoms I had to respond to my team growing overnight to 18 people as we merged with another. Using Scrum the team size was far from ideal (cognitive load and the number of communication paths). We could have done nothing and trundled along. We didn’t spend weeks building consensus with stakeholders, running through process diagrams or debating every possible scenario. Almost instantaneously we decided (1) to go fully remote and (2) to work as two sub-teams with a couple of light touch processes to keep in sync. The changes happened within a week (which in a large corporate is almost instantaneous) and with the result of moving quickly there was no loss of momentum on the work in progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you start looking at decisions as either reversible or irreversible it becomes easier to be someone who makes things happen. You’ll know it when you have to dig a bit deeper to find patience with people that don’t move as fast. If something is easily reversible, you just decide and move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When something is reversible, it’s a lot easier to be bold.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="agile" /><category term="decisions" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="agility" /><category term="agile" /><summary type="html">Make decisions quickly and with confidence.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/Effort_Reversible.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/Effort_Reversible.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The First 90 Days by Michael Watkins</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/the-first-90-days-by-michael-watkins" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The First 90 Days by Michael Watkins" /><published>2020-09-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/the-first-90-days-by-michael-watkins</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/the-first-90-days-by-michael-watkins">&lt;p&gt;Essential reading if you’re about to start a new job in a leadership role; whether you’ve been promoted or joined a new company. The book is well structured and provides clear strategies for approaching the new challenge and setting yourself up for success. Every time I change roles, I re-read this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-notes&quot;&gt;My notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is packed with useful information. I really recommend buying a copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The root causes of transition failure lie in a pernicious interaction between the situation, with its opportunities and pitfalls, and the individual, with his or her strengths and vulnerabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are systematic methods that leaders can employ to both lessen the likelihood of failure and reach the breakeven point faster.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The goal is to &lt;strong&gt;build momentum by creating virtuous cycles that build credibility and by avoiding getting caught in vicious cycles that damage credibility.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-promote-yourself&quot;&gt;1. Promote yourself&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t assume what has made you successful at this point will continue to do so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-accelerate-your-learning&quot;&gt;2. Accelerate your learning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Climb the learning curve as fast as possible. Markets, products, technologies, systems, structures, culture and politics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Getting acquainted with a new organisation can feel like drinking from a fire hose”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be systematic and focussed about deciding what you need to learn and how you will learn it efficiently.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Planning to learn means figuring out in advance what the important questions are an how you can best answer them.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Baseline question: how did we get to this point?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Start by generating questions about the &lt;strong&gt;past&lt;/strong&gt;, questions about the &lt;strong&gt;present&lt;/strong&gt; and questions about the &lt;strong&gt;future&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An &lt;strong&gt;actionable insight&lt;/strong&gt; is knowledge that enables you to make better decisions earlier and so helps you reach the break even point in personal value sooner.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Extract actionable insights from the mass of information available to you.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Efficient - identify the best sources of insight and figure out how to extract maximum insight with the least possible outlay of time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a virtuous cycle of information gathering, analysing, hypothesising and testing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What do you most need to learn?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions about the past&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance&lt;/strong&gt;
      - How has this organisation performed in the past? How do people in the organisation think it has performed?
      - How were goals set? Were they insufficiently or overly ambitious?
      - Were internal or external benchmarks used?
      - What measures were employed? What behaviours did they encourage or discourage?
      - What happened if goals were not met?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Root causes&lt;/strong&gt;
      - If performance has been good, why has this been the case?
      - What have been the relative contributions of the organisation’s strategy, its structure, its technical capabilities, its culture and its politics?
      - If performance has been poor, why has this been the case? Do the primary issues reside in the organisation’s strategy? Its structure? Its technical capabilities? Its culture? Its politics?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;History of change&lt;/strong&gt;
      - What efforts have been made to change the org?
      - Who has been instrumental in shaping it?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the present&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vision and strategy&lt;/strong&gt;
      - What is the stated vision and strategy of the org?
      - Is it really pursuing that strategy? If no, why not? If so, is the strategy going to take the org where it needs to go?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People&lt;/strong&gt;
      - Who is capable and who isn’t?
      - Who can be trusted and who can’t?
      - Who has influence and why?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Processes&lt;/strong&gt;
      - What are the key processes in the org?
      - Are they performing acceptably in terms of quality, reliability and timeliness? If not, why not?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Land mines&lt;/strong&gt;
      - What lurking surprises could detonate and push you off track?
      - What potentially damaging cultural or political missteps must you avoid making?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early wins&lt;/strong&gt;
      - In what areas (people, relationships, processes, or products) can you achieve some early wins?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions about the future&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenges and opportunities&lt;/strong&gt;
      - In what areas is the business most likely to face stiff challenges in the coming year? What can be done now to prepare for them?
      - What are the most promising unexploited opportunities? What would need to happen to realise their potential?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barriers and resources&lt;/strong&gt;
      - What are the most formidable barriers to making needed changes? Technical? Cultural? Political?
      - Are there islands of excellence or other high quality resources that you can leverage?
      - What new capabilities need to be developed or acquired?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Culture&lt;/strong&gt;
      - Which elements of the culture should be preserved?
      - Which need to change?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of information:&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Customers&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Distributors&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Suppliers&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Outside analysts&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Frontline R&amp;amp;D and Operations&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sales and Purchasing&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Staff&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Integrators&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Natural historians&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pick up ‘Soft information’ by talking to people.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask direct reports the same 5 questions
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What are the biggest challenges the org is facing or will face in the future?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Why is the org facing or going to face these challenges?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What are the most promising unexploited opportunities for growth?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What would need to happen for the org to exploit the potential of these opportunities?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you were me, what would you focus attention on?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How people answer can tell you a lot about your new team and its politics.&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Who answers directly? Who is evasive and prone to going on tangents? Who takes responsibility and who points fingers? Who has a broad view of the business and who seems stuck in a silo.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating a learning plan&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;p50-52 provides a learning plan template. The above is what you want to learn, this is how you will learn it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning about culture&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Symbols are signs that distinguish one culture from another. Including logos or styles of dress.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Norms are shared social rules that guide behaviour. What get encouraged or rewarded? What elicits scorn or dispproval.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Assumptions are often unarticulated beliefs that underpin social systems. What truths does everyone take for granted?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;There are organisational, professional and geographic culture perspectives that often intersect.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-match-strategy-to-situation&quot;&gt;3. Match strategy to situation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Diagnosis before developing an action plan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identify which transition type your situation is:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Start up&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Turnaround&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Realignment&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sustaining success&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What you do depends on this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When clear on the situation you’ll face 3 fundamental early choices.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;How much emphasis will you place on learning as opposed to doing?
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Realignment and sustaining success - more learning. Startup or turnaround - more doing.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;How much emphasis will you place of offence as opposed to defence?
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Realignment or startup are offence. Sustaining or turnaround are defence.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What should you do to get some early wins?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-secure-early-wins&quot;&gt;4. Secure early wins&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;These build credibility and create momentum. They create virtuous cycles. Leverage the energy you’re putting in to create a sense that good things are happening.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the first few weeks identify opportunities to build credibility. In the first 90 days you need to identify ways to create value, improve business results and get to the breakeven point more rapidly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Common traps:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Failing to focus&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Not taking the business situation into account&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Not adjusting for the culture&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Failing to get wins that matter to your boss&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Letting your means undermine your ends
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;eg. being seen as manipulative or underhanded&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each wave of change consists of:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Learning&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Designing the changes&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Building support&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Implimenting the changes&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Observing results&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The point is to define your goals so you can lead with a distinct endpoint in mind.&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A-item priorities - should follow naturally from core problems.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Behaviour changes. Lack of:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Focus&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Discipline&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Innovation&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Teamwork&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Sense of urgency&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;At this stage your objective is to build personal credibility.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Craft a few messages tailored to your key audiences
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Focus on who you are, the values and goals you represent, your style and how you plan to conduct business.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Remove minor but persistent irritants:
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Redundant meetings&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Shorten excessively long ones&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Improve physical space problems&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-negotiate-success&quot;&gt;5. Negotiate success&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Figure out how to build a productive relationship with your new boss and manage their expectations.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Carefully plan critical conversations about:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Situation&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Expectation&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Style&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Resources&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Personal development&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developing and gaining consensus on your 90 day plan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fundamentals on building a productive relationship:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Don’t trash the past&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Don’t stay away&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Don’t surprise your boss&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Don’t approach your boss only with problems&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Don’t run down your checklist&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Don’t try to change the boss&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Do take 100 percent responsibility for making the relationship work&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Do clarify mutual expectations early and often&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Do negotiate timelines for diagnosis and action planning&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Do aim for early wins in areas important to the boss&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Do pursue good marks from those whose opinions your boss respects&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Plan for 5 conversations:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Situational diagnosis conversations - you seek to understand how your new boss understands the situation&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The expectations conversation&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The style conversations&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The resources conversation&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The personal development conversation&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Identify untouchables.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Educate your boss - get realistic expectations.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Underpromise and overdeliver.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Plan the conversations (p.120).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-achieve-alignment&quot;&gt;6. Achieve alignment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Org architect: figure out if the orgs strategy is sound, bring its structure into alignment with its strategy and develop the systems and skill bases necessary to realise strategic intent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 areas of org architecture need to work together:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Strategy&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Structure&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Systems&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Skills&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Culture&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identify misalignments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Common traps:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Trying to restructure your way out of deeper problems&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Creating structures that are too complex&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Automating problem processes&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Making changes for change’s sake&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Overestimating your group’s capacity to absorb strategic shifts&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting started:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Start with strategy&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Look at supporting structure, systems and skills.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Decide how and when you will introduce the new strategy&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Reshape structure, systems and skills simultaneously&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Close the loop&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Crafting strategy:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Customers&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Capital&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Capabilities&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Commitments&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shape your groups structure:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Units&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Decision rights&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Performance management and rewards systems&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Reporting relationships and information sharing mechanisms&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Initiating cultural change:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Change performance measures and incentives&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Set up pilot projects&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bring in new people&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Promote collective learning&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Engage in collective visioning&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-build-your-team&quot;&gt;7. Build your team&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select the right people for the right positions - critical for success.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoid common traps:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Keeping the existing team too long
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Rule of thumb: by the end of your first 90 days decide who shall remain and go. But end of 6 months should have been communicated to key stakeholders.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Not repairing the airplane - ie doing nothing&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Not working organisational alignment and team restructuring issues in parallel&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Not holding onto the good people&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Undertaking team building before the core team is in place:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Tempting to launch team-building activities such as joint problem solving, brainstorming and visioning right away…but poses a danger, strengthens the bond of the group.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Making implementation dependent decisions too early&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Trying to do it all yourself - get support from a good HR person&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assessing your existing team:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Competence&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Judgement&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Energy&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Focus&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Relationships&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Trust&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assign each team member the following categories:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Keep in place&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Keep and develop&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Move to another position&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Observe for a while&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Replace (low priority)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Replace (high priority)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Your direct reports will form lasting impressions of you based on how you manage this part of your job.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aligning goals, incentives and measures:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Push tools:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Incentives&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Reporting system&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Planning processes&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Procedures&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Mission statement&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pull tools:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Shared vision&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Teamwork&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decision making:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Unilateral (most leader control)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Consult-and-decide&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Build consensus&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Unanimous (least leader control)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To avoid confusion, consider explaining to direct reports what you’re using and why. Strive to run a fair process. Even if they don’t agree, they’ll support if they feel 1) that their views have been heard and taken seriously and 2) that you have given a plausible rationale for why you made the call you did&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Charade consensus building for a decision already made doesn’t fool anyone&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-create-coalitions&quot;&gt;8. Create coalitions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identify whose support is essential for your success, and figure out how to line them up on your side.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A common mistake is for leaders to focus too much on the vertical dimension of influence (bosses and DRs) and not enough on the horizontal dimension - peers and external constituencies.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Discipline yourself to invest in building relationship capital with people you anticipate needing to work with later.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identify key players. Consider creating priority relationship lists for direct reports.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Notice to whom people go for advice and insight.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sources of power:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Expertise&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Access to information&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Status&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Control of resources, such as budgets and rewards&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Personal loyalty
    - You’ll notice &lt;strong&gt;power coalitions&lt;/strong&gt;.
    - Draw an influence map - p.190
    - Appeal to core values - loyalty, commitment and contribution, individual worth and dignity, integrity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;9-keep-your-balance&quot;&gt;9. Keep your balance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The right advice and council network is indispensable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watch out for:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Riding off in all directions&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Undefended boundaries&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Brittleness&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Isolation&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Biased judgement&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Work avoidance. Need to take the bull by the horns&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Going over the top&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The 3 pillars of self-efficacy:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Adopting success strategies&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Enforcing personal disciplines:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Plan to plan&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Judiciously defer commitment&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Set aside time for hard work&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Go to the balcony - look from a high level&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Focus on process&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Check in with yourself&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Guidelines for self reflection p.215 - questions to ask yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-expedite-everyone&quot;&gt;10. Expedite everyone&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop high quality leaders
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Succession planning&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="book" /><category term="careers" /><summary type="html">Essential reading if you’re about to start a new job in a leadership role; whether you’ve been promoted or joined a new company. The book is well structured and provides clear strategies for approaching the new challenge and setting yourself up for success. Every time I change roles, I re-read this book.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/first-90.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/first-90.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Don’t go there by Svetlana Oss</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/dont-go-there-by-svetlana-oss" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Don’t go there by Svetlana Oss" /><published>2020-09-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/dont-go-there-by-svetlana-oss</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/dont-go-there-by-svetlana-oss">&lt;p&gt;In 1959 nine university students were found dead in the Russian Ural mountains in mysterious circumstances. They had been on a mountaineering trip; their tent was ripped open and the bodies were found not far. Nobody knows with certainty what happened, at least not anyone who’s willing to come forward with the details. This is what’s known as “The Dyatlov Pass Incident”. Svetlana introduces us to the students, outlining their steps and the details of the macabre discovery; along the way photos and excerpts from journal entries bring this to life. We get a critique of various theories; was it an avalanche, military test, espionage, a UFO (meteor or celestial body) or an act of local tribes? Eventually this concludes with a rationale of the most likely explanation. I found the book engaging and although it’s made clear early on that there isn’t a definitive answer I was satisfied by the end that the author’s conclusion has firm grounding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No notes here, to avoid giving away the conclusion. :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="book" /><category term="non-fiction" /><category term="mystery" /><summary type="html">In 1959 nine university students were found dead in the Russian Ural mountains in mysterious circumstances. They had been on a mountaineering trip; their tent was ripped open and the bodies were found not far. Nobody knows with certainty what happened, at least not anyone who’s willing to come forward with the details. This is what’s known as “The Dyatlov Pass Incident”. Svetlana introduces us to the students, outlining their steps and the details of the macabre discovery; along the way photos and excerpts from journal entries bring this to life. We get a critique of various theories; was it an avalanche, military test, espionage, a UFO (meteor or celestial body) or an act of local tribes? Eventually this concludes with a rationale of the most likely explanation. I found the book engaging and although it’s made clear early on that there isn’t a definitive answer I was satisfied by the end that the author’s conclusion has firm grounding.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-dont-go-there.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-dont-go-there.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>