<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://kaufie.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://kaufie.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-07T17:29:51+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/feed.xml</id><subtitle>Sasha Kaufmann's profile website and article archive.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 2 - What to measure</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/what-to-measure" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 2 - What to measure" /><published>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/what-to-measure</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/what-to-measure">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/options-and-outcomes&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (CHAPTER 1 - Options and Outcomes)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-should-we-measure&quot;&gt;What should we measure?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Measurement is fabulous. Unless you’re busy measuring what’s easy to measure as opposed to what’s important.”[1]&lt;br /&gt;
 	&lt;i&gt;- Seth Godin (Author and entrepreneur)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the previous chapter we saw the difference between leading and lagging indicators, and what can happen if you measure something that’s only loosely aligned to your overall goals. You’d be surprised at how many leaders use other people’s metrics to assess how things are going, even when they provide little information on whether business results are being achieved or values acted upon. I’ve witnessed managers obsessing over teams’ velocity&lt;i&gt;[2]&lt;/i&gt; whilst remaining ignorant of whether it bore any relation to the business outcomes (it didn’t). But, it’s easy to measure and other teams use it, so they latched onto it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, similar organisations may be looking to achieve the same thing, and in those cases metrics may be alike. But that’s the wrong place to start. A measurement should provide information that helps you decide what to do next. It needs to take you in the direction of your goals and values. The weaker the relationship between what you’re measuring and what you actually want to achieve, the less useful that information is. Using it to decide on what to do next could mean setting off on the wrong path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is for organisations taking on progressive values, including but not limited to those shared by the Agile movement. If you’re moving in that direction, then you’ll need build the following organisation abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ability to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;ORIENT&lt;/b&gt;. Have a clear view of progress towards outcomes, so that measures can be taken to support teams to correct or change course.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;RESPOND&lt;/b&gt;. React and adapt to changing requirements, so that a firm can better compete in a complex and changing environment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;COMMUNICATE&lt;/b&gt;. Creating an environment where individuals value one another and can be open, so that problems are exposed early and the creativity and potential of people can be leveraged.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;LEARN&lt;/b&gt;. To cultivate a culture of reflection and continuous improvement throughout the organisation. Across people, process and product.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building and improving these abilities isn’t easy but it will set you up for the best possible chance of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[1] Godin, Seth. ‘Measuring without Measuring’. &lt;a href=&quot;https://seths.blog/2013/06/measuring-without-measuring/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Seth’s Blog (blog), 1 June 2013&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[2] Velocity is a metric used by some Scrum teams: the number of ‘story points’ completed within a sprint. More on this later.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/use-cases-for-metrics&quot;&gt;next page (Use Cases for Metrics) &amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Chapter 2 looks at what to measure in your organisation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 3 - Orient</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/understanding-context" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 3 - Orient" /><published>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/understanding%20context</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/understanding-context">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/orient&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (Orient)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;understanding-context&quot;&gt;Understanding context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How you deliver, and how you measure progress depends on the level of complexity of the domain you’re working in. Like the well known saying; “Horses for courses” - you need to assess the approach depending on the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In their paper &lt;i&gt;“A Leader’s Framework for Decision Making”&lt;/i&gt; David Snowden and Mary Boone introduce Cynefin[1] and the five contexts; simple, complicated, complex, chaotic and disorder. For the purposes of this book, we’re interested in the contrast between the simple, the complicated and the complex in guiding our decisions on delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;b&gt;Simple&lt;/b&gt; context is stable and predictable. This is the domain of best practice - we know what works and generally there’s one clear way of doing it. Leaders should assess the facts of the situation, categorise the work and identify the best practice that fits. An off the shelf delivery plan can be followed with accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;b&gt;Complicated&lt;/b&gt; context is the &lt;i&gt;“domain of experts”&lt;/i&gt;. Here there tend to be multiple right answers. The cause and effect relationship is clear but not to everyone, which is why this domain has specialists who may advise on differing good practice. For this reason after assessing facts, analysis is needed in order to find a solution. A good way to picture the complicated context is as a machine. A driver may notice a problem, but it would take a mechanic to diagnose it. Although not straightforward for the average driver, there are manuals documenting every inch of the car  and the mechanic should be able to take it apart and put it back together. In delivery, with the right expertise complicated work follows a plan, but the more components there are, the greater need there is for regular integration to ensure the end result will work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;b&gt;Complex&lt;/b&gt; context is &lt;i&gt;“emergent”&lt;/i&gt;. There are no known answers. We need to probe - run some experiments - try some approaches, sense the impact these have made, and respond based on what we’ve learned. It requires patience and toleration of failure so that the right approach emerges, which leads to the results. For the contrast between complex and complicated, view the complex as more like an ecosystem. Changes in climate or the removal of one part of an ecosystem can have big, hard to predict knock on effects. We’ll see that more often organisations are situated in the complex context. A plan to take us to the outcome cannot exist in this context as by definition, the right way will need to be discovered with a test and learn approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contexts border upon each other, and problems occur when a mis-categorisation leads to the wrong approach. An expert may apply their good practice on a complex context that requires a more iterative, trial and error process. This can lead to massive waste and failure to achieve the goal. We cannot accurately predict the result of our actions when dealing with the Complex, which is why we must test and learn. The Agile and Business consultancy industry is full of well meaning individuals with &lt;i&gt;“man with a hammer syndrome”[2]&lt;/i&gt; when the same solution (usually an off the shelf scaling framework) is applied to every problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[1] Snowden, D. J., and M.E. Boone. ‘A Leader’s Framework for Decision Making’. Harvard Business Review 85, no. 11 (2007): 68–76.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[2] “..it is tempting, if the only tool you have is a hammer, to treat everything as if it were a nail.” - Abraham Maslow in The Psychology of Science: A Reconnaissance (1966)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/measure-orient&quot;&gt;next page (Measuring Orient) &amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Developing the organisational ability to Orient.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 3 - Orient</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/orient" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 3 - Orient" /><published>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/orient</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/orient">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/good-bad-ugly&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (The Good, the Bad and the Ugly)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;orient-the-ability-to-measure-where-you-are-in-relation-to-where-you-want-to-be&quot;&gt;Orient: the ability to measure where you are in relation to where you want to be&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What gets measured gets managed - even when it’s pointless to measure and manage it, and even if it harms the purpose of the organisation to do so.”
 	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;-Edward Deming&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What should leadership be looking at to gauge progress?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve already seen that any measurement needs to provide us with information that helps decide what to do next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-job-of-senior-management&quot;&gt;The job of Senior Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only measure something if you are prepared to act on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leadership’s job is to help teams to do their best work, to create an environment where they can excel, provide clarity of purpose and remove blockers in order for them to achieve business outcomes. Clearly to provide this support you have to know how things are progressing. This measure provides a signal as to where your help, or a decision might be needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many contexts (but not all), teams should be as autonomous as possible. Being closest to the work, and most knowledgeable about it, they’re often best placed to make decisions. The availability of information makes the decisions better, and faster too since they don’t need to pass information up the chain and wait for it to come down. I’m not saying that leadership should be over eager, on edge and jumping in at the first sign of an issue - or distrust that teams will come to them. I’m saying that there needs to be a decent feedback loop in place for management to gain awareness, give (and receive) feedback, and proactively provide support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The information should lead to &lt;b&gt;5 questions related to progress:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If teams are struggling to show progress, are there obstacles we can remove?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is there something we can provide, or do, to help them move forward?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do they need our support to move in another direction, having identified that the work isn’t providing the expected outcome?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are we recognising great work and celebrating success?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is this sustainable? Progress at the expense of health due to overwork or stress can’t be maintained and is unethical. If it isn’t sustainable and it’s hurting people, intervention is needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/understanding-context&quot;&gt;next page (Developing Orient) &amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Chapter 3 looks at how we develop and measure the abitlity to Orient.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 2 - What to measure</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/good-bad-ugly" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 2 - What to measure" /><published>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/good-bad-ugly</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/good-bad-ugly">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/use-cases-for-metrics&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (Use Cases for Metrics)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly&quot;&gt;The Good, the Bad and the Ugly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we look at developing our Organisational Abilities, we’ll encounter The Good, The Bad and The Ugly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve already seen that &lt;b&gt;Good metrics&lt;/b&gt; are an indicator related to the goal we’re trying to achieve. They provide us with information that helps us decide what to do next to achieve that goal. Working integrated software, customer satisfaction and conversion rates are examples of good metrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bad metrics&lt;/b&gt; mislead us. The information they provide does not have a meaningful bearing on our goal. When we use them to made decisions, we may as well have flipped a coin. At worst they influence decisions by sending us in the wrong direction. Bad metrics are usually measured with the best of intentions. They’re just not thought through. In software, velocity is useful for a team but it’s a bad metric for managers to use because it can be gamed at the expense of actual results. In sales, looking at sales numbers is important, but if returns and customer satisfaction aren’t taken into account then sales numbers can go up at the expense of future goodwill and profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ugly metrics&lt;/b&gt; are seriously dysfunctional, sometimes tyrannical. They’re less about the goal, and more about control or dominance. Avoid these like the plague, and if you meet or work for someone using them - question whether it’s the right place for you. I recently saw a video-calling feature being advertised to managers by an analytics company. They allow the managers to track the number and duration of video-call meetings taking place. You can imagine how this could easily be misused. Employees may set up meetings they don’t even need to meet their quota. What a powerful way for managers to make a company look busy whilst killing productivity!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In future pages we’ll revisit the Good, Bad and Ugly pattern in relation to metrics associated with abilities discussed in this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/orient&quot;&gt;next page (introducing our first Organisational Ability: Orient) &amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Chapter 2 looks at what to measure in your organisation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 3 - Orient</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/applying-approach-to-context" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 3 - Orient" /><published>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/applying-approach-to-context</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/applying-approach-to-context">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/understanding-context&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (Understanding Context)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;applying-approach-to-context&quot;&gt;Applying Approach to Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s now look at how to approach measurement of progress in the different contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;measuring-progress-when-work-is-simple-or-complicated&quot;&gt;Measuring progress when work is Simple or Complicated&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I contracted a builder to convert our loft into a bedroom. He’s done this before in very similar houses. The high level &lt;b&gt;outcome&lt;/b&gt; I wanted was space and value (since house prices go up with an additional bedroom). I could have achieved the same outcome by building a basement, an extension, a conservatory or a cabin in the garden. I had &lt;b&gt;options&lt;/b&gt;. The option I opted for was a loft conversion. The builder performed &lt;i&gt;actions&lt;/i&gt; to create the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt;, which realised the option; the converted loft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed to keep track of both the state of the option (completion of the conversion) and the outcome (whether this would give me space and value). If the loft doesn’t get converted then I have no outcome, so if I don’t follow progress how do I know that any work is happening? You may think you would just wait for them to finish the job. But would you wait indefinitely, or pay any price? I had to measure progress to some extent (I hadn’t used the builder before, and I’m not what the cowboys would call a ‘sucker’). In this case, I could measure progress by the builder checking in with me to tell me what he expected to have done at a given moment, and where he was actually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tracking the output is pretty easy in this linear and predictable example. But then it usually in Simple contexts and even at the lighter end of Complicated. Progress on the option I chose was important, but still subservient to the outcome I was looking for. If at any time it seems the option you’ve chosen won’t deliver the outcome, then you need to change tact. In this case I knew the space and value I wanted out of this would be achieved if we got the loft. But imagine if the reason I wanted the space was to take up the drums? My wife and neighbours wouldn’t put up with that upstairs. If I discovered this early on, I might be able to choose a different option. Maybe to soundproof the room, or build a cabin down the garden. The outcome is what guides the option you choose. It doesn’t matter how fast you’re driving, you’ll still be late if you’re going in the wrong direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;An option is a combination of actions or outputs that together contribute to the outcome.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my example, the builder could estimate cost accurately, because he knew all the steps to carry out the work, how long they’d take and the materials needed. This type of project is linear and predictable. He could tell for himself, and show me how things were progressing by looking at the schedule. I could also see progress by looking at the physical space, but I trusted his plan on a page because he knew what should have been done at any point in time for the project to be on track. This won’t be adequate for most of you reading this book. If you’re working in an organisation creating new products, developing and integrating software, or in any domain where work is complex and innovation and experimentation is needed, following the linear approach of planning all the work up front and tracking the plan is a bad way to measure progress. Why? Because the plan fools you into thinking you know what’s going on and what the end result will be when in fact it’s impossible to predict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;measuring-progress-in-complex-domains&quot;&gt;Measuring progress in Complex domains&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever your desired outcome. More market share. Lower customer churn. Etc. To achieve it actions will need to be taken and usually some kind of output produced. Often, in business and software development, at first it is not evident what will deliver the outcome or how technology will be used to achieve it. That’s what makes the context complex, requiring a test and learn approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take the example of a telco looking to increase market share as it’s &lt;b&gt;outcome&lt;/b&gt;. The teams have a list of ranked options that they believe will achieve this. Top of the list are several features which will bring more customers to the site. This is more than a hunch, they’ve been looking at the data they’ve got and used it to create a hypothesis for each &lt;b&gt;option&lt;/b&gt;. The work is complex, they don’t know for sure how the options will perform until they test them with real users. Expecting a fully estimated plan from them, is asking for the unknowable. Worse, held to a plan they will be pressured into delivering options (probably in the form of outputs - functionality) that don’t deliver the outcome. They’ll have done what you wanted, but it’ll have wasted everyone’s time. My builder could provide a plan, because his work involved largely things he’d done before or at worse known unknowns. The teams creating something new face &lt;i&gt;unknown unknowns&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this example, the relationship between the options (in this case functionality) and its effect on the outcome needs to be measured often because it’s not a clear cause and effect relationship. They need test often to make sure they’re on the right path and tweak accordingly. Hypothesis may be created, but they need to be tested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;In a complex context the only true measure of progress is the effect of the option on the outcome.&lt;/b&gt; In the software example, this would be measuring the effect of a new feature (the option) on market share. In development of a new antiviral drug, it would be the effect of the drug on the virus. This is how we can really tell we’re doing well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other measures are at best weak proxies, and at worst fool us into thinking progress has been made when in fact we’re standing still. You measure what matters, so if the outcome is what’s important then that’s what counts. If you are only measuring the implementation of your options (as many in business do), then you are merely focussed on output. This often happens from the top down; a senior manager will focus on an output (mistakingly equating this with the outcome), they hold their people accountable for the output and measure them against it,  and before you know it the only thing that matters is delivering the output. That’s perfect if there is a 1:1 relationship between the output and achieving your outcome, a predefined route; however with an untried route you’re simply looking at progress in mileage without checking that you’re closer to your destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Management should be focussed on the destination, but there is every reason to check the mileage if it allows for better support of the teams. Shortly we’ll see how that works. But first lets look at how breaking options down benefits delivery in a Complex context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;breaking-options-down&quot;&gt;Breaking options down&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say that you have a series of options that independently affect the outcome. Their independence is important. If an option only affects the outcome when combined with another then it’s possible to deliver a whole lot without having any realisable value. This creates waste and contributes to many failed programmes[1].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The teams break the option down in a way that suits their work. You could break an option down ad infinitum into smaller options. The constraint is that it must affect the outcome. Breaking work down into smaller batches leads to faster feedback, so smaller options can be turned around, explored, tweaked, ditched faster as teams test and learn towards their destination. These are better in Complex contexts but Complicated contexts also benefit from smaller batch sizes since an option produces benefit in the form of an affected outcome or learning. The earlier we get this, the better as we’ll start realising the benefit sooner and also reduce some of the risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;checking-the-mileage---measuring-progress-on-your-options&quot;&gt;Checking the mileage - measuring progress on your options&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of completed options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My loft converted into a bedroom.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A feature on a website.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new drug ready for trials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does completed mean? The Agile manifesto articulates the value of “working software over comprehensive documentation” because clearly you are closer to delivering value with working software than a document. The best measure of milage is the completed option; working software, a drug that can be tested, the bedroom in my loft. In the Simple and Complicated contexts where the road is known, mileage is actually a pretty good measure. Not so much for the Complex, but still the next best - and many organisations would fare much better if they stuck to this as a measure of progress rather than putting confidence in the current position in relation to a plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do we measure when the option is “complete”? Isn’t it subjective? It’s obvious that my bedroom wouldn’t be accepted as complete if the builder hadn’t connected the wiring so that electricity was available in the room. In the same way working software isn’t complete until it integrates with other components that enable it to create value. A drug being developed isn’t complete until it can be trialed. Think of it this way, for an option to be complete it needs to be at the point where it can be used or executed. This is because anything else requires further work, possibly a lot more - in the complex domain we can’t be sure. Be conscious of what a completed option should look like - the more complex the context the more concerned you should be with anything less than an executable state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Agile, teams talk about a Definition of Done to avoid doubt. It simply makes explicit everything that we think should happen, but that may be assumed by some and missed by others. This may include automated tests being in place, and documentation being updated. Things that could be unique to a team, or ambiguous can be in a definition of done. A working, integrated solution should be view as important as connecting the bedroom up to the electricity. In the latter case, it is so obvious that I don’t need to make it explicit to the builder - in the former case, it would be an advanced organisation that recognises this as obvious - they will do well from it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A completed option is executable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you see why management shouldn’t be interested in number of story points[2], number of stories completed or hours worked? They are too far removed from delivery of verifiable value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What should management be looking at?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine the following options as measures of progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;a.&lt;/b&gt; Each iteration I get a car that I can drive around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;b.&lt;/b&gt; Each iteration I get a list of completed work that’s been done to a car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;c.&lt;/b&gt; Each iteration see how many hours or work units they have managed to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your life depended on getting out a working product that affects the outcome, which would you use as a measure of progress?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Simple and Complicated contexts (&lt;b&gt;b.&lt;/b&gt;) will suffice if the right people are working on it, whilst (&lt;b&gt;a.&lt;/b&gt;) is clearly the better option. (&lt;b&gt;c.&lt;/b&gt;) is rarely useful even in these contexts - if you focus on this you will surely have everyone busy. But producing value?Management should be leaving (&lt;b&gt;b.&lt;/b&gt;) and (&lt;b&gt;c.&lt;/b&gt;) to the teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we should aim for is the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Team decides to go with X options which fit into a given time box. Could be 1, could be 10.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;At the end of the time box, a number of these options have been implemented. Some may not have been finished.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The team and relevant stakeholders, including management review the implemented options and their effect on the outcome. This is the progress. Management asks the 5 questions of themselves. If it’s too soon to measure the option’s effect on the outcome, this will need to be measured as soon as the data is available.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Feedback, learning and continue, pivot or ditch decisions are made.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The process loops back around.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Management should be reviewing progress by objectively looking at the implemented option on a given cadence. What you see above may look somewhat like a Sprint Review used in Scrum - but we can be framework agnostic. This isn’t rocket science - everyone reviews progress - the difference is in using the right measures. That means looking at things of verifiable value (the option) rather than tenuous links to the things we care about. Management shouldn’t be looking at anything other than options and outcomes. No proxies, no tenuous links, no self deception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Management tracking the work at a task level can show lack of trust. You’re better off finding great people that you don’t feel the need to task track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For simple and some complicated work, with regularity appropriate to the situation, it will give a fairly accurate view of where you are in relation to the destination. You can know how much there is to do in relation to what’s been done and take action accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For complex work this is futile. More than any other domain, you need people who can make decisions on their own and escalate only when something is outside their sphere of influence. If they’re not on track to deliver an option in a given time period, allow them to work out what to do without breathing down their necks. Constraints and difficulties can result in creative solutions. Aside from distracting the teams, looking at the tasks required to deliver the option, as we have seen, will be misleading as in the context they may change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Most organisations are operating in Complex contexts. In this situation the effect of the option on the outcome is like your SatNav telling you how much closer you are to your destination. It is the only true measure of progress.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you cannot measure the outcome at a given point, a completed option indicates you are making progress - it will either affect the outcome, or you will learn something&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[1] As an example: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/society/2013/sep/18/nhs-records-system-10bn&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;‘Abandoned NHS IT System Has Cost £10bn so Far’. The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;, 18 September 2013.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[2] Story pointing is an Agile technique whereby User Stories are given a point value. This represents the amount of work, it’s complexity and any risk and uncertainty around them. The stories are pointed relative to one another. It’s a heuristic, not a science, and for a dedicated, stable team this can make the process of deciding what to work on, and how much work to pull in faster. It’s a better, more systemic representation of the work as opposed to time based estimation. The latter takes longer, is generally less accurate (as less holistic) and encourages managers to hold people to their estimates.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;next page () &amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Applying approach to context in delivery.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 2 - What to measure</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/use-cases-for-metrics" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 2 - What to measure" /><published>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/use-cases-for-metrics</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/use-cases-for-metrics">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/what-to-measure&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (What Should we Measure?)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-cases-for-metrics&quot;&gt;Use cases for metrics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a summary of what we should measure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Common needs of managers in organisations:&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;We will look at how to:&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Ability to:&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;I want to know if we’re on track, so that I can take measures to alter our course. Correct, pivot or ditch.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Measure progress and forecast.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Orient - Chapter 3&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;I want to know and improve our ability to respond to change so that we can more quickly and effectively adapt to changing markets.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Measure and improve our agility.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Respond - Chapter 4&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;I want to increase our openness and transparency internally so that problems are exposed early and we can leverage the creativity and potential of our people.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Measure and improve openness.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Communicate - Chapter 5&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;I want to know we are evolving; improving what we are doing.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Measure and improve the culture of learning and continuous improvement.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Learn - Chapter 6&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We’ll be exploring each of these individually in detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/good-bad-ugly&quot;&gt;next page (The Good, the Bad and the Ugly) &amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Chapter 2 looks at what to measure in your organisation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 1 - Terms</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/leading-and-lagging-indicators" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 1 - Terms" /><published>2020-09-05T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/leading-and-lagging-indicators</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/leading-and-lagging-indicators">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/terms&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (Mearurements, Metrics and KPIs)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;leading-and-lagging-indicators&quot;&gt;Leading and lagging indicators&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To illustrate the difference between leading and lagging indicators, let’s look at a simple example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My daughter is learning how to play the guitar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more she practices, the better she’ll get. There’s a link between how much practice she puts in and the desired outcome, in this case good guitar playing skills. Hours practiced is a leading indicator. It provides us with information we can use to predict the future outcome before it has materialised. More practice means better guitar playing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Leading indicator: A measurement that provides information on what a situation or outcome may be in the future.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice that I’ve said &lt;i&gt;‘may’&lt;/i&gt; rather than ‘will’. Since a leading indicator predicts the future, it guides us but that doesn’t mean it will always be accurate. Sticking to the example I’ve used, there’s a well known correlation between practice and success in most activities, which makes practice a good leading indicator to influence for musical success. But, if I were to pick up the same guitar, it’s possible that no amount of practice will make me good at it. Still, it’s the best way to have a shot at becoming a rockstar!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other examples of leading indicators: the results of safety inspections as a leading indicator for safety in manufacturing companies; claims for unemployment benefit as a leading indicator for the economy; employee satisfaction as a leading indicator for staff retention; the smell coming from the kitchen as a leading indicator of a good meal. It’s not always straightforward to identify leading indicators, but when you do, you have a powerful lever for achieving your desired results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading indicators:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Help us look forward to future outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are typically harder to measure than lagging, but easier and more powerful to influence.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Predict what may happen with accuracy that varies according to the strength of the relationship between indicator and result. [1]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lagging indicators are much easier to measure, since they’re the result of past actions. This is generally an output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going back to the example I gave of my guitar playing daughter, the lagging indicator for her skill (the desired outcome) could be the number of tunes she can play, or number of errors in the tunes. Easy to measure, however harder to leverage and influence. If she knows that practice helps her to improve, and she works on that leading indicator (in this case practicing more), she knows it will improve her proficiency. In contrast, the lagging indicators show the results of past actions and as such are only useful in telling us how we’ve done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lagging indicator: A measurement that provides information on what a situation has been like in the past.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focussing on lagging indicators can be counter productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“People do what you count, not necessarily what counts” [2].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you focus on the indicator, it can lead to optimising for output over outcome. In our musical example, let’s say we focus on the lagging indicator ‘number of errors’. This could influence my daughter to pick easy, or short tunes which will indeed most likely lead to fewer errors. However, if our desired outcome is improved guitar skill then this is missing the point. A complicated tune with a few errors is surely demonstrating more skill than an easy song with none. In business this kind of focus on outputs over outcomes is common. It could be a development team hitting targets for the number of features delivered, whilst not delivering business results; or a manufacturing plant hitting targets for the number of units delivered, but causing the business to loose money with high levels of returns due to defects. That’s why &lt;b&gt;we need to be really careful of what we measure.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other examples of typical lagging indicators: number of sales, number of projects delivered, revenue, staff turnover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lagging indicators:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Look backwards, showing us the results of past actions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Typically emphasise outputs over outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are easy to measure, but do not provide the leverage to improve. By the time you’re looking at the result, it’s too late to do anything about it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can be gamed, at the expense of the outcome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why does this matter? &lt;b&gt;Think of the leading indicators as the rudder of a ship. You use them to steer and change course. The lagging indicators should be the radar system and GPS. They show where you are. Used together in the right way they are important tools to achieve desired outcomes.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[1] Practice is closely related to guitar skill, but if I use quality of service in a restaurant as a leading indicator for a great meal, I may be disappointed (or surprised) more often than not when I get a bad meal with impeccable service, or vice versa.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[2] Seddon, John. I Want You to Cheat!: The Unreasonable Guide to Service and Quality in Organisation. Buckingham: Vanguard Press, 2007. p83&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/options-and-outcomes&quot;&gt;next page (Options and Outcomes) &amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Leading and lagging indicators.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 1 - Terms</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/options-and-outcomes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 1 - Terms" /><published>2020-09-05T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/options-and-outcomes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/options-and-outcomes">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/leading-and-lagging-indicators&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (Leading and Lagging Indicators)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;outcomes-options-and-tasks&quot;&gt;Outcomes, Options and Tasks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There many frameworks, methods and practices for breaking work down. I like to keep things simple, and where possible universal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An &lt;b&gt;Outcome&lt;/b&gt; is a high level business objective. Something that happens as the result of something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get an outcome, you need &lt;b&gt;Options&lt;/b&gt;. These can be actions or outputs that once completed contribute to the outcome in a measurable way. There may be many options that would satisfy an outcome. It’s up to you to decide which is best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To carry out an Option, whether it’s building something or doing something, you’ll need to carry out &lt;b&gt;Tasks&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outcome: Increased market share 
Options: New social share features on website. Advertising campaign. Takeover competitor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big Options can be broken down into small Options - we’ll get to why that’s a good idea and look at some examples in Chapter 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some common terms and how they relate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User stories - called such to emphasise the value of understanding within the team, and from the perspective of who a feature is for, what it is and what the purpose of it is. A user story would be an option as would any parent big picture item, often called an “Epic”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Requirements - these would be a subset of an Option. Criteria to tell us what should be included. Rarely of value on their own, typically in Agile requirements manifest as acceptance criteria within user stories.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bets - I like the implication that we don’t know if it will work. All options in the complex context are bets. When you move into the simple or complicated context and you start dealing  with sure things, the term “option” holds better and more broadly.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/what-to-measure&quot;&gt;next page (CHAPTER 2 - What to Measure) &amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Options and outcomes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 1 - Terms</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/terms" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 1 - Terms" /><published>2020-09-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/terms</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/terms">&lt;h2 id=&quot;measurements-metrics-and-kpis&quot;&gt;Measurements, metrics and KPIs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often the terms measurements, metrics and KPIs are used interchangeably, however there are some differences. Measurement is defined by Douglas W. Hubbard in his excellent book “How to Measure Anything”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Measurement: a set of observations that reduce uncertainty where the result is expressed as a quantity.
[1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A measurement should provide us with information that helps us decide what to do next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, lets say that managers in one organisation want to improve staff retention. They carry out a set of actions, measuring staff turnover before and after. If turnover has reduced, then they have an indication that what they have done has worked, they either keep doing it, tweak it or do nothing. If it hasn’t, then they know something has to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although often used interchangeably with measurement, a metric is the product of a calculation, a method for measurement or a measurement from a standardised system. For example, a telecoms operator uses a customer churn metric to measure how well they’re doing at retaining customers (number of churned customers / total number of customers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term key performance indicator (KPI) refers to measurements or metrics that are specifically used in relation to business related objectives. They signal that this is an important measurement for success. Going back to our previous example of the customer churn metric, if this is something the company will want to move the needle on, it will be considered a KPI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lead-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/measurement-terms.png&quot; alt=&quot;metric kpi and measurement relationship diagram&quot; style=&quot;max-width:100%;&quot; /&gt;
￼
&lt;i&gt;[1] Hubbard, Douglas W. How to Measure Anything: Finding the Value of ‘Intangibles’ in Business. Hoboken, N.J: John Wiley &amp;amp; Sons, 2007. p21 &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/leading-and-lagging-indicators&quot;&gt;next page (Leading and Lagging Indicators) &amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Terms.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Unlimited Memory by Kevin Horsley</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/unlimited-memory-by-kevin-horsley" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unlimited Memory by Kevin Horsley" /><published>2020-08-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-08-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/unlimited-memory-by-kevin-horsley</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/unlimited-memory-by-kevin-horsley">&lt;p&gt;Some powerful strategies for memorisation and recall. Quite a bit is overly explained; the techniques are simple (a good thing). I skimmed over fluff and pulled out what I thought could be useful. I have no need to remember long strings of numbers, but linking names and information to images and other associations is something I’ll use.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-big-idea&quot;&gt;The big idea&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the senses and your imagination to enhance memory. Associate numbers and names with sounds, images, emotions; massively improves your recall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-notes&quot;&gt;My notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;images-are-powerful&quot;&gt;Images are powerful&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;People that learn quickly or have a so - called photographic memory apply creativity to everything they learn.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;When you see information as an image in your mind, you can jump in and out of it; this improves your understanding.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;neuroscientist John Medina said, “Hear a piece of information and three days later you’ll remember 10 percent of it. Add a picture and you’ll remember 65 percent. ”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The SEE Principle
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;S — Senses&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;E — Exaggeration&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;E — Energize: Give your mental pictures action. Would you rather watch a movie of your holiday or a slide show? What creates more feeling in your imagination: a horse standing still or a horse that is running and moving?&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The greatest secret to having a powerful memory is bringing information to life with your endless imagination.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Organizing new information is key to retention and retrieval.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;use-your-car-or-body-to-remember&quot;&gt;Use your car or body to remember&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The car list works because your whole car is in your long - term memory (LTM). LTM offers you a place to store the new information; that is, the locations in the car become “ storage compartments ” for short - term memories (STMs). All the memory methods in this book work with this formula: LTM + STM = MTM&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The body method was originally invented by the ancient Greeks. You can use it to remember information for exams, work, shopping, or any list of items.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;remembering-numbers&quot;&gt;Remembering numbers&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The “ shape peg ” method was developed in 1651 by Henry Herdson, who linked numbers to objects shaped like the digits. The “rhyming peg ” method was introduced two centuries later by John Sambrook in 1879.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Rhyming Pegs - eg 1 = fun&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The 10 emotions of power help you remember. Use one of them with a peg.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The 10 emotions of power are: Love and warmth Appreciation and gratitude Curiosity Excitement and passion Determination Flexibility Confidence Cheerfulness Vitality Contribution&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Shape Pegs The second peg method, the shape system, converts numbers into concrete shapes. It works in the same way as the rhyming peg method, only this time the pegs are shaped like the number.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;linking-thoughts&quot;&gt;Linking Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can remember all 45 presidents just by linking one thought to the next. If you have any problems recalling the list, just make it more detailed and make the links clearer. Here is the list of the first 12 presidents: George Washington: washing a tin.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;remembering-names&quot;&gt;Remembering Names&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;“Remember that a person’s name is to that person the sweetest and most important sound in any language”. — Dale Carnegie&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Concentrate
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;the first thing you have to do is take control of the introduction so you can slow it down. Next, pay attention and really listen to the name, because if you don’t hear it you will not remember it. As Oliver Wendel Holmes said, “ A person must get a thing before they can forget it. ” If you hear the name, repeat it back to the person ; this will improve your recall. If you don’t hear the name, ask the person to say it again. If it is a difficult name, ask them to spell it, too. Listen and be genuinely interested in the other person’s name.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Create
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Create an image for the name in your mind so you can recreate it later.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Connect
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Remember that all learning is creating relationships between the known and the unknown. When you’re introduced to someone, you see ( know ) their face — an image — so you need to connect their unknown name to their known face. When you see their face again it must act as a trigger or peg to bring the name to your awareness. Here are some methods to make the connection. All the methods listed here take a great deal longer to explain than to use. Comparison Connection With this method, you connect the person to a name that you already know.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Face Connection&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;With this method, you make a link between the name and an outstanding feature in the person’s appearance. Every face is unique and every face has an outstanding feature.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Meeting Location Connection&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Continuous Use
 	- If you concentrate, get the name, make it meaningful, and connect it to the person, you will remember it for the short term. To make the name stick in your long - term memory, however, you have to continue using it. Talk about their name. If it is a foreign name ask the person what it means. How do they spell it? Also, use their name in conversation.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;presenting-from-memory&quot;&gt;Presenting from Memory&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Great presenters know that audiences tend to remember:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;F — First things&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;L — Last things&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;O — Outstanding information&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;O — Own links&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;R — Repeated information&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Therefore, they make their introductions and conclusions powerful and outstanding. They open with memorable demonstrations, questions, facts, quotations, or meaningful stories. They also continually link information to the audience, make it more outstanding, and repeat the main points. If you design your presentation with the FLOOR principle in mind, your audience will remember more — and your presentation will be more enjoyable.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="self-development" /><category term="memory" /><summary type="html">Some powerful strategies for memorisation and recall. Quite a bit is overly explained; the techniques are simple (a good thing). I skimmed over fluff and pulled out what I thought could be useful. I have no need to remember long strings of numbers, but linking names and information to images and other associations is something I’ll use.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/memory.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/memory.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>