<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://kaufie.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://kaufie.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-02-20T18:55:48+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/feed.xml</id><subtitle>Sasha Kaufmann's profile website and article archive.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Brave New World by Aldous Huxley</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/brave-new-world-by-aldous-huxley" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Brave New World by Aldous Huxley" /><published>2021-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/brave-new-world-by-aldous-huxley</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/brave-new-world-by-aldous-huxley">&lt;p&gt;A very different dystopia from the brutal totalitarianism of 1984. A civilisation where everything is stable and happiness is only a pill away. There’s little disease and hunger, pleasure is on tap yet there’s also no real intimacy. A ‘savage’ visits and learns that this world is empty and superficial. It’s an interesting future and despite feeling like the characters weren’t much developed it was a readable book. But I found it unsatisfying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this world either we’ve got savagery, pain and suffering or empty superficial lives of pleasure and consumerism. The book paints an ‘either-or’ picture which didn’t resonate with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huxley himself said more than a decade later that there should have been a middle ground. It’s insufficient to merely have the choice of embracing suffering or rejecting a life of meaning. The world is not that simple and clearly the more comfortable your position in life, the easier it is to decry the boredom of a stable society where all basic needs are met. He never clearly states that the ‘civilisation’ is worse than the savagery, but I felt it was implied weakly and if there was a philosophical point it wasn’t properly developed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huxley looks prophetic given the book’s echos of the consumerist society we live in today (it was just emerging at the time he wrote it) and the superficiality of our social media culture. People will see what they want to in this and make all sorts of comparisons (after all, it’s natural to see patterns); not a bad thing. Still a good book but if you’re only going to read one dystopian classic then make it 1984.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;World State’s motto: Community, Identity, Stability.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Barbaric things for the ‘collective good’.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hatcheries farm embryos. Depriving of foetuses of oxygen to lower intelligence. Epsilons, the lower caste. Manipulating embryos according to the job they’ll be doing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conditioning: making people grateful for their unescapable social destiny.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;God is “Our Ford”. Signing of the model “T”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Everybody belongs to everybody else”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No real intimacy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;John the Savage, disappointed with this Brave New World (Shakespeare).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bernard Marx enjoys superficial favour whilst he has his guest. He’s quite a pathetic character. Different, curious, intelligent but also vain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being sent to an island, such as Iceland, is the punishment. Yet it’s where all the interesting people are. Marx doesn’t appreciate this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People conditioned to hate solitude.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stability of civilisation is the reason for all these measures; hatcheries, breeding, conventions, soma (drug).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The savage; “But I don’t want comfort. I want God, I want poetry, I want real danger, I want freedom, I want goodness. I want sin.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="fiction" /><category term="classics" /><category term="dystopian" /><summary type="html">A very different dystopia from the brutal totalitarianism of 1984. A civilisation where everything is stable and happiness is only a pill away. There’s little disease and hunger, pleasure is on tap yet there’s also no real intimacy. A ‘savage’ visits and learns that this world is empty and superficial. It’s an interesting future and despite feeling like the characters weren’t much developed it was a readable book. But I found it unsatisfying.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-brave-new-world.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-brave-new-world.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Modern delivery principles for complex work</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/modern-delivery-principles-for-complex-work" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Modern delivery principles for complex work" /><published>2021-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/modern-delivery-principles-for-complex-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/modern-delivery-principles-for-complex-work">&lt;h2 id=&quot;values-guide-behaviours-we-choose-these&quot;&gt;Values guide behaviours. We choose these.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These values are correlated with successful delivery and motivated people in modern enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People&lt;/strong&gt; come first. Creating an environment where they have safety to be open, to be human and where communication between individuals and teams is effective is a moral obligation and leads to better business results.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning and improvement&lt;/strong&gt; should be part of daily work for people, process and product. It will bring innovation, continuous improvement and fulfilment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Constant &lt;strong&gt;connection to the customer&lt;/strong&gt; should be maintained for rapid, frequent feedback. External and internal. So we can understand their needs, respond to them and continually improve that response to move towards the best possible outcome.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flow&lt;/strong&gt; of customer value delivered continuously. When flow of value is accounted for in organisation design and the way work is broken down and delivered, it means faster value realisation, decreased risk, faster learning, lower stress and cognitive load, happier people and teams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;principles-are-universal-truths-and-observations-our-values-shape-the-principles-we-choose-to-follow&quot;&gt;Principles are universal truths and observations. Our values shape the Principles we choose to follow.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;flow-of-value&quot;&gt;Flow of value&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Handoffs and dependencies cause friction. The more friction, the more misunderstandings, rework, failure demand, greater cognitive load, wait times and work in progress. Small cross functional teams improve communication, ownership and reduce the aforementioned. Strive for autonomy; every dependency doubles your chance of being delayed or late.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where handoffs exist, explicit policies, events and working agreements improve their quality. Minimise rather than manage dependencies.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prioritisation and focus is vital. WIP increases cycle time of work and delays delivery of business value. Too much reduces flow, increases context switching, reduces quality and motivation. If everything is a priority, then nothing is. It’ll all be late.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;learning-and-improvement&quot;&gt;Learning and improvement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Embrace change; if we find out something needs to change it means we were heading in the wrong direction. Find out and act quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Small batches allow more frequent delivery of value, reduced risk and faster learning. Find the sweet spot between batch size and the tradeoffs of economies of scale.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Progress towards the desired outcome is the primary measure of progress. Working software is an inferior proxy, but better than any percentage complete type measure. We shouldn’t put confidence in anything until we can see it working.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For effective learning to happen, business areas, customers and development must be part of a tightly knit feedback loop.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To improve the Product, Process and People (relationships and working patterns) we must inspect these areas on a regular basis and adapt as necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pursue improvement through evolutionary change. In the complex context we discover the answers through inspection and incremental changes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transparency through visualisation improves collaboration.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collect, find and use data. Be data informed rather than data driven.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;environment&quot;&gt;Environment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stability and consistency produce more sustainable, predictable environments.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Psychological safety is essential for discovering issues early, which is a prerequisite for fixing them early.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People need purpose, autonomy and mastery in their work to be motivated. Connection to others produces a great working environment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Communication should be frequent and explicit. Where teams interact, working agreements and policies smooth interactions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;grappling-with-complex-contexts&quot;&gt;Grappling with complex contexts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aim for the simplest viable solution: minimise work, facilitate knowledge transfer and ease maintainability.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be effective first, efficient second. Only put your foot on the accelerator when you know you’re heading in the right direction..&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Commit at the ‘last responsible moment’; minimise the possibility of wasted effort, maximise the chance of learning something new before starting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="agile" /><category term="agility" /><category term="agile" /><summary type="html">What works.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">1984 by George Orwell</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/1984-by-george-orwell" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="1984 by George Orwell" /><published>2021-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/1984-by-george-orwell</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/1984-by-george-orwell">&lt;p&gt;Winston is a functionary in a totalitarian state. He begins to rebel, and meets a girl, but finds that he’s no match for the system. As Orwell wrote this the Allies were battling Fascism, Stalinism was showing its true colours, and it looked like no matter the ideology all roads led to authoritarianism and consolidation of power (to the disillusionment of many communists). There’s a fairly dull patch around the middle, but it’s a powerful book and it became a fixture of popular culture, influencing many other dystopian visions.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Side note:&lt;/strong&gt; I learned that much of the plot is very similar to Yevgeny Zamyatin’s novel ‘We’; which written in 1924 some 25 years prior to the publication of 1984, is in fact the first dystopian novel. Even so, there are many aspects of 1984 which are dystopian “classics” such as Thought Crime, Room 101 and Newspeak which all shaped the genre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Newspeak: exerting control by changing language.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Hate: enemy created to draw attention and anger.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The party
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;“ Who controls the past controls the future: who controls the present controls the past.“ &lt;/i&gt;- called “reality control”.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Slogans: War is peace, freedom is slavery, ignorance is strength&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Winston (protagonist) on the proles, the masses; &lt;i&gt;“Until they become conscious they will never rebel, and until after they have rebelled they cannot become conscious.“&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proles p76: &lt;i&gt;“All that was required of them was a primitive patriotism which could be appealed to whenever it was necessary to make them accept longer working hours or shorter rations.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The all-seeing Telescreen invites parallels between smart devices in homes. But it seems that all new technology or at least a great deal of it has the potential both for uses that improve peoples lives and the use by governments and organisations for nefarious purposes. Atomic energy provides clean power for millions but the science also brought the atomic bomb. The advent of motor transport and aviation allows people to travel and move around more freely but also agents of control to do so. Smart devices in homes enables easy communication, easy entertainment and connection to others but also the potential for monitoring and snooping. Same can be said with connectivity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“&lt;i&gt;All this marching up and down and cheering and waving flags is simply sex gone sour. If you’re happy inside yourself, why should you get excited about Big Brother and Three-Year-Plans and the Two-Minutes-Hate and all the rest of the bloody rot?“&lt;/i&gt;p142&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;“There was a direct intimate connection between chastity and political orthodoxy. For how could the fear, the hatred and the lunatic credulity which the party needed in its members be kept at the right pitch, except by bottling down some powerful instinct and using it as a driving force? The sex impulse was dangerous to the party, and the party had turned it to account.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Children… were systematically turned against the parents and taught to spy on them and report the deviations. ..the family had become in affect an extension of the Thought Police.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="fiction" /><category term="classics" /><category term="dystopian" /><summary type="html">Winston is a functionary in a totalitarian state. He begins to rebel, and meets a girl, but finds that he’s no match for the system. As Orwell wrote this the Allies were battling Fascism, Stalinism was showing its true colours, and it looked like no matter the ideology all roads led to authoritarianism and consolidation of power (to the disillusionment of many communists). There’s a fairly dull patch around the middle, but it’s a powerful book and it became a fixture of popular culture, influencing many other dystopian visions.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-1984.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-1984.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Candide and Other Stories by Voltaire</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/candide-and-other-stories-by-voltaire" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Candide and Other Stories by Voltaire" /><published>2021-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/candide-and-other-stories-by-voltaire</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/candide-and-other-stories-by-voltaire">&lt;p&gt;Candide is a philosophical tale with real events mixed in; a shocking and humorous satire on Voltaire’s times with problems that haven’t really gone away; greed, exploitation, corruption, debauchery and violence. Voltaire challenges the beliefs of Leibnitzian optimism and determinism, religion and the many churches of the time.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Candide is an innocent, naive chap who suffers many (many!) misfortunes whilst trying to reunite with his love, Cunégonde. He and other characters suffer floggings, beatings, sacking, rape, mutilation, inquisitors, selfishness, and thieving. Through all this suffering and injustice he very slowly comes to understand (barely) the ridiculousness of the view ingrained in him by his philosopher teacher Pangloss that all is for the best in the world and everything is well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still relevant to our times and never boring this rightly lives on as a classic. Aside from its attacks and satire, the morale is summed up near the end. The Turk states “Work keeps us from three great evils: boredom, vice, and need”. “We must cultivate our garden”. I take this to mean that work and conscious effort is needed to live well; in contrast to the Leibnitzian view of things being as they are for a reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;micromégas&quot;&gt;Micromégas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A philosophical tale about a giant being visiting our planet, who hears of the deeds men do to one another for a few small lumps of earth. “…deep down he was a trifle vexed to see that being so infinitesimally small should have a degree of pride that was almost infinitely great.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;zadig&quot;&gt;Zadig&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An asian tale of a clever, virtuous and courageous man who benefits from his attributes but also suffers for them. “ in this world things did not always turn out the way wisemen wanted.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-white-bull&quot;&gt;The White Bull&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A story of the Middle east based on the Greek mythological tale of Europa and the bull (where the white bull is the king of the Greek gods, Zeus, in disguise). A princess encounters an old woman with a beautiful white bull and other animals from scripture (the serpent, doves, a whale). It is in fact her love, a prince. She is entranced by it but her father wishes to have it sacrificed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Candide
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Philosophy (Leibnitzian). Everything works out for the best. Everything happens for a reason.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The nose is there for spectacles. Legs are created to wear trousers.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Dr Pangloss - “Individual misfortunes contribute to the general good with the result that the more individual misfortunes there are, the more all is well.”&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The bad things that happen to Candide he thinks good and inevitable once a good end is obtained.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Characters have little agency. When the good Anabaptist is drowning; it’s fine, thats why the harbour is there.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“It is impossible for things not to be where they are. For all is well.”&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Harsh world. Floggings, beatings, sacking, rape, inquisitors, selfishness, theiving.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Candide-“If this is the best of all possible worlds what must the others be like?“; he’d just had a flogging and seen his mentor being hanged by the inquisitors.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Encounters a sugar processing slave in Surinam with a missing hand and foot. Suffering so that the Europeans can enjoy their sugar. Not unlike the third world today.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After escaping the inquisitors in Portugal travels to Argentina, then Paraguay. Finds and kills Cunegonde’s brother a Jesuit, encounters natives, El Dorado, the pirate, return voyage to Venice.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;No-one is happy on closer inspection- the Theatine monk and Paquette. Even the Venetian nobleman who has everything is unhappy with it - bored. Only in the mythical land of El Dorado, which is unattainable, are people truly happy.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Yet eventually he finds and frees Cunégonde and lives on a farm with his small group. There they are bored and miserable.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Old woman: “I would like to know which is worse: being raped 100 times by negro pirates, having a buttock chopped off, running the gauntlet of the Bulgars, being flogged and hanged in an auto-da-fé, being dissected, rowing in a galley, in short suffering all the misfortunes we all suffered, or simply being stuck here and doing nothing? “That is a good question”, said Candide. This speech gave rise to renewed speculation, and Martin in particular came to the conclusion that man was born to spend his life ultimately a pray to the throes of anxiety and the lethargy of boredom.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Morals at the end:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The Turk: ‘Work keeps us from three great evils: boredom, vice, and need.”&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“We must cultivate our garden” - you make the best of the world.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zadig
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“..self-esteem is a balloon filled with wind, from which great tempests surge when it is pricked.”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hermes the doctor says Zadig will loose an eye. All Babylon marvelled at the depth of his knowledge…but it is cured. He writes a book proving it shouldn’t have got better. Zadig didn’t read it. = Iatrogenics&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Zadig is desperately trying to be happy.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“It is to Zadig that nations owe the great principle that it is better to risk sparing a guilty man than it is to condemn an innocent one.”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Woman who will throw herself on the funeral pyre: “..one has to do the done thing.” - compliance.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After getting his armour and emblem robbed, and his chances of becoming king of Babylon ruined by the cowardly Itobad, Zadig says there it is; ‘education, virtue, courage: they brought me nothing but disaster’.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It was agreed in the course of conversation that in this world things did not always turn out the way wisemen wanted.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Ingenu
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A foreigner in Brittany. Speaks to the ridiculousness of organised religion. The rules of men vs God. The Ingenu breaks and questions them. Eg why not marrying his godmother. Nothing in the scriptures.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For having learnt nothing at all in his childhood, he had not acquired any prejudices.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Iatrogenics the cause of the Ingenu’s love Saint-Yves’ death.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="fiction" /><category term="classics" /><summary type="html">Candide is a philosophical tale with real events mixed in; a shocking and humorous satire on Voltaire’s times with problems that haven’t really gone away; greed, exploitation, corruption, debauchery and violence. Voltaire challenges the beliefs of Leibnitzian optimism and determinism, religion and the many churches of the time.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-candide.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-candide.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Making Work Visible by Domenica DeGrandis</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/making-work-visible-by-Domenica-DeGrandis" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making Work Visible by Domenica DeGrandis" /><published>2021-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/making-work-visible-by-Domenica-DeGrandis</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/making-work-visible-by-Domenica-DeGrandis">&lt;p&gt;Accessible guide to making work visible; exposing time thieves and using Kanban practices to improve flow. So easy to read it’s great as a refresher for practitioners and a strong entry point for pretty much everyone else.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make work visible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Limit work-in-progress (WIP).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Measure and manage the flow of work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prioritise effectively.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make adjustments based on lessons from feedback and metrics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-5-thieves-of-time&quot;&gt;The 5 thieves of time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too much work in progress (WIP)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unknown dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unplanned work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conflicting priorities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Neglected work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-expose-time-theft-to-optimise-workflow&quot;&gt;How to expose time theft to optimise workflow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make work visible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make WIP visible and limit it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Expose dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unplanned work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prioritise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prevent negligence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;flow-metrics&quot;&gt;Flow metrics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flow time: a measure of how long something took to do from beginning to end.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cycle time: ambiguous - different meanings depending on who you ask.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WIP is a leading indicator.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little’s Law assumptions
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;All measure units are consistent.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Average arrival rate = average departure rate.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;All work that enters the system flows to competion and exists.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Average age of WIP is neither increasing or decreasing.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The total amount of WIP is roughly the same at the beginning and at the end.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Queuing Theory
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;There’s a direct correlation between WIP and capacity utilization.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Unpredictable events cause variability. The more variability, the more vulnerable we are to capacity overload.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The single biggest factor that affects queue size is capacity utilization.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kingman’s formula shows an approximation for the average wait time in a queue.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;As we move from 60%-80% utilization, the queue doubles. As we move from 80%-90% it doubles again.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;finding-out-where-waste-is-emerging&quot;&gt;Finding out where waste is emerging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consider measuring:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Unplanned work&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Unknown dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Conflicting priorities&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Neglacted work&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reporting
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Aging reports&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Card type distribution&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Failure load (value demand vs failure demand)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Flow efficiency&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="non-fiction" /><category term="kanban" /><category term="lean" /><category term="ways-of-working" /><summary type="html">Accessible guide to making work visible; exposing time thieves and using Kanban practices to improve flow. So easy to read it’s great as a refresher for practitioners and a strong entry point for pretty much everyone else.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-making-work-visible.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-making-work-visible.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Agent Sonya - Lover, Mother, Soldier, Spy by Ben Macintyre</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/agent-sonya-by-ben-macintyre" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Agent Sonya - Lover, Mother, Soldier, Spy by Ben Macintyre" /><published>2021-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/agent-sonya-by-ben-macintyre</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/agent-sonya-by-ben-macintyre">&lt;p&gt;The remarkable life of Ursula Kuczynski. German Jewish communist, mother, radio technician, writer, spy and spymaster. Carrying out covert activities through the horrors of Nazism; in Japanese occupied China, spy ridden Switzerland and in the rolling hills of the Cotswolds. The engrossing life story of an idealistic (albeit ultimately misguided), determined and very tough woman. Recommended.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="spy" /><category term="espionage" /><category term="ww2" /><category term="russia" /><summary type="html">The remarkable life of Ursula Kuczynski. German Jewish communist, mother, radio technician, writer, spy and spymaster. Carrying out covert activities through the horrors of Nazism; in Japanese occupied China, spy ridden Switzerland and in the rolling hills of the Cotswolds. The engrossing life story of an idealistic (albeit ultimately misguided), determined and very tough woman. Recommended.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-sonya.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-sonya.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Into Thin Air by Jon Krakauer</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/into-thin-air-by-jon-krakauer" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Into Thin Air by Jon Krakauer" /><published>2021-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/into-thin-air-by-jon-krakauer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/into-thin-air-by-jon-krakauer">&lt;p&gt;This is an account of the 1996 Everest disaster by a journalist who was with one of the groups. Eight climbers lost their lives; the author attempts to get to the heart of what happened up there. It’s rarely a single mistake that creates these events. In this case we learn about the commercialisation of Everest, the danger of inexperienced climbers paying to be taken up, the competition between tour groups and the myriad of human errors that happen when the brain is starved of oxygen. As fascinating as the subject is, the book is brilliantly written, with an engaging build up and a pace that keeps the page turning. This one went quickly.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="adventure" /><category term="mountaineering" /><category term="survival" /><summary type="html">This is an account of the 1996 Everest disaster by a journalist who was with one of the groups. Eight climbers lost their lives; the author attempts to get to the heart of what happened up there. It’s rarely a single mistake that creates these events. In this case we learn about the commercialisation of Everest, the danger of inexperienced climbers paying to be taken up, the competition between tour groups and the myriad of human errors that happen when the brain is starved of oxygen. As fascinating as the subject is, the book is brilliantly written, with an engaging build up and a pace that keeps the page turning. This one went quickly.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-intothinair.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-intothinair.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The fast way to identify bad technique</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/the-fast-way-to-identify-bad-technique" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The fast way to identify bad technique" /><published>2021-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/the-fast-way-to-identify-bad-technique</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/the-fast-way-to-identify-bad-technique">&lt;p&gt;Technique achieves mastery. It’s the skill with which you do something. To refine it you need to learn what you’re doing right, but more crucially what you’re doing wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you do weights, the heavier you go, the clearer the feedback you get on bad technique; you get hurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt a healthy fear the first time I lifted a 24kg kettlebell. The kind you feel to stop yourself from doing something stupid. I could tell that if I held it in the wrong way, or moved badly it could snap my arm like a twig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do what’s called the Turkish get-up. You start off laid on your back, lift the kettlebell up overhead and in a series of movements stand up and then in reverse lie back down. Every time I used it I’d concentrate on the way I held it, where the weight was positioned and how I moved with it. The more muscle I built, the easier it became and the less my technique mattered. I’d concentrate less and take it in my stride. When I got the 32kg I again felt a good, healthy kind of fear. Less than the first time, but it was there all the same. But I’d got used to focussing on muscle over technique, so when I lifted it overhead I damaged my shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back, I now realise that I was lifting it wrongly; pulling it instead of bringing it first to my chest and pushing it up. What I’d done before worked for the 24, but it was only by moving up to the 32 that I really learned something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is; the further past your comfort zone you go, the more powerful the feedback, because the more technique matters. It’s clear with weights, because the price is high and tangible (physically paid in pain). The principle is also true of other sports, activities and things in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A trainer or coach can help improve technique without you having to go through that pain. With weights thats probably the smart way of doing it. In general though nothing helps you grow and learn more than first hand experience. It’s the pain, physical or psychological, that makes you change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A reminder: push beyond your comfort zone to significantly improve. But make sure your technique is “good enough” to take the real or metaphorical weight.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="life" /><category term="technique" /><category term="skill" /><category term="life" /><summary type="html">Push beyond your comfort zone without getting hurt.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/kettlebell.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/kettlebell.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hard Boiled Wonderland and the End of the World by Haruki Murakami</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/hard-boiled-wonderland-and-the-end-of-the-world-by-haruki-murakami" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hard Boiled Wonderland and the End of the World by Haruki Murakami" /><published>2020-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/hard-boiled-wonderland-and-the-end-of-the-world-by-haruki-murakami</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/hard-boiled-wonderland-and-the-end-of-the-world-by-haruki-murakami">&lt;p&gt;This book delivers on a number of things you’d expect from Murakami; it’s surreal, has tonnes of references to 60/70/80s pop culture, plus detailed descriptions of cooking and characters getting on with life. There’s a lot to like, including a parallel story connected to the main narrative which felt similar to a Kafka novel. Alas, the sci-fi dystopian bent didn’t do anything for me. Talk about Semiotecs, shuffling and brain connections (etc.) I found more silly than surreal. It got pretty tedious. Ok but not one of his best books.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-notes&quot;&gt;My notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deep rivers run quiet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I love these descriptions of food (goes on for a few pages). “While I waited for her, I fixed supper. I mashed an umeboshi salt plum with mortar and pestle to make a sour-sweet dressing; I fried up a few sardines with abura-agé tofu-puffs in grated yama-imo taro batter; I sautéed a celery-beef side dish. Not a bad little meal.” p89&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Histories within stories. Characters reading books in a book. The discovery of a unicorn skull in Ukraine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="book" /><category term="fiction" /><category term="short-stories" /><summary type="html">This book delivers on a number of things you’d expect from Murakami; it’s surreal, has tonnes of references to 60/70/80s pop culture, plus detailed descriptions of cooking and characters getting on with life. There’s a lot to like, including a parallel story connected to the main narrative which felt similar to a Kafka novel. Alas, the sci-fi dystopian bent didn’t do anything for me. Talk about Semiotecs, shuffling and brain connections (etc.) I found more silly than surreal. It got pretty tedious. Ok but not one of his best books.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-hard-boiled.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-hard-boiled.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Navigating without a map</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/navigating-without-a-map" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Navigating without a map" /><published>2020-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/navigating-without-a-map</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/navigating-without-a-map">&lt;p&gt;What are the best things to have happened to you in life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you’re thinking of when you met your partner. Your kids. Starting a business. Lifelong friends. A career you love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suspect that some of these things were planned out. Others were the direct or indirect result of being in the right place, at the right time and of the decisions you made in the moment. Most of the time you only know that it’s the right place when you’re there. You can’t plan for it, which is why seeing every situation as having the potential for something amazing to happen and maximising that chance is a far better strategy than planning life out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are two approaches to life that aren’t mutually exclusive: We can focus on creating a plan, on drawing a map. We can also work on building the skills to get over the fact that we don’t have one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does a map give you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clarity of where to go, the route.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Comfort and security, you know the way and can see your progress.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A way to show others where you’re going and what you’re doing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your destination is specific and there’s only one route; if your journey is far and hard; if you don’t have time for any detours; then you need a map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focussing on having a map means spending a lot of time planning and waiting for the right moment for something to happen. If you do that, you’ll get on the route, and you’ll probably make it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we can obsess over having a map. That’s a mistake; again, life is often so uncertain that we don’t even know our destination, let alone what will happen along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the other strategy: rather than focussing on the map, build the skills to navigate without one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Knowing what’s important to you. The direction is more important than the route.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learning how to explore, read signs along the way, assess situations and make fast decisions based on the information available, your gut and their &lt;a href=&quot;/bold-decisions-reversible&quot;&gt;reversibility&lt;/a&gt;. Often this means learning by doing and making mistakes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Going on detours. Finding some dead ends. Discovering the hidden gems of life off the beaten track.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use a map, you’re efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can handle life without a map, you’re resilient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an unpredictable world be the latter.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="life" /><category term="decisions" /><category term="development" /><category term="life" /><summary type="html">Go on detours. Find some dead ends. Discover the hidden gems of life off the beaten track.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/navi-without-a-map.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/navi-without-a-map.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>