<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://kaufie.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://kaufie.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-10T14:08:37+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/feed.xml</id><subtitle>Sasha Kaufmann's profile website and article archive.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 4 - Respond</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/respond" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 4 - Respond" /><published>2020-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/respond</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/respond">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/forecasting&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (forecasting)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respond&quot;&gt;Respond&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming in October 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Respond.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 3 - Orient</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/forecasting" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 3 - Orient" /><published>2020-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/forecasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/forecasting">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/applying-approach-to-context&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (Applying Approach to Context)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;forecasting&quot;&gt;Forecasting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In business, we can’t predict the future - but that doesn’t stop everyone trying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;management-need-forecasts&quot;&gt;Management need forecasts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several important reasons why management need to forecast when options will be carried out and outcomes achieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shareholders want to know when they can expect a return on investment. The business will need to show an investor that the investment is worth pursuing over other opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Businesses need to know when money will start coming in:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To establish how long staff can be paid, among other fixed costs. Flows must be managed to avoid falling into financial trouble.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To know when funds will be available for other work, initiatives, products etc.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To make decisions on whether to ‘stick, twist, or fold’ on certain initiatives. If it becomes clear that the outcome isn’t worth the outlay, and the investment is better elsewhere then the sooner that decision is made the better.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst there is no getting away from the need, it’s critical to maintain an understanding that a forecast is a snapshot in time. What we’re working on may become irrelevant. It may need to change. Forecasting should be completely separate from target setting. It should be the act of providing information and probabilities to support decisions. If a forecast becomes a commitment it means that management have misunderstood the term, have integrated it with target setting, and have lost focus on the outcome in favour of the option being worked on. Use a forecast to decide, not to chastise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-do-we-forecast&quot;&gt;How do we forecast?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A forecast is what we expect to happen given what we know right now. Its most useful when it’s provided as a range and with a probability. A probabilistic forecast. Think of a weather forecast - knowing the probability of rain helps you prepare. This is as opposed to a deterministic forecast which simply points to an exact number. The more ‘known unknowns’ and ‘unknown unknowns’, the less accurate a forecast will be by definition - there’s too much left out of it. If you’re working in a Simple context, then clearly you can follow a plan, along a timeline, and have a good idea of when something will be delivered - and even the likely result - a deterministic forecast would be OK. Even this, though, could be scuppered if say, a global pandemic breaks out during the delivery. When the context becomes more Complicated, it can still follow a plan, however there will be more moving parts and therefore a greater chance of unexpected problems. In Complex contexts the future is highly uncertain and we’re being a lot more honest with ourselves if we start using ranges and probabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re working off a plan to deliver something you’ve delivered many times over, then you can provide an estimate of how long it will take based on the past experience. It took us 2 months to build X, so with the same conditions it’s take us 2 months to build another one. In other circumstances you’ll need to use data on past performance in delivery as a predictor of future delivery. This is your input. It’s crucial for management to be aware that past results can provide an indicator of future performance, but there are no guarantees that the future will play out in the same way. Unforeseen events in the business environment, the global economy and the climate can render a forecast completely irrelevant. Nassim Taleb has written extensively with regards to what he called &lt;i&gt;“Black Swan”&lt;/i&gt; events. If you were to use past performance of the economy as a predictor of the future performance, then in 2008 you would have been caught out. Delivery performance, at least in terms of past output can and should be used to forecast future output (because it’s all we’ve got). But always be open to the possibility that the future may bring something that renders previous data irrelevant. That’s why we need to build in contingency, buffers and spare capacity. This is about building resilience. Efficiency is good up to a point, however it makes you susceptible to shocks relating to events that fall outside of your expectations. Taleb deals with the effects of efficiency causing fragility his subsequent book, &lt;i&gt;Antifragile[1]&lt;/i&gt;. Optimising for efficiency removes the ability to absorb shocks. Contrast the human body’s capacity to adapt, heal and often benefit from shocks (eg fasting), with traffic systems that are designed to a certain threshold and buckle when capacity over and above is needed. If you operate the M25 motorway at capacity, it goes no-where. Both the smooth flow of work and resistance require spare capacity; the relationship to forecasting of delivery is that the more optimised an organisation is for efficiency, the more fragile our operations and forecasts are to unforeseen events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In delivery our forecasts usually look to say when an option will be complete (that is, an output created, or an action carried out). Below you can see some of the typical ways that forecasting is done in delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;time-based-forecasting---only-for-simple-contexts&quot;&gt;Time based forecasting - only for Simple contexts&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, work items are given time estimates by people that know exactly how long the job takes. They’ve done it, it’s a known quantity and it’s suitable for traditional waterfall project management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Forecast = Critical path&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach only works if the estimates are accurate. For this to be true:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the person has had to done the work, or very similar work before.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the integration of the work done by different individuals and teams is simple, it has been done before.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the individuals doing the work and the work itself are only affected by predictable external factors. They factor these into their estimates, along with some buffer - even in Simple contexts curveballs happen. They are still subject to external factors, like illness, climate, economy etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most work in large organisations will sit outside of these criteria. Even if work has been done before, the way it integrates with other work and with other teams will often be untested. That’s why most large projects or initiatives are destined to be late and over-budget. In fact, the bigger the project the more likely it is to be over budget due to the increasing complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following forms of forecasting are based on business cadence, that is, using proxies for quantities of past work to forecast when another quantity will be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;velocity2-based-forecasting&quot;&gt;Velocity[2] based forecasting&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve already discussed the fact that Management shouldn’t use Story Points as a measure of progress since they’re too far removed from verifiable value. The more complex the context, the more unlikely it is that teams will consistently get the sizing in the right ballpark, the less reliable the forecast. But when they do achieve a good level of consistency and get the measure of how much they can do within a time period (velocity) then they can use the information to forecast when future work might be completed.
Deterministic forecast = (Remaining number of story points/Average Velocity) 
This kind of forecast will provide a single number - whether of sprints or a delivery date. This can quite easily be misinterpreted by management as a commitment. There’s no indication about how probable it is that it’ll be achieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we’ve discussed, since we should have delivery data, a better way to forecast is to provide a range and a probability. What’s the point of showing the deterministic forecast? I’ve done this because in some situations it may be appropriate; you may need some ‘back of the napkin’ calculations done in a hurry. You may see others doing it. It’s useful to know the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create a probabilistic forecast, you perform what’s known as a Monte Carlo simulation. Plugging in the previous velocities, the simulation will run 10,000 tests based on the data we’ve input and provide a histogram of all its results. This gives us our possibilities and the relevant probabilities. As an example, now instead of giving one date, we can say that there’s an 80 percent change that the option will be finished by mid- July. Not only does this provide richer data, it also clearly implies that this is not a certainty. Whilst you may wish you could have an exact date, knowing the reality is much more helpful in decision making. Plenty of exact dates have been given, costly preparations made, and the dates missed. Acknowledge the uncertainty and plan for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach to forecasting hinges on the Story Points being a proxy for the lead time on work. In environments where the lead time is affected by handovers and significant wait time it will not produce a forecast worth using. How you fix this is by creating teams that can deliver end to end, which will provide greater consistency and predictability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;throughput-based-forecasting&quot;&gt;Throughput based forecasting&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This type of forecasting uses the number of items completed over a given time period (throughput). Many organisations use User Stories. I class them as a type of option. No matter what you call them, as long as there’s a relatively even distribution of sizes, throughput does provide a relatively good way to forecast future work. Again, we can forecast in this way both deterministically and probabilistically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Deterministic forecast = (Number of stories remaining / Throughput)&lt;/i&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the probabilistic forecast again you plug in the throughput data gathered over a time period and run the Monte Carlo simulation. The histogram will provide the range and probabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any type of forecast is based on past data or information. If inaccurate data is used, or the conditions change, then the forecast is likely to be much less accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I will leave you with a quote from organisational theorist Russel Ackoff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“A good deal of the corporate planning I have observed is like a ritual rain dance; it has no effect on the weather that follows, but those who engage in it think it does. Moreover, it seems to me that much of the advice and instruction related to corporate planning is directed at improving the dancing, not the weather.”[3]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use forecasts, set up a stable environment and system which will allow for some level of consistency. In doing so you will gain a much greater level of predictability. However create resilience in your organisation to ensure that any shocks are absorbed when they come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;forecasting-1&quot;&gt;FORECASTING&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Good&lt;/b&gt; - more of this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using past and current data and information to make a decision.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Separate from target setting. The forecast should indicate if you’re on track to meet the target, but not be the target.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applying the forecasting approach based on the context.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Probabilistic forecasting provides richer information and reflects reality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Bad&lt;/b&gt; - can be misused or produce negative results&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ignoring whether the domain is Simple, Complicated or Complex.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deterministic forecasting misleads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Ugly&lt;/b&gt; - bad practice in most organisational contexts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Holding teams and individuals to the forecast as if it were a commitment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Treating the forecast as a target.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;1] Taleb, Nassim Nicholas, and Nassim Nicholas Taleb. Antifragile: Things That Gain from Disorder. Incerto, Nassim Nicholas Taleb[…]. London: Penguin Books, 2013.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[2] Velocity is a term used for average number of story points “banked” by completing features over a regular time boxed cadence.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[3] Ackoff, Russell Lincoln. Creating the Corporate Future: Plan or Be Planned For. New York: Wiley, 1981. p. ix&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/respond&quot;&gt;next page (Organisational Ability: Respond) &amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Forecasting - predicting the future based on limited data..</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 5 - Communicate</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/communicate" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 5 - Communicate" /><published>2020-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/communicate</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/communicate">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/respond&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (Chapter 4: Respond)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;communicate&quot;&gt;Communicate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming in December 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Communicate.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 6 - Learn</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/learn" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 6 - Learn" /><published>2020-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/learn</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/learn">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/communicate&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (Chapter 5: Communicate)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;learn&quot;&gt;Learn&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming in February 2021.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Learn.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 3 - Orient</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/orient" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 3 - Orient" /><published>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/orient</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/orient">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/good-bad-ugly&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (The Good, the Bad and the Ugly)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;orient-the-ability-to-measure-where-you-are-in-relation-to-where-you-want-to-be&quot;&gt;Orient: the ability to measure where you are in relation to where you want to be&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What gets measured gets managed - even when it’s pointless to measure and manage it, and even if it harms the purpose of the organisation to do so.”
 	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;-Edward Deming&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What should leadership be looking at to gauge progress?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve already seen that any measurement needs to provide us with information that helps decide what to do next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-job-of-senior-management&quot;&gt;The job of Senior Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only measure something if you are prepared to act on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leadership’s job is to help teams to do their best work, to create an environment where they can excel, provide clarity of purpose and remove blockers in order for them to achieve business outcomes. Clearly to provide this support you have to know how things are progressing. This measure provides a signal as to where your help, or a decision might be needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many contexts (but not all), teams should be as autonomous as possible. Being closest to the work, and most knowledgeable about it, they’re often best placed to make decisions. The availability of information makes the decisions better, and faster too since they don’t need to pass information up the chain and wait for it to come down. I’m not saying that leadership should be over eager, on edge and jumping in at the first sign of an issue - or distrust that teams will come to them. I’m saying that there needs to be a decent feedback loop in place for management to gain awareness, give (and receive) feedback, and proactively provide support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The information should lead to &lt;b&gt;5 questions related to progress:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If teams are struggling to show progress, are there obstacles we can remove?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is there something we can provide, or do, to help them move forward?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do they need our support to move in another direction, having identified that the work isn’t providing the expected outcome?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are we recognising great work and celebrating success?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is this sustainable? Progress at the expense of health due to overwork or stress can’t be maintained and is unethical. If it isn’t sustainable and it’s hurting people, intervention is needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/understanding-context&quot;&gt;next page (Developing Orient) &amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Chapter 3 looks at how we develop and measure the abitlity to Orient.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 2 - What to measure</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/good-bad-ugly" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 2 - What to measure" /><published>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/good-bad-ugly</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/good-bad-ugly">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/use-cases-for-metrics&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (Use Cases for Metrics)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly&quot;&gt;The Good, the Bad and the Ugly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we look at developing our Organisational Abilities, we’ll encounter The Good, The Bad and The Ugly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve already seen that &lt;b&gt;Good metrics&lt;/b&gt; are an indicator related to the goal we’re trying to achieve. They provide us with information that helps us decide what to do next to achieve that goal. Working integrated software, customer satisfaction and conversion rates are examples of good metrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bad metrics&lt;/b&gt; mislead us. The information they provide does not have a meaningful bearing on our goal. When we use them to made decisions, we may as well have flipped a coin. At worst they influence decisions by sending us in the wrong direction. Bad metrics are usually measured with the best of intentions. They’re just not thought through. In software, velocity is useful for a team but it’s a bad metric for managers to use because it can be gamed at the expense of actual results. In sales, looking at sales numbers is important, but if returns and customer satisfaction aren’t taken into account then sales numbers can go up at the expense of future goodwill and profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ugly metrics&lt;/b&gt; are seriously dysfunctional, sometimes tyrannical. They’re less about the goal, and more about control or dominance. Avoid these like the plague, and if you meet or work for someone using them - question whether it’s the right place for you. I recently saw a video-calling feature being advertised to managers by an analytics company. They allow the managers to track the number and duration of video-call meetings taking place. You can imagine how this could easily be misused. Employees may set up meetings they don’t even need to meet their quota. What a powerful way for managers to make a company look busy whilst killing productivity!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In future pages we’ll revisit the Good, Bad and Ugly pattern in relation to metrics associated with abilities discussed in this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/orient&quot;&gt;next page (introducing our first Organisational Ability: Orient) &amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Chapter 2 looks at what to measure in your organisation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 3 - Orient</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/forecasting" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 3 - Orient" /><published>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/forecasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/forecasting">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/applying-approach-to-context&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (Applying Approach to Context)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;forecasting&quot;&gt;Forecasting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Section coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Forecasting in delivery.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 3 - Orient</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/applying-approach-to-context" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 3 - Orient" /><published>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/applying-approach-to-context</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/applying-approach-to-context">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/understanding-context&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (Understanding Context)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;applying-approach-to-context&quot;&gt;Applying Approach to Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s now look at how to approach measurement of progress in the different contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;measuring-progress-when-work-is-simple-or-complicated&quot;&gt;Measuring progress when work is Simple or Complicated&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I contracted a builder to convert our loft into a bedroom. He’s done this before in very similar houses. The high level &lt;b&gt;outcome&lt;/b&gt; I wanted was space and value (since house prices go up with an additional bedroom). I could have achieved the same outcome by building a basement, an extension, a conservatory or a cabin in the garden. I had &lt;b&gt;options&lt;/b&gt;. The option I opted for was a loft conversion. The builder performed &lt;i&gt;actions&lt;/i&gt; to create the &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt;, which realised the option; the converted loft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed to keep track of both the state of the option (completion of the conversion) and the outcome (whether this would give me space and value). If the loft doesn’t get converted then I have no outcome, so if I don’t follow progress how do I know that any work is happening? You may think you would just wait for them to finish the job. But would you wait indefinitely, or pay any price? I had to measure progress to some extent (I hadn’t used the builder before, and I’m not what the cowboys would call a ‘sucker’). In this case, I could measure progress by the builder checking in with me to tell me what he expected to have done at a given moment, and where he was actually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tracking the output is pretty easy in this linear and predictable example. But then it usually in Simple contexts and even at the lighter end of Complicated. Progress on the option I chose was important, but still subservient to the outcome I was looking for. If at any time it seems the option you’ve chosen won’t deliver the outcome, then you need to change tact. In this case I knew the space and value I wanted out of this would be achieved if we got the loft. But imagine if the reason I wanted the space was to take up the drums? My wife and neighbours wouldn’t put up with that upstairs. If I discovered this early on, I might be able to choose a different option. Maybe to soundproof the room, or build a cabin down the garden. The outcome is what guides the option you choose. It doesn’t matter how fast you’re driving, you’ll still be late if you’re going in the wrong direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;An option is a combination of actions or outputs that together contribute to the outcome.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my example, the builder could estimate cost accurately, because he knew all the steps to carry out the work, how long they’d take and the materials needed. This type of project is linear and predictable. He could tell for himself, and show me how things were progressing by looking at the schedule. I could also see progress by looking at the physical space, but I trusted his plan on a page because he knew what should have been done at any point in time for the project to be on track. This won’t be adequate for most of you reading this book. If you’re working in an organisation creating new products, developing and integrating software, or in any domain where work is complex and innovation and experimentation is needed, following the linear approach of planning all the work up front and tracking the plan is a bad way to measure progress. Why? Because the plan fools you into thinking you know what’s going on and what the end result will be when in fact it’s impossible to predict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;measuring-progress-in-complex-domains&quot;&gt;Measuring progress in Complex domains&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever your desired outcome. More market share. Lower customer churn. Etc. To achieve it actions will need to be taken and usually some kind of output produced. Often, in business and software development, at first it is not evident what will deliver the outcome or how technology will be used to achieve it. That’s what makes the context complex, requiring a test and learn approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take the example of a telco looking to increase market share as it’s &lt;b&gt;outcome&lt;/b&gt;. The teams have a list of ranked options that they believe will achieve this. Top of the list are several features which will bring more customers to the site. This is more than a hunch, they’ve been looking at the data they’ve got and used it to create a hypothesis for each &lt;b&gt;option&lt;/b&gt;. The work is complex, they don’t know for sure how the options will perform until they test them with real users. Expecting a fully estimated plan from them, is asking for the unknowable. Worse, held to a plan they will be pressured into delivering options (probably in the form of outputs - functionality) that don’t deliver the outcome. They’ll have done what you wanted, but it’ll have wasted everyone’s time. My builder could provide a plan, because his work involved largely things he’d done before or at worse known unknowns. The teams creating something new face &lt;i&gt;unknown unknowns&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this example, the relationship between the options (in this case functionality) and its effect on the outcome needs to be measured often because it’s not a clear cause and effect relationship. They need test often to make sure they’re on the right path and tweak accordingly. Hypothesis may be created, but they need to be tested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;In a complex context the only true measure of progress is the effect of the option on the outcome.&lt;/b&gt; In the software example, this would be measuring the effect of a new feature (the option) on market share. In development of a new antiviral drug, it would be the effect of the drug on the virus. This is how we can really tell we’re doing well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other measures are at best weak proxies, and at worst fool us into thinking progress has been made when in fact we’re standing still. You measure what matters, so if the outcome is what’s important then that’s what counts. If you are only measuring the implementation of your options (as many in business do), then you are merely focussed on output. This often happens from the top down; a senior manager will focus on an output (mistakingly equating this with the outcome), they hold their people accountable for the output and measure them against it,  and before you know it the only thing that matters is delivering the output. That’s perfect if there is a 1:1 relationship between the output and achieving your outcome, a predefined route; however with an untried route you’re simply looking at progress in mileage without checking that you’re closer to your destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Management should be focussed on the destination, but there is every reason to check the mileage if it allows for better support of the teams. Shortly we’ll see how that works. But first lets look at how breaking options down benefits delivery in a Complex context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;breaking-options-down&quot;&gt;Breaking options down&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say that you have a series of options that independently affect the outcome. Their independence is important. If an option only affects the outcome when combined with another then it’s possible to deliver a whole lot without having any realisable value. This creates waste and contributes to many failed programmes[1].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The teams break the option down in a way that suits their work. You could break an option down ad infinitum into smaller options. The constraint is that it must affect the outcome. Breaking work down into smaller batches leads to faster feedback, so smaller options can be turned around, explored, tweaked, ditched faster as teams test and learn towards their destination. These are better in Complex contexts but Complicated contexts also benefit from smaller batch sizes since an option produces benefit in the form of an affected outcome or learning. The earlier we get this, the better as we’ll start realising the benefit sooner and also reduce some of the risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;checking-the-mileage---measuring-progress-on-your-options&quot;&gt;Checking the mileage - measuring progress on your options&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of completed options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My loft converted into a bedroom.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A feature on a website.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new drug ready for trials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does completed mean? The Agile manifesto articulates the value of “working software over comprehensive documentation” because clearly you are closer to delivering value with working software than a document. The best measure of milage is the completed option; working software, a drug that can be tested, the bedroom in my loft. In the Simple and Complicated contexts where the road is known, mileage is actually a pretty good measure. Not so much for the Complex, but still the next best - and many organisations would fare much better if they stuck to this as a measure of progress rather than putting confidence in the current position in relation to a plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do we measure when the option is “complete”? Isn’t it subjective? It’s obvious that my bedroom wouldn’t be accepted as complete if the builder hadn’t connected the wiring so that electricity was available in the room. In the same way working software isn’t complete until it integrates with other components that enable it to create value. A drug being developed isn’t complete until it can be trialed. Think of it this way, for an option to be complete it needs to be at the point where it can be used or executed. This is because anything else requires further work, possibly a lot more - in the complex domain we can’t be sure. Be conscious of what a completed option should look like - the more complex the context the more concerned you should be with anything less than an executable state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Agile, teams talk about a Definition of Done to avoid doubt. It simply makes explicit everything that we think should happen, but that may be assumed by some and missed by others. This may include automated tests being in place, and documentation being updated. Things that could be unique to a team, or ambiguous can be in a definition of done. A working, integrated solution should be view as important as connecting the bedroom up to the electricity. In the latter case, it is so obvious that I don’t need to make it explicit to the builder - in the former case, it would be an advanced organisation that recognises this as obvious - they will do well from it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A completed option is executable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you see why management shouldn’t be interested in number of story points[2], number of stories completed or hours worked? They are too far removed from delivery of verifiable value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What should management be looking at?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine the following options as measures of progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;a.&lt;/b&gt; Each iteration I get a car that I can drive around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;b.&lt;/b&gt; Each iteration I get a list of completed work that’s been done to a car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;c.&lt;/b&gt; Each iteration see how many hours or work units they have managed to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your life depended on getting out a working product that affects the outcome, which would you use as a measure of progress?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Simple and Complicated contexts (&lt;b&gt;b.&lt;/b&gt;) will suffice if the right people are working on it, whilst (&lt;b&gt;a.&lt;/b&gt;) is clearly the better option. (&lt;b&gt;c.&lt;/b&gt;) is rarely useful even in these contexts - if you focus on this you will surely have everyone busy. But producing value?Management should be leaving (&lt;b&gt;b.&lt;/b&gt;) and (&lt;b&gt;c.&lt;/b&gt;) to the teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we should aim for is the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Team decides to go with X options which fit into a given time box. Could be 1, could be 10.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;At the end of the time box, a number of these options have been implemented. Some may not have been finished.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The team and relevant stakeholders, including management review the implemented options and their effect on the outcome. This is the progress. Management asks the 5 questions of themselves. If it’s too soon to measure the option’s effect on the outcome, this will need to be measured as soon as the data is available.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Feedback, learning and continue, pivot or ditch decisions are made.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The process loops back around.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Management should be reviewing progress by objectively looking at the implemented option on a given cadence. What you see above may look somewhat like a Sprint Review used in Scrum - but we can be framework agnostic. This isn’t rocket science - everyone reviews progress - the difference is in using the right measures. That means looking at things of verifiable value (the option) rather than tenuous links to the things we care about. Management shouldn’t be looking at anything other than options and outcomes. No proxies, no tenuous links, no self deception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Management tracking the work at a task level can show lack of trust. You’re better off finding great people that you don’t feel the need to task track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For simple and some complicated work, with regularity appropriate to the situation, it will give a fairly accurate view of where you are in relation to the destination. You can know how much there is to do in relation to what’s been done and take action accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For complex work this is futile. More than any other domain, you need people who can make decisions on their own and escalate only when something is outside their sphere of influence. If they’re not on track to deliver an option in a given time period, allow them to work out what to do without breathing down their necks. Constraints and difficulties can result in creative solutions. Aside from distracting the teams, looking at the tasks required to deliver the option, as we have seen, will be misleading as in the context they may change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Most organisations are operating in Complex contexts. In this situation the effect of the option on the outcome is like your SatNav telling you how much closer you are to your destination. It is the only true measure of progress.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you cannot measure the outcome at a given point, a completed option indicates you are making progress - it will either affect the outcome, or you will learn something&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lead-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/summary_of_domains.png&quot; alt=&quot;Summary of domains&quot; style=&quot;max-width:100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image-credit&quot;&gt;Summary of domains: table based on the Cynefin framework [3]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary-of-measuring-progress&quot;&gt;SUMMARY OF MEASURING PROGRESS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Good&lt;/b&gt; (more of this)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Measuring progress on getting to your destination: the effect of the option (the actions or outputs) on the outcome&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Management by walking around.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One-to-one meetings with reports.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;These measures should be used to prompt the 5 questions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Secondary measure - mileage: the completion of an option so that it is ready to execute.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;an objective view of a working, integrated system or product&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Bad&lt;/b&gt; (can be misused or produce negative results)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applying linear tracking to Complex contexts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Story points - for management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Ugly&lt;/b&gt; (bad practice in most organisational contexts)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using a plan in Complex context.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Management tracking and comparing story points between teams.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Optimising for busyness:  maximising % utilisation of individuals and tracking time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[1] As an example: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/society/2013/sep/18/nhs-records-system-10bn&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;‘Abandoned NHS IT System Has Cost £10bn so Far’. The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;, 18 September 2013.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[2] Story pointing is an Agile technique whereby User Stories are given a point value. This represents the amount of work, it’s complexity and any risk and uncertainty around them. The stories are pointed relative to one another. It’s a heuristic, not a science, and for a dedicated, stable team this can make the process of deciding what to work on, and how much work to pull in faster. It’s a better, more systemic representation of the work as opposed to time based estimation. The latter takes longer, is generally less accurate (as less holistic) and encourages managers to hold people to their estimates.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[3] Snowden, D. J., and M.E. Boone. ‘A Leader’s Framework for Decision Making’. Harvard Business Review 85, no. 11 (2007): 68–76.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/forecasting&quot;&gt;next page (Forecasting) &amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Applying approach to context in delivery.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 2 - What to measure</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/use-cases-for-metrics" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 2 - What to measure" /><published>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/use-cases-for-metrics</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/use-cases-for-metrics">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/what-to-measure&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (What Should we Measure?)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-cases-for-metrics&quot;&gt;Use cases for metrics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a summary of what we should measure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Common needs of managers in organisations:&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;We will look at how to:&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Ability to:&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;I want to know if we’re on track, so that I can take measures to alter our course. Correct, pivot or ditch.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Measure progress and forecast.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Orient - Chapter 3&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;I want to know and improve our ability to respond to change so that we can more quickly and effectively adapt to changing markets.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Measure and improve our agility.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Respond - Chapter 4&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;I want to increase our openness and transparency internally so that problems are exposed early and we can leverage the creativity and potential of our people.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Measure and improve openness.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Communicate - Chapter 5&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;I want to know we are evolving; improving what we are doing.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Measure and improve the culture of learning and continuous improvement.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Learn - Chapter 6&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We’ll be exploring each of these individually in detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/good-bad-ugly&quot;&gt;next page (The Good, the Bad and the Ugly) &amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Chapter 2 looks at what to measure in your organisation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 2 - What to measure</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/what-to-measure" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 2 - What to measure" /><published>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/what-to-measure</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/what-to-measure">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/options-and-outcomes&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (CHAPTER 1 - Options and Outcomes)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-should-we-measure&quot;&gt;What should we measure?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Measurement is fabulous. Unless you’re busy measuring what’s easy to measure as opposed to what’s important.”[1]&lt;br /&gt;
 	&lt;i&gt;- Seth Godin (Author and entrepreneur)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the previous chapter we saw the difference between leading and lagging indicators, and what can happen if you measure something that’s only loosely aligned to your overall goals. You’d be surprised at how many leaders use other people’s metrics to assess how things are going, even when they provide little information on whether business results are being achieved or values acted upon. I’ve witnessed managers obsessing over teams’ velocity&lt;i&gt;[2]&lt;/i&gt; whilst remaining ignorant of whether it bore any relation to the business outcomes (it didn’t). But, it’s easy to measure and other teams use it, so they latched onto it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, similar organisations may be looking to achieve the same thing, and in those cases metrics may be alike. But that’s the wrong place to start. A measurement should provide information that helps you decide what to do next. It needs to take you in the direction of your goals and values. The weaker the relationship between what you’re measuring and what you actually want to achieve, the less useful that information is. Using it to decide on what to do next could mean setting off on the wrong path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is for organisations taking on progressive values, including but not limited to those shared by the Agile movement. If you’re moving in that direction, then you’ll need build the following organisation abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ability to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;ORIENT&lt;/b&gt;. Have a clear view of progress towards outcomes, so that measures can be taken to support teams to correct or change course.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;RESPOND&lt;/b&gt;. React and adapt to changing requirements, so that a firm can better compete in a complex and changing environment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;COMMUNICATE&lt;/b&gt;. Creating an environment where individuals value one another and can be open, so that problems are exposed early and the creativity and potential of people can be leveraged.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;LEARN&lt;/b&gt;. To cultivate a culture of reflection and continuous improvement throughout the organisation. Across people, process and product.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building and improving these abilities isn’t easy but it will set you up for the best possible chance of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[1] Godin, Seth. ‘Measuring without Measuring’. &lt;a href=&quot;https://seths.blog/2013/06/measuring-without-measuring/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Seth’s Blog (blog), 1 June 2013&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[2] Velocity is a metric used by some Scrum teams: the number of ‘story points’ completed within a sprint. More on this later.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/use-cases-for-metrics&quot;&gt;next page (Use Cases for Metrics) &amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Chapter 2 looks at what to measure in your organisation.</summary></entry></feed>