<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-15T10:31:47+01:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">What makes a great Agile Coach?</title><link href="/what-makes-a-great-agile-coach" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What makes a great Agile Coach?" /><published>2020-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/what%20makes%20a%20great%20agile%20coach</id><content type="html" xml:base="/what-makes-a-great-agile-coach">&lt;p&gt;Agile Coach is a term widely used. It’s been defined by the Agile Coaching Institute, but also frequently interpreted and modified by organisations and practitioners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you call any difference a “context specific improvement” or “corruption” depends on whether it fits or contradicts Agile, progressive principles. Certainly some Agile Coach interpretations do, but otherwise looking at the context and not sticking with a rigid dictate of what something is and how it should be done is the very essence of agility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, I present my view on what the role is and what great looks like. It’s shaped by my experience and what I’ve learned over the years; I’ve seen what works and what doesn’t work. I’ve been a Scrum Master 5 years, interviewed, hired and managed a team of Scrum Masters, hired and led a team of Agile Coaches in a transformation; working as an Agile Coach at team and leadership levels in a major telco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Done right the role is a powerful catalyst for change and improvement. Done badly it can be ineffective and even detrimental - like a doctor prescribing the wrong medicine to a patient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-does-an-agile-coach-do&quot;&gt;What does an Agile Coach do?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a high level description of the role; it supports an organisation, its teams and people in their adoption of Agile values (or similar modern values related to people, flow, improvement and customer focus). It encourages experimentation with new ways of working, empiricism and adoption of new behaviours promoting flow, continuous improvement, quality communication and improved customer outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The word “Coach” is misleading, since it’s only a facet of the role. The Agile Coaching Institute uses “Practitioner”, but it seems that “Coach” has stuck. As the below image shows, taken from their website, other expected skills are teaching, mentoring, technical mastery, business mastery, transformation mastery and facilitation. Individuals will bring their own skills and be stronger in some areas than others. That’s what makes diversity great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Agile-Coach-Competency-Framework-for-website.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Agile Coach competency framework&quot; style=&quot;max-width:100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the word “Agile” is limiting. The ACI has included “Lean”, however personally I’ve sought individuals with a wider skillset, which I also strive to develop myself. Communication skills expertise, Liberating Structures, Systems thinking and a number of other tools and techniques can be useful. Look at what the organisation wants to achieve, then establish the skills you need. Like the old adage; if you only bring a hammer, every problem looks like a nail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another diagram that’s useful is the one below. It’s a modification of a much older diagram on “the consulting role”. This modification works for our case (credit to Dandy People who created it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every business and context is different, every team is at a different stage in their journey. A great Agile Coach selects the appropriate stance for the context and will modify this over time. Usually in a way that gives individuals the capability and confidence to no longer need the support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/choosing-coaching-stance-graph.png&quot; alt=&quot;choosing a coaching stance&quot; style=&quot;max-width:100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An Agile Coach works at one, or all of three levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team level:&lt;/strong&gt; supporting a number of teams of “doers” carrying out work on a product. This would involve observation and coaching of the team or individuals. The “why” behind suggestions and techniques to try to solve a particular problem. Training of the team in roles, techniques and events. “Showing by example” - hands on mentoring or training of individuals by facilitating events or working through activities (eg helping a new Product Owner on managing a backlog). If a team isn’t doing Scrum but has a dedicated individual to support them with ways of working expertise and Agile, then they’re generally called an Agile Coach to be non Scrum specific.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team of teams level:&lt;/strong&gt; supporting a team of teams of a particular value stream, product or programme. The principle difference between this and team level is a focus on handoff points and dependencies between teams. Using Agile approaches to minimise or improve these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enterprise level:&lt;/strong&gt; sometimes called “Enterprise Coaches”. These individuals will work with senior managers and business leaders. Helping them understand the “why” behind certain Agile concepts, and how they can be implemented. Think organisational design, creating an environment supportive of the Agile principles, policies etc. I should add that I find creating a hierarchy of Agile Coaches unhelpful. A great Agile Coach should work at all levels from time to time in order to keep their skills sharp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-difference-between-an-agile-coach-and-a-scrum-master&quot;&gt;The difference between an Agile Coach and a Scrum Master&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s be clear. An Agile Coach is not necessarily more advanced or a step up from a Scrum Master. Many assume it is because they generally work at a higher level and earn more. I’ve known Scrum Masters that are more knowledgeable and capable than someone calling themself an Agile Coach, and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re hiring an Agile Coach, you should expect a broader experience with various ways of working techniques. One may be Scrum but they should be framework agnostic. That’s not to say there aren’t a lot of great Scrum Masters out there that apply much more than Scrum and XP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-is-the-agile-coach-role-important&quot;&gt;Why is the Agile Coach role important?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ve got a problem to solve. The old ways of doing things aren’t working, or are leaving you behind the competition. You’re bringing on Agile Coaches to help the organisation towards Agile values and ways of working. If this is successful you will see happier people, working in an environment where they can raise issues and see the value they’re producing; improved business outcomes, from increased customer focus and connection; a more effective organisation through improved feedback, shorter lead times (a true measure of agility) and accelerated innovation with a culture of continuous improvement. That’s why the role is important - but only if it can fix your problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-whats-the-future-of-the-role&quot;&gt;So what’s the future of the role?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My prediction:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agile Coaches will still be called such when helping businesses to roll out specific Agile frameworks, or working with teams using Agile, eg XP and Scrum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increasingly we’ll see a role that isn’t specifically related to Agile, or confused by the word “coach”. Something along the lines of “Ways of working specialist” or “agility practitioner: (as mentioned the ACI already uses Agile Practitioner). This is probably closer to what I’ve intended for the role when I’ve hired Agile Coaches, something broader. Once new terms are familiar, they’ll be easier to hire for.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="agile" /><summary type="html">and what the hell do they do anyway?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">So Good They Can’t Ignore You - by Cal Newport</title><link href="/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you-by-Cal-Newport" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="So Good They Can’t Ignore You - by Cal Newport" /><published>2020-08-07T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-08-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/so%20good%20they%20cant%20ignore%20you%20by%20Cal%20Newport</id><content type="html" xml:base="/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you-by-Cal-Newport">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendation: 8/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;so good they can't ignore you book cover&quot; style=&quot;height: 200px; float: right; padding: 0px 0px 0px 15px;&quot; /&gt;An alternative to the famous “follow your passion” advice. It’s well argued and I can relate personally. I’ve found work I’m passionate about, but as a student I’d not even heard of my industry. Following your passion sounds great, but that assumes you know your passion, and that following it will provide you with a successful and meaningful career (there are examples in the book to illustrate how it can lead you astray). For me the work, skills and purpose came over time. There are definitely exceptions (sports being one), but for many it’s great advice; get out there and start working to discover your passion and earn options to pursue it. One of the best career advice books I’ve read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-big-idea-what-so-what-now-what&quot;&gt;The big idea. What, so what, now what?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To get work you love, following your passion is bad advice. First, you need to &lt;strong&gt;develop rare skills and experience&lt;/strong&gt;. This gives you &lt;strong&gt;control&lt;/strong&gt;. It makes you valuable. With control you can get more &lt;strong&gt;autonomy&lt;/strong&gt;. You can negotiate. You have options. This allows you to pursue a mission. Providing you with &lt;strong&gt;purpose&lt;/strong&gt;. Working at the cutting edge of a field is where you usually find it - to get there you must build skills, experience and value. A compelling mission should be &lt;strong&gt;remarkable&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This means rather than dreaming up a passion and pursuing it (except in some situations, like sports), you should focus on developing valuable skills and following the route I’ve described. These can be in an areas you’re interested in. But as the examples show, you may be surprised and find out it’s not so great. Developing skills and experience will take you on a journey that will lead you to your passion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pick a field that appeals. Work hard, develop rare skills. Pursue the options that interest you as they begin to emerge. You’ll start to arrive at the cutting edge, where the interesting work is. This will take you to your purpose and true fulfilment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;hr /&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-follow-your-passion&quot;&gt;Don’t follow your passion&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Steve jobs didn’t follow his passion. He got a lucky break from a small time scheme that eventually paid off. His passion was Buddhism, natural retreats and spiritualism. Electronics was a way to make money.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Career passions are rare&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;top 5 identified passions for students were dance, hockey, skiing, reading and swimming. These don’t have much to offer when it comes to choosing a job.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passion takes time&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;in studies of collage administrative assistants, the more experience an assistant had, the more likely she was to love her work.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;if you’ve had many year’s experience then you’ve had time to get better at what you do and develop a feeling of efficacy. It gives you more time to build relationships and see your work benefit others.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passion is a side effect of mastery&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Self determination theory (SDT). Three basic needs to feel intrinsically motivated at work.
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Autonomy; the feeling that you have control over your day, and that your actions are important&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Competence; the feeling that you are good at what you do. (mastery in Daniel Pink’s book Drive)&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Relatedness; the feeling of connection to other people.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The assistants build the three of these areas over time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working right trumps finding the right work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Following your passion is chasing an elusive dream.&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Following your passion doesn’t make you happy. Keeping options open, taking opportunities, doing great work - you build passion in what you do.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Replace the passion mindset (what value your jobs gives you) with &lt;strong&gt;the craftsman mindset&lt;/strong&gt; (what value you’re producing in your job)
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“Be so good they can’t ignore you” - Steve Martin’s philosophy for success. Develop so much experience that you can’t help but succeed. You get confidence in pushing the envelope.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;the-importance-of-skill&quot;&gt;The importance of &lt;strong&gt;skill&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;** The traits that make a great job are rare and valuable. Therefore, if you want a great job you have to build up rare and valuable skills.**
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Cal calls these skills your “career capital”.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Examples include Steve Martin, Steve Jobs, Ira Glass (radio), Merrick (surfboard). All worked hard building skills and ended up in dream jobs because of that.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;This means a craftsman’s mindset. But there are 3 disqualifiers:
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;The job presents few opportunities to distinguish yourself by developing relevant skills that are rare and valuable.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;The job focuses on something you think is useless or bad for the work (ie tax consultant).&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;The job forces you to work with people you really dislike.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Examples of people building career capital;
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;a debater becomes assistant, becomes staff writer, becomes producer. Honing craft, writing in the evening, seeking frequent feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;a biologist works on an energy project for his professor, becomes energy entrepreneur, meets vc and gets clean energy role from introduction, ending up as the clean energy vc.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deliberate practice is needed&lt;/strong&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;10,000 hour rule. If you just show up and work hard, you’ll plateu.
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Deliberate practice is “activity designed, typically by a teacher, for the sole purpose of effectively improving specific aspects of an individual’s performance”.&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5 habits to a craftsman&lt;/strong&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Identify the market you’re in (2 types)
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Winner takes all markets (blogging, script writing) are all about one specific skill you have to optimise relentlessly.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Auction markets are less structured. A collection of various skills can help you succeed. (venture capitalist). There is more flexibility. If doors open, you can take the opportunity and build capital.&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Identify your capital type
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;As above. For auction you can go for open doors. For Winner, you know what it must be.&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Define good
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;You need clear goals&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Stretch and destroy
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Get uncomfortable.
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                      &lt;li&gt;“Deliberate practice is often the opposite of enjoyable.” It takes focus and concentration. If you’re not uncomfortable then you’re probably stuck at an acceptable level.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Embrace honest feedback.
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                      &lt;li&gt;Even if it destroys what you thought was good.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Be patient.
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                      &lt;li&gt;Steve Martin thought, when taking up the banjo, that if he stuck to it then one day he’ll have been playing for 40 years. And someone whose been playing for 40 years will be pretty good at it.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;control-is-important-or-turn-down-the-promotion&quot;&gt;Control is important (or turn down the promotion)&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Control over what you do and how you do it is one of the most powerful traits you can acquire when creating the work you love.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You gain control by investing your career capital. It’s a great investment.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Example of a guy that built a lot of capital in farming. He invested it in setting up a farm.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;ROWE (results only work environment) - reportedly highly rewarding.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Giving people more control over what they do and how they do it increases their happiness, engagement and sense of fulfilment.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control that’s acquired without career capital isn’t sustainable.&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;In other words, if you don’t have the skills and experience that makes you valuable, and can be exchanged for control, you don’t have any real leverage for the control.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you have the career capital to get control over your working life, you’ll be so valuable that your current employer will seek to prevent you making the change.&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Example of a software developer, Lulu. She build strong skills, used it to take time off etc. Had to deal with aggressive counter offers and show courage choosing other options (eg freelance.)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The key is knowing when it’s right to be courageous in your career decisions. Calculated, rather than the “follow your passion” kind.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid the traps with the law of financial viability&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do what people are willing to pay for&lt;/strong&gt; - Derek Sivers&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;When deciding to pursue something that will give more control over your work life, seek evidence that people are willing to pay for it. If you find this evidence, continue. If not, move on.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;the-importance-of-mission&quot;&gt;The importance of mission&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To have a mission is to have a unifying focus for your career.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A mission chosen before you have relevant career capital is not likely to be sustainable. Missions emerge.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Good career missions are found in the Adjacent possible - you have to get to the cutting edge in order to find your mission, this take time and requires you to develop skill first.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&quot;”Term from science writer Steven Johnson, who took it from Stuart Kauffman, that helps explain the origin of innovation. Johnson notes that the next big ideas in any field are typically found right beyond the cutting edge, in the adjacent space that contains the possible new combinations of existing ideas. The key observation is that you have to get to the cutting edge of a field before it’s adjacent possible - and the innovations it contains -becomes visible.” -from So good they can’t ignore you p236 #innovation #creativity”&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Advancing to the cutting edge in a field means you have to focus on a narrow collection of subjects for a potentially long time.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Example of a biologist with a great mission, using computational genetics to understand and fight ancient diseases. First focussed for years on a narrow niche - the genetics of diseases in Africa.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Great missions are transformed into great successes through small, achievable projects - little bets - to explore the concrete possibilities surrounding an idea.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;References a book - &lt;strong&gt;Little Bets&lt;/strong&gt; by Peter Sims&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Missions require marketing&lt;/strong&gt;; they must be remarkable
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Law of remarkability: A mission driven project should compel people who encounter it to remark about it to others. Second, it must be launched in a venue that supports such remarking.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;References Seth Godin’s book Purple Cow. “The world is full of boring stuff - brown cows - which is why so few people pay attention…A purple cow… now that would stand out. Remarkable marketing is the art of building things worth noticing.”&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;cals-routines&quot;&gt;Cal’s routines&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Research bible
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Once a week he summarises in his “bible” a paper he thinks might be relevant to his research. Description of the result, how it compares to previous work, main strategies to obtain it.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Introduces the strain of deliberate practice.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hour tally routine
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Tallies the total number of hours he’s spent each month in deliberate practice.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Theory notebook routine
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Fancy notebook, to remind him it’s important. Brainstorming of new theory results. Formally recorded on a dated page. More deliberate practice.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working right trumps finding the right work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="book" /><category term="careers" /><category term="work" /><summary type="html">Recommendation: 8/10 An alternative to the famous “follow your passion” advice. It’s well argued and I can relate personally. I’ve found work I’m passionate about, but as a student I’d not even heard of my industry. Following your passion sounds great, but that assumes you know your passion, and that following it will provide you with a successful and meaningful career (there are examples in the book to illustrate how it can lead you astray). For me the work, skills and purpose came over time. There are definitely exceptions (sports being one), but for many it’s great advice; get out there and start working to discover your passion and earn options to pursue it. One of the best career advice books I’ve read.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Extreme Ownership - by Jocko Willink and Leif Babin</title><link href="/extreme-ownership-by-jocko-willink" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Extreme Ownership - by Jocko Willink and Leif Babin" /><published>2020-07-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-07-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/extreme%20ownership%20by%20jocko%20willink</id><content type="html" xml:base="/extreme-ownership-by-jocko-willink">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendation: 9/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/extreme-ownership.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Extreme Ownership&quot; style=&quot;height: 200px; float: right; padding: 0px 0px 0px 15px;&quot; /&gt;I really like the concept of Extreme Ownership; a leader owns everything in their world, “there is no-one else to blame”. It’s written by two ex U.S. Navy SEAL officers who served in Iraq. Each leadership principle is given along with examples from their time in combat, as well as what they’ve seen whilst consulting in industry. All the principles in the book are important, however some of the chapters are better than others; in terms of the combat story, principle and business story pattern each follows. In particular “no bad teams, only bad leaders” was standout for me. It’s definitely something I’ll use and recommend to others. To borrow a line from the book, what’s in there is simple, but it isn’t easy. A must read for leaders of any rank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-big-idea-what-so-what-now-what&quot;&gt;The big idea. What, so what, now what?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extreme ownership is owning everything in your world. This means there are no bad teams, only bad leaders. To be a great leader, you must understand the mission and communicate it effectively; empower your people to make decisions and at the same time ensure they’re clear on boundaries and direction (it’s your responsibility); be confident to inspire confidence, but not cocky; be decisive, using your experience and the information at hand in uncertainty; make sure priority is clear, and that there’s a clear plan to execute along with contingencies.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is no-one else to blame. You need to own everything, lead from the front and figure out a way to win.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set the example, own it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-notes&quot;&gt;My notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leadership and teamwork concepts…are &lt;strong&gt;simple but not easy&lt;/strong&gt;. They require dedication and discipline over time to master and become effective leaders.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Simple, not easy” - a phrase often used to describe jiu-jitsu, can also describe Scrum and Kettlebell Simple &amp;amp; Sinister #quote #simplicity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;extreme-ownership-leaders-must-own-everything-in-their-world-there-is-no-one-else-to-blame&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extreme Ownership: Leaders must own everything in their world. There is no-one else to blame&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;set asside ego&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;attack weaknesses&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;consistently work to build a better and more effective team&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;not take credit for his team’s successes but bestows the honour upon his subordinate leaders and team members&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;expects the same example from junior leaders
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;People see Extreme ownership in their leaders, and as a result emulate extreme ownership throughout the chain of command down to the most junior personnel.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;accept responsibility for failures #responsibility #failure
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Good SEAL leaders took ownership of failures, sought guidance on how to improve, figured out a way to overcome challenges. The best checked their egos, accepted blame, sought constructive criticism, took detailed notes for improvement.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Bad leaders blaming others - the attitude is picked up by subordinates who follow suit.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The direct responsibility of a leader includes getting people to listen, support, and execute plans.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Take ownership of them&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Develop a plan to win&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The leader takes full responsibility for explaining the strategic mission, developing the tactics, and securing training and resources to enable the team to properly and successfully execute.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the individual on the team is not performing at the level required for the team to succeed, the leader must train and mentor the underperformer. If underperformers cannot improve, the leader must make the tough call to terminate them and hire others that can get the job done. It is all on the leader.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;no-bad-teams-only-bad-leaders&quot;&gt;No bad teams, only bad leaders&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hackworth, in &lt;strong&gt;About Face: The Odyssey of an American Warrior&lt;/strong&gt;: American mentors who fought in WWII stated “There are no bad units, only bad officers”.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;a difficult concept accept.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;crucial to fully understand and implement to enable them to most effectively lead a high performing team.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leadership is the single greatest factor in any team’s performance.&lt;/strong&gt; Whether a team succeeds or fails is up to the leader. The leader’s attitude sets the tone for the entire team. The leader drives performance, or doesn’t.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;On the SEAL boat crew, team 2 were killing it. Team 6 were failing. Swapping the leaders, team 6 turned it around and took the lead. Team 2 came second (extreme ownership is contagious).&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lead from the front, from the most difficult position.&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;__“I figured out that I had to put myself in the most difficult position at the front of the boat to lead”.__p49.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on something immediate. Then the next.&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;”..more effective to focus their efforts not on the days to come or the far-distant finish line they couldn’t yet see, but instead on a physical goal immediately in front of them - the bead marker, landmark, or road sign..”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s not what you preach, it’s what you tolerate&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;If substandard performance is accepted, and no-one held accountable - poor performance becomes the new standard.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Leaders must enforce standards.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A leader must pull together different elements within the team to support one another, with all focused on how to best accomplish the mission&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Every team must have junior leaders ready to step up&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;ready to temporarily take on the roles and responsibilities of their immediate bosses.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leaders should never be satisfied&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;always strive to improve and build that mind-set into the team.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bad leaders make excuses. Good leaders figure out a way to get it done and win.&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;CTO wouldn’t accept responsibility. All excuses.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“Tortured Genius” -  accepts zero responsibility for mistakes, makes excuses, blames everyone else for failings. In their mind the rest of the world can’t see or appreciate the genius in what they are doing. An individual with this mind-set can have a catastrophic effect on a team’s performance.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;believe-you-must-understand-the-mission-how-things-fit-together-or-ask-why-until-you-do&quot;&gt;Believe: &lt;strong&gt;You must understand the mission, how things fit together, or ask why until you do&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Actions and words reflect belief.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Detach from the immediate tactical mission and understand how it fits into strategic goals.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is he responsibility of the subordinate leader to reach out and ask if they do not understand.&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;People don’t ask often because they’re scared to look stupid.
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;but look even more stupid trying to explain a mission or strategy you don’t understand or believe in.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Up to you to ask questions until you understand how and why those decisions are being made.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;check-the-ego-criticism&quot;&gt;Check the Ego #criticism&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ego clouds and disrupts everything: the planning process, the ability to take good advice, and the ability to accept constructive criticism.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Everyone has an ego.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be confident, not cocky. Never get complacent.&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Admitting mistakes, taking ownership, developing a plan to overcome challenges are integral to any successful team. #ego&lt;/strong&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Put your ego in check by taking the blame, accepting responsibility. Will take others off their guard.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;cover-and-move-teamwork&quot;&gt;Cover and move: #Teamwork&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;All elements within the greater team are crucial and must work together to accomplish the mission, mutually supporting one another for that singular purpose.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;not compete with one another, blame will develop&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explain what you need from others and why.&lt;/strong&gt; #teamwork&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask them what you can do to help them get you what you need.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make them part of the team.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Departments and groups must
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;break down silos&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;depend on each other&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;understand who depends on them&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leaders: continually keep perspective on the strategic mission and remind the team that they are part of the greater team and the strategic mission is paramount&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;keep-things-simple&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep things simple&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plans and orders must be communicated in a way that is simple, clear, and concise. You must brief to ensure the lowest common denominator understands.&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Combat has inherent layers of complexities. Simplifying is critical to success.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When something goes wrong, and it eventually does - complex plans add to confusion, which can compound into disaster. No mission ever goes according to plan, there are simply too many variables to deal with. This is where simplicity is key. If the plan is simple enough, everyone understands it, which means each person can rapidly adjust and modify what he or she is doing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Example: Simplification of worker bonuses plan in a factory. Before, hugely complex, no-one understood it to drive their behaviour. After, simple and they could actually work to it.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;prioritise-and-execute&quot;&gt;Prioritise and execute&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;In complex situations a leader must remain calm and make the best decisions possible. To do this you must prioritise and execute.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Through &lt;strong&gt;careful contingency planning&lt;/strong&gt; a leader can &lt;strong&gt;anticipate challenges&lt;/strong&gt; that could arise during execution and &lt;strong&gt;map out an effective response to those challenges&lt;/strong&gt; before they happen.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;If the team has been briefed and understands what actions to take through such likely contingencies, the team can rapidly execute when those problems arise, even without specific direction.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To implement prioritise and execute, a leader must:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;evaluate the highest priority item.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;lay out in simple, clear, and concise terms the highest priority effort for your team.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;develop and determine a solution, seek input from key leaders and from the team where possible.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;direct the execution of that solution, focusing all efforts and resources toward this priority task.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;move on to the next highest priority problem. Repeat.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;when priorities shift within the team, pass situational awareness both up and down the chain.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;don’t let the focus on one priority cause target fixation. Maintain the ability to see the other problems developing and rapidly shift as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;decentralised-command&quot;&gt;Decentralised command&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Humans aren’t capable of managing more than 6 to 10 people.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Break teams down into 4/5 operators with a clearly designated leader.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The leader must:&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;understand the overall mission - the Commander’s Intent&lt;/strong&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;WHAT IT IS AND WHY THEY ARE DOING IT
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;if they don’t understand, they must ask their boss to clarify why.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;purpose of the mission, how it ties to strategic goals&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;be empowered to make decisions on key tasks to accomplish the mission&lt;/strong&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;must understand what is within their decision making authority&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;communicate with sr leaders to recommend decisions outside their authority and pass critical information up the chain.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell higher authority what they plan to do&lt;/strong&gt;, rather than ask what to do&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Sr leaders must constantly communicate, push information down - situational awareness&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“Battlefield aloofness” - leaders who are far removed from the frontline become ineffective - appearance of control but no idea of what their teams are doing and can’t effectively direct them.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Understanding proper positioning as a leader is a key component of decentralised command&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Simplicity is important - decentralised command required &lt;strong&gt;simple, clear and concise orders&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;give clear guidance and set distinct boundaries.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;plan-planning&quot;&gt;Plan #planning&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“Mission planning was all about: never taking anything for granted, preparing for likely contingencies, and maximising the chance of a mission success while minimising the risk to the troops executing the operation.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Iraqi kid hostage rescue example given. IEDs and bunkered machine guns intel comes in last minute. No need to replan as already accounted for and mitigated this situation. Good planning.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Planning processes should be standardised so that other departments, and supporting assets outside the company, can understand and use the same format and terminology. This will ensure the highest level of performance and give the team the greatest chance to accomplish the mission and win.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Must be repeatable and guide users with a checklist of all the important things they need to think about.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analyse the mission&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Understand the overall mission, Commander’s intent, and endstate (the goal)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Identify and state your own commander’s intent, and endstate for the specific mission.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do this for the lowest common denominator - the most junior people must be able to understand it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;A broad and ambiguous mission results in lack of focus, ineffective execution, and mission creep. #scope creep&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The mission must explain the overall purpose and desired results, or “end state” of the operation&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identify personnel, assets, resources and timeline available&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decentralise the planning process&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Empower key leaders within the team to analyse possible courses of action.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Determine a specific course of action&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Lean towards the simplest course&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Focus efforts on the best course of action&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empower key leaders to develop the plan for the selected course of action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan for likely contingencies through each phase of the operation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigate risks that can be controlled as much as possible&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delegate portions of the plan and brief to key junior leaders&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;stand back and be the tactical genious&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;standing back gives you another view, which allows you to spot issues, and makes you look like a tactical genius&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continually check and question the plan against emerging information to ensure it still fits the situation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brief the plan to all participants and supporting assets&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Emphasize Commander’s Intent&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Ask questions and engage in discussion and interaction with team to ensure they understand.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“it was critical that we all understood the plan, how and when to communicate and what to do if and when things went wrong”.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conduct post-operatonal debrief after execution&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Analyse lessons learned and implement them in future planning&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;leading-up-and-down-the-chain&quot;&gt;Leading up and down the chain&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Leading down the chain
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Leaders must routinely communicate with their team members to help them understand their role in the mission and how it impacts the company’s strategic goals&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Stepping out of the office, fact to face conversations, observing workers in action, understand their challenges, read them into the Commander’s Intent&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;If they aren’t doing what you need them to do, you must figure out a way to better communicate it to them in terms that are simple, clear, concise, so that they understand.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Leading up the chain
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;A leader must push situational awareness up the chain of command.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Takes more savvy and skill than leading down the chain, no positional authority
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;use influence, experience, knowledge, communication, and maintain the highest professionalism.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;One of the most important jobs of any leader is to support your own boss.
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Leadership must always present a united front to the troops
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;public display of discontent or disagreement undermines the authority of leaders at all levels&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;if you don’t understand - you must ask questions up the chain&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Once the debate over a particular course of action is over and the boss has made a decision, even if that decision is one you argued against, you must execute the plan &lt;strong&gt;as if it were your own&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;If your leader isn’t giving you the support you need, don’t blame them, instead reexamine what you can do to better clarify, educate, influence, or convince that person to give you what you need in order to win.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take responsibility for leading everyone in your world, superiors and subordinates alike.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If someone isn’t doing what you need them to do, look in the mirror first and determine what you can do to better enable this.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t ask your leader what you should do, tell them what you are going to do.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;decisiveness-amid-uncertainty&quot;&gt;Decisiveness amid uncertainty&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Critical for leaders. Make the best decisions based on the immediate information available.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;example of sniper mission in Iraq. Shadow in building, unsure if it’s an enemy. Army commanded wants them to take the shot. Despite pressure -  based on the info, uncertainty and possible outcomes the Seal Commander decides not to take the shot. It was the right call as friendlies in the building.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;No 100% right solution. Picture is never complete. Leaders must be comfortable with this and be able to make decisions promptly, then be ready to adjust those decisions quickly bases on evolving situations and new information.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Intelligence gathering and research are important, but must be employed with realistic expectations and not impede swift decision making that’s often the difference between victory and defeat.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Waiting for 100% certainty leads to
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;delay&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;indecision&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;inability to execute&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Leaders must make an educated guess based on previous experience, knowledge of how the enemy operates, likely outcomes, whatever intel is available at the immediate moment.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A leader’s default setting should be aggressive, proactive rather than reactive.&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;critical to the success of any team - instead of letting the situation dictate our decisions, we must dictate the situation.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;discipline-equals-freedom&quot;&gt;Discipline Equals Freedom&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Discipline gives you freedom. Getting up early gives you more time, you get an advantage, you have freedom. Executing with discipline means we do better, save time, have efficiency, giving freedom.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The dichotomy of leadership&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;A good leader must be:
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;confident but not cocky&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;courageous but not foolhardy&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;competitive but a gracious loser&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;strong but have endurance&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;a leader and a follower&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;humble but not passive&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;aggressive but not overbearing&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;calm but not robotic; logical but not devoid of emotions&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;quiet but not silent&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;close with the troops but not so close that one becomes more important than another or more important than the good of the team; not so close that they forget who is in charge.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;able to execute Extreme Ownership while exercising Decentralised Command&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A good leader has nothing to prove, but everything to prove&lt;/strong&gt;. The team understands they are in charge, nothing to prove. But the leader has to develop trust and confidence in judgement, so everything to prove.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="book" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="performance" /><category term="teams" /><category term="critical" /><summary type="html">Recommendation: 9/10 I really like the concept of Extreme Ownership; a leader owns everything in their world, “there is no-one else to blame”. It’s written by two ex U.S. Navy SEAL officers who served in Iraq. Each leadership principle is given along with examples from their time in combat, as well as what they’ve seen whilst consulting in industry. All the principles in the book are important, however some of the chapters are better than others; in terms of the combat story, principle and business story pattern each follows. In particular “no bad teams, only bad leaders” was standout for me. It’s definitely something I’ll use and recommend to others. To borrow a line from the book, what’s in there is simple, but it isn’t easy. A must read for leaders of any rank.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Oscars vs language</title><link href="/the-oscars-vs-language" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Oscars vs language" /><published>2020-07-27T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-07-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/the-oscars-vs-language</id><content type="html" xml:base="/the-oscars-vs-language">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/oscars.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;lots of Oscars statues&quot; style=&quot;max-width:100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you noticed how often people accepting an award say that they feel humbled?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be humbled means to be made to feel lowly or insignificant; you’re humbled if you’ve been beaten. It’s the feeling you get of being small when looking at a vast horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t square with me that receiving an award can make you feel humbled; attending an event surrounded by people you think are more worthy humbles you, but going on to beat them lifts you up. You’ve been told you’re the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From what I can tell, the word humbled is used, instead of “proud” for three reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We’re so used to hearing recipients of awards saying they feel humbled that it feels natural. It’s part of popular culture. I think that this is the reason most people use it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Virtue signalling - saying you’re humbled makes you sound humble. It’s self effacing, an acknowledgement of unworthiness. “Check me out - I could boast, but I’m humble”; it could only have come from Hollywood or politics.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Due to the above, you actually sound like a dick if you don’t say you’re humbled.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The irony is that you’re only in a position to be humbled when you’re on top. You’ll rarely hear the loser (the most likely person to be humbled) saying that they’re humbled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Language changes over time and new cultural norms emerge; Hollywood rewrote this one. Oscars 1 : Dictionary 0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final thought..&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humbled might be turning into a contranym; a word that can mean both something, and its opposite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few good examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sick, wicked, badass are all used colloquially as “good or great”.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To dust, can mean to both add dust (like to dust a cake with sugar) and remove dust (to dust a room).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Critical can mean vital to success (eg. a critical component), or disparaging (a critical comment).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If like me you’re interested in these geeky things, more can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/Appendix:English_contranyms&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="culture" /><summary type="html">Only winners get to feel &quot;humbled&quot;.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forever Employable - by Jeff Gothelf</title><link href="/forever-employable-by-jeff-gothelf" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forever Employable - by Jeff Gothelf" /><published>2020-07-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-07-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/forever%20employable%20by%20jeff%20gothelf</id><content type="html" xml:base="/forever-employable-by-jeff-gothelf">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendation: 6/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/f-emp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Forever employable book cover&quot; style=&quot;height: 200px; float: right; padding: 0px 0px 0px 15px;&quot; /&gt;I like the way Jeff takes us through his personal epiphany that led to the central idea of this book; to become a well known expert in a particular niche and have employers seek you out. The message is good but you really could get the key points across in an article (it’s a very short book as it is). Useful enough to recommend though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-big-idea-what-so-what-now-what&quot;&gt;The big idea. What, so what, now what?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Traditional career paths lead to a dangerous place. You become a manager rather than a doer. You loose skills and become dependent on a company. Instead become a recognised expert.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Far from becoming irrelevant. People will come and find you. You won’t depend on a company. You’ll be “forever employable”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop a specialism in a niche. Get out there, produce content, deliver it. Build a reputation in that area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-notes&quot;&gt;My notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 key areas of the philosophy:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Entrepreneurialism&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Self-confidence&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Continuous learning&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Improvement&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Reinvention&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SOLVE REAL WORLD PROBLEMS. GIVE PEOPLE SOMETHING THEY CAN ACTION.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;plant-a-flag&quot;&gt;Plant a Flag&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A topic, an expertise or point of view that you own and then go all in on.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You have to have an opinion, a strong conviction about some topic. You build a platform on top of your informed opinion about a very specific topic.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You have to have a story - to keep people listening. Something you realised about the profession, early failures, ridiculous things you’ve seen.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are you pasionate about? What are you expert in? What path do you want your future to take? What aspects of your whole person has value to others?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is your target audience? What are you going to help them with - what will you improve? What are you going to teach them? How are you going to reach them?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;TOPIC: In what field will you plant your flag and what will be your unique angle?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;AUDIENCE: Who will be your target audience? Beginners? Experts? Creating content for everyone means creating content for no one.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;FORMAT: How will you reach your target audience? Videos, blogs, events, podcasts. Choose 1 or 2 initially.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;MEASURES OF SUCCESS: How will you know you’re reaching your audience? Resonating? “If my content resonates and reaches my audience, what will they be doing differently?” More followers, inbound requests to speak at meetups and events. Evidencing attention, changing behaviours is the true measure.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Write hypothesis. I believe that &lt;strong&gt;something provided to target audience&lt;/strong&gt; will &lt;strong&gt;achieve this outcome&lt;/strong&gt;. I will know I am right when I see &lt;strong&gt;quantifiable changes of behaviour in my target audience&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Run experiments.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pay attention to:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Trends. geopolitical, economic, social, environmental.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Technology. Social media, privacy, security, ethics, machine learning, artificial intelligence.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Opportunities. ““In the middle of difficulty lies.” #opportunity #difficulty #quote”Look for pain points that businesses, employees and customers endure, seek solutions that have potential to resolve them.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Expertise, keep yours up to date.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The intersection of all of these.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;tell-your-story&quot;&gt;Tell your story&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Solve a real problem.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Real world experience gives you authenticity and credibility.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Be humble, share the wins and losses.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Practical and tactical advice for people to use.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Consistent and refined vocabulary that people can use.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Characters, plot and story arc.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Personal anecdotes.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Practice.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Speak the language of your audience.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;follow-the-new-path&quot;&gt;Follow the (new) path&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;teach&quot;&gt;Teach&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Workshops, conferences, meetups, webinars, podcasts, guest articles and interviews.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Workshops are a good revenue source or for lead generation.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;give-it-all-away&quot;&gt;Give it all away&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The more you give away, the more success you’ll drive for your business.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Expensive means people value it more.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;First build a following and credibility.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Be consistent. People know you’ll always publish a newsletter every month, a post on one of 4 subjects every month.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Give back to the community. Free events.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Be a recognised expert (Stand out, book by Dorie Clark):
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;content creation&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;social proof&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;your network&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Think about the things that aren’t going to change - the things that people are going to need consistently time and time again. That’s going to be good process, good collaboration, good places to work, good leadership.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;““I very frequently get the question: ‘What’s going to change in the next 10 years?’ And that is a very interesting question; it’s a very common one. I almost never get the question: ‘What’s not going to change in the next 10 years?’ And I submit to you that that second question is actually the more important of the two – because you can build a business strategy around the things that are stable in time. … [I]n our retail business, we know that customers want low prices, and I know that’s going to be true 10 years from now. They want fast delivery; they want vast selection. It’s impossible to imagine a future 10 years from now where a customer comes up and says, ‘Jeff I love Amazon; I just wish the prices were a little higher,’ [or] ‘I love Amazon; I just wish you’d deliver a little more slowly.’ Impossible. And so the effort we put into those things, spinning those things up, we know the energy we put into it today will still be paying off dividends for our customers 10 years from now. When you have something that you know is true, even over the long term, you can afford to put a lot of energy into it.” #quote #change #stability #future”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Do this:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Follow thought leaders, what are they talking about and how are they talking about it?&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Join the conversation. Always be polite, contributing, not trying to take it over.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Share your work regularly. Every couple of weeks or month, blog post, tweet, article.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provide value, not just noise. Something tangible the audience can do. Something someone could try to do differently&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Scale ideas that resonate. Double down on them. From tweets to blog posts to presentations.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Intercom as an example, get their people to generate content and be present in conversations - generates buzz and inbound leads.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="book" /><category term="career" /><category term="self-help" /><summary type="html">Recommendation: 6/10 I like the way Jeff takes us through his personal epiphany that led to the central idea of this book; to become a well known expert in a particular niche and have employers seek you out. The message is good but you really could get the key points across in an article (it’s a very short book as it is). Useful enough to recommend though.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Operation Mincemeat - by Ben Macintyre</title><link href="/operation-mincemeat-by-ben-macyntyre" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Operation Mincemeat - by Ben Macintyre" /><published>2020-05-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-05-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/operation%20mincemeat%20by%20ben%20macyntyre</id><content type="html" xml:base="/operation-mincemeat-by-ben-macyntyre">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendation: 9/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/op-mm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Operation Mincemeat book cover&quot; style=&quot;height: 200px; float: right; padding: 0px 0px 0px 15px;&quot; /&gt;Fascinating account of one of the strangest and most daring deceptions of the Second World War. The details and pace are such that it’s hard to put down. Little wonder so many within intelligence at the time, such as Ian Fleming, were or became novelists. Fiction inspired real life which went on to inspire fiction. As the author states, we’ll never really know the extent to which Mincemeat helped the invasion of Sicily over other deception activities going on (such as the fake army build ups, activities in Greece etc). But if it wasn’t the key element, it played a big role. An important story to tell, and well told.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-a-dead-man-and-a-bizarre-plan-fooled-the-nazis-and-assured-an-allied-victory&quot;&gt;How a Dead Man and a Bizarre Plan Fooled the Nazis and Assured an Allied Victory&lt;/h4&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="book" /><category term="spy" /><category term="espionage" /><category term="war" /><category term="great" /><summary type="html">Recommendation: 9/10 Fascinating account of one of the strangest and most daring deceptions of the Second World War. The details and pace are such that it’s hard to put down. Little wonder so many within intelligence at the time, such as Ian Fleming, were or became novelists. Fiction inspired real life which went on to inspire fiction. As the author states, we’ll never really know the extent to which Mincemeat helped the invasion of Sicily over other deception activities going on (such as the fake army build ups, activities in Greece etc). But if it wasn’t the key element, it played a big role. An important story to tell, and well told.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Antifragile - by Nassim Taleb</title><link href="/antifragile-by-nassim-taleb" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Antifragile - by Nassim Taleb" /><published>2020-04-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-04-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/antifragile%20by%20nassim%20taleb</id><content type="html" xml:base="/antifragile-by-nassim-taleb">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendation: 10/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/antifragile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Antifragile book cover&quot; style=&quot;height: 200px; float: right; padding: 0px 0px 0px 15px;&quot; /&gt;Taleb’s style is rough around the edges. That’s what’s so refreshing about him and his work. We need outsiders; challenging the status quo, providing different perspectives and calling out bullshit. Antifragile takes us across disciplines to look at what’s causing fragility in our systems and economies, why and how we can resolve them using the concept of antifragility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-notes&quot;&gt;My notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Split into 4 “Books”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;book-1-introduction-to-the-concept&quot;&gt;Book 1: Introduction to the concept&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Antifragile. Something which gains from and in fact needs disorder (to an extent). Human body needs stressors.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fragile-Robust-Antifragile.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Antifragility of the whole depends on the fragility of the parts. Small failures prevent large failures.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;book-2-denial-of-antifragility-and-its-manifestation-in-naive-interventionism&quot;&gt;Book 2: Denial of antifragility and it’s manifestation in naive interventionism&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;[[The Procrustean Bed]] used an example. We chop and stretch things to fit our world.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;Subsidiarity&lt;/strong&gt; is a principle of social organisation that holds that social and political issues should be dealt with at the most immediate (or local) level that is consistent with their resolution.” (https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Subsidiarity) General principle of [[European Union]] law - this is linked to [[Decentralisation]]&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;[[Switzerland]] - collection of small municipalities that have enmity. Is antifragile. Small volatile mini states but [[stable]] on an aggregate level.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Principle-Agent problem. When the one providing the services’ interests are divorced from those using his services.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Naive [[Interventionism]] makes things fragile. Doctors overprescribing patients. Prevention of small forest fires which causes buildup of material that creates massive ones. Greenspan or Gordon Brown smoothing the booms and busts in economies that just made the eventual collapse of 2008 bigger. Bush in the Iraq war post 9/11. Other times more intervention is needed, such as with the environment. We need a systemic protocol to determine when to intervene and when to leave systems alone. #[[Systems Thinking]]
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Drachten effect - in the Dutch town they took away street signs, made it safer since people had to concentrate more.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Nowadays there is more and more noise drowning out the signal - ie more data means more noise. Best way to mitigate naive interventionism is to ration the supply of information as naturalistically as possible. Science does not mean more data. #Data&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Other examples of intervention causing harm. The Chinese famine between ‘59 and ‘61 that killed 30 million people.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;[[Iatrogenics]]: where treatment causes more harm than benefit. Like blood letting of George Washington to ‘cure’ him.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;book-3-asymmetry-the-barbell-strategy---8020-rule&quot;&gt;Book 3: Asymmetry. The barbell strategy - 80/20 rule.&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Talks [[Seneca]] - creating more upside than downside. Don’t go for the ‘middle’ where there is risk of ruin. Go for maximally safe and maximally speculative (80/20). #investment. Pure action and pure reflection.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;book-4-optionality-technology-and-the-intelligence-of-antifragility&quot;&gt;Book 4: Optionality, technology and the intelligence of antifragility.&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Observes we are in a complex, non linear world, we don’t know what works and people don’t know what they want. [[Apple]] built the iPhone, they didn’t ask people if they wanted one.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Basically says to have options with limited downside but that have high potential upside. Like Thales and his rental of the olive presses.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I find this identical to the way things are done in new product development. You need to have the option, you need to have the intelligence to spot when to cash in / when it’s not working etc.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Talks about [[Epiphenomenon]]: secondary phenomenon that occurs alongside or in parallel to a primary phenomenon - can be mistaken for the cause. Uses the example of the assumption that education-&amp;gt; increase in GDP, when actually prosperity leads to increase in education.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;[[Heuristic]] are valuable. Not only survived due to their own effectiveness, they survived because people that used them survived.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Architects relied on them, Romans didn’t use maths to build aqua-ducts. Empirical methods and tools used. Cathedrals built with small tricks and rules. Innovation through practice - theory comes later.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Examples of innovation coming from practice less well known as history is written by theorists “teaching birds to fly”. Jet engine. “The role of formal knowledge over appreciated as it it &lt;strong&gt;highly visible&lt;/strong&gt;.”
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;the computer&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;the internet&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;-their use today was not predicted. All examples are anti-teleology, that is contrary to the idea of an “explanation of phenomena in terms of the purpose they serve rather than of the cause by which they arise.”&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;[[Heuristic]]:”..the kind of knowledge that comes out of a master guiding his apprentices”.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Cooking provides a great example of applying heuristics over theory.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Venture capitalists say “you bet on the jockey, not the horse”. Innovations drift, it is the individuals that can sport the new opportunities and pivot, take advantage, that do well - not the initial idea. #investment #[[Diversification of investments]] #adaptability #innovation&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“The right approach requires a certain style of blind funding”. “The payoff can be so large that you can’t afford not to be in everything”. #innovation #investment #funding #[[Beyond Budgeting]]&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“Collaboration has explosive upside.” 1+1 is more than 2, exponentially. Superadditive function. #collaboration&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“No evidence that strategic planning works…we seem to have evidence against it”p234. “It makes corporations option-blind, as it get’s locked in to a opportunistic course of action. See William Starbuck’s work. #planning #[[Beyond Budgeting]] #funding&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Examples of pivoting, changing industries, not following a plan. #pivots #planning #agility #adaptability
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Coca cola started as a medicine&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Tiffany &amp;amp; Co was a stationary store&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Raytheon who created the first guided missile system was a refrigerator maker&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Nokia was a paper mill&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Dupont, now making teflon, countertops and kevlar started as an explosives company&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Avon started in door to door book sales&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Oneida Silversmiths was a community religious cult who started a company for regulatory reasons&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evidence of absence is not absence of evidence&lt;/strong&gt;. #empiricism #science&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the antifragile, good news tends to be absent from past data, and for the fragile it is the bad news that doesn’t show easily&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Two distinct payoffs - you want bounded left with unlimited right. Not the reverse.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“bounded left” - limited losses, like Thales’ bet&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“bounded right” - limited gains, like insurance or banking&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The payoff, what happens to you (the benefits or harm from it), is always the most important thing, not the event itself.&lt;/strong&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Checking people at airports, incase there are terrorists. We check because we are fragile to terrorism. Asymmetry.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Spend millions on safety of nuclear reactors.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Do you think this random medicine will harm you. No. But do you ingest pills? No, no, no.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“The probability (hence True/false) does not work in the real world,; it is the payoff that matters”.&lt;/strong&gt; #
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Modify your exposure, rather than learn to predict better.&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Two domains
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Ludic - set up like a game, rules applied in advance in a specific way - the casino. Domain-specific.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Ecological - we don’t know the rules and cannot isolate variables, as in real life #complexity&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;We must embrace the randomness to be antifragile&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Education&lt;/strong&gt; #education
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Follow what interests you. Following a curriculum makes you a robot and you loose creativity and important links that other’s don’t see.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;When you get board, jump to something else.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Read 30-60hours a week.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;This will set you for life rather than the classroom.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knowledge&lt;/strong&gt; #knowledge
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Narrated, intelligible knowledge. School curriculums.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Opaque, probed by tinkering - heuristics. Error of thinking that things always have a reason that is intelligible to us.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;We mistake the unintelligible for the unintelligent. “What is not intelligible to me is not necessarily unintelligent”.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Similar to the turkey problem, mistaking what we don’t see for the nonexistent. Sibling to mistaking absence of evidence for evidence of absence.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Quotes/talks about [[Nietzsche]] quite a bit.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;book-5-nonlinearity---the-difference-between-a-large-stone-and-1000-pebbles-efficiency&quot;&gt;Book 5: Nonlinearity - the difference between a large stone and 1000 pebbles #efficiency&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Maximum efficiency = fragile. Think roads, airports.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Size hurts you in times of stress. Kind of like negative economies of scale.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Gains from size of corporations are highly visible, but risks are hidden.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Why so many mergers fail.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Bent Flyvbjerg has shown that increase in size of projects maps to poor outcomes and higher costs of delays as a proportion of total budget. There is nuance - it is size per segment. Meaning breaking down projects helps prevent this. Which is why roads fare well. #project-management #forecasting #planning
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Projects of 100 million dollars are more unpredictable than projects of 5 million. Higher unpredictability and fragility. More unknowns, more interrelationships.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Smooth functioning at regular times is different from rough functioning at times of stress.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Todays world -complexity, interdependence, globalisation increases Black Swan effects, efficiency makes people sail too close to the wind.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Projects tend to be as weak as the weakest link in the chain.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;If uncertainty were linear we would see some projects completed extremely early. This is not the case.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Complexity plus asymmetry can lead to explosive errors
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;The Great War, WWII, US war in Iraq. Indirect costs multiply.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The fragility in any domain resides in the nonlinear&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;book-6-via-negativa&quot;&gt;Book 6: Via negativa&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;[[Subtraction]], Via negativa, can be more powerful than addition.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“More data - such as paying attention to the eye colours of people around when crossing the street - can make you miss the big truck.” #Data&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Antifragility implies that the old is superior to the new.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“Time has sharp teeth that destroy everything”. - Simonides of Ceos #time&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The Lindy Effect - a technology, or anything non-perishable, increases in life expectancy with every day of its life - unlike perishable items (such as humans, cats, dogs and tomatoes). So a book that has been a hundred years in print is likely to stay in print another hundred years.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Information hides failures - we hear about success stories. Investors are led to overestimate chances of success.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Read as little as feasible from the last twenty years, except history books that are not about the last fifty years”. Read the classics - Lindy effect! - New books outdate fast. #learning #life-hacks #reading #tips&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“The good is mostly in the absence of bad” [[Ennius]] #quote #good&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Sometimes scantiness of nourishment restores the system” - [[Plotinus]] #quote #health&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Caloric restriction as the one key way to lengthen lives. #health&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People who construct or oversee a system must be fully responsible for it&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;[[Hammurabi’s code]] - 229 If a &lt;strong&gt;builder&lt;/strong&gt; builds a house for someone, and does not construct it properly, and the house which he built falls in and kills its owner, then that &lt;strong&gt;builder&lt;/strong&gt; shall be put to death. #responsibility&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“He who does not stop a crime is an accomplice.” - [[Publilius Syrus]] #quote #integrity #ethics #guilt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Globalisation brings fragilities and requires a great deal of redundancies to operate properly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Don’t be fooled by money. These are just numbers. Being self-owned is a state of mind.” - Said by Fat Tony - #quote #happiness #freedom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="book" /><category term="risk" /><category term="critical" /><category term="complexity" /><summary type="html">Recommendation: 10/10 Taleb’s style is rough around the edges. That’s what’s so refreshing about him and his work. We need outsiders; challenging the status quo, providing different perspectives and calling out bullshit. Antifragile takes us across disciplines to look at what’s causing fragility in our systems and economies, why and how we can resolve them using the concept of antifragility.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forty Stories - by Anton Chekhov</title><link href="/forty-stories-anton-chekhov" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forty Stories - by Anton Chekhov" /><published>2020-04-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-04-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/forty%20stories-anton%20chekhov</id><content type="html" xml:base="/forty-stories-anton-chekhov">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendation: 8/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/forty.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Forty stories book cover&quot; style=&quot;height: 200px; float: right; padding: 0px 0px 0px 15px;&quot; /&gt;A brilliant collection; Chekhov is master of the short story. In a few pages, he can bring you closer to a character than many authors can over the course of a novel. These stories add up to a vivid picture of 19th century Russia with a patchwork of characters spanning classes. Kindness, innocence, guilt, miserliness and cruelty are all on display in sometimes surprising and somewhat shocking situations. Personally I found The Little Apples, The Ninny, The Huntsman, The Malefactor, The Peasant Women, After the Theatre, The Lady with the Pet Dog and The Bride to be the most interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="book" /><category term="russian" /><category term="literature" /><summary type="html">Recommendation: 8/10 A brilliant collection; Chekhov is master of the short story. In a few pages, he can bring you closer to a character than many authors can over the course of a novel. These stories add up to a vivid picture of 19th century Russia with a patchwork of characters spanning classes. Kindness, innocence, guilt, miserliness and cruelty are all on display in sometimes surprising and somewhat shocking situations. Personally I found The Little Apples, The Ninny, The Huntsman, The Malefactor, The Peasant Women, After the Theatre, The Lady with the Pet Dog and The Bride to be the most interesting.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Spy and The Traitor - by Ben Macintyre</title><link href="/the-spy-and-the-traitor-by-ben-macyntyre" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Spy and The Traitor - by Ben Macintyre" /><published>2020-04-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-04-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/the%20spy%20and%20the%20traitor%20by%20ben%20macyntyre</id><content type="html" xml:base="/the-spy-and-the-traitor-by-ben-macyntyre">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendation: 9/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sandt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Spy and the Traitor&quot; style=&quot;height: 200px; float: right; padding: 0px 0px 0px 15px;&quot; /&gt;A gripping true spy thriller. This is the perfect combination: an incredible story, well written. I couldn’t put this down. Gordievsky harboured a huge secret, for a long time, and right under his enemies noses. The Soviet Union’s top man, a mole? If you made this up, people would tell you it’s far fetched. Who needs fiction when there are these stories to be told.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-greatest-espionage-story-of-the-cold-war&quot;&gt;The Greatest Espionage Story of the Cold War&lt;/h4&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="book" /><category term="spy" /><category term="espionage" /><category term="war" /><category term="great" /><summary type="html">Recommendation: 9/10 A gripping true spy thriller. This is the perfect combination: an incredible story, well written. I couldn’t put this down. Gordievsky harboured a huge secret, for a long time, and right under his enemies noses. The Soviet Union’s top man, a mole? If you made this up, people would tell you it’s far fetched. Who needs fiction when there are these stories to be told.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Team Topologies - by Matthew Skelton and Manuel Pais</title><link href="/team-topologies-by-matthew-skelton-and-manuel-pais" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Team Topologies - by Matthew Skelton and Manuel Pais" /><published>2020-04-05T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-04-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/team-topologies-by-matthew-skelton-and-manuel-pais</id><content type="html" xml:base="/team-topologies-by-matthew-skelton-and-manuel-pais">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendation: 7.5/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/team-top.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Team topologies book cover&quot; style=&quot;height: 200px; float: right; padding: 0px 0px 0px 15px;&quot; /&gt;The authors have pulled together a lot of wisdom to create some simple, easy to use patterns for team design. It provides many examples, diagrams and case studies which makes them “real”. The central points are simple (that’s the point), so the book could be a lot shorter but I’d certainly recommend it to anyone setting up teams and I’m sure I’ll refer back to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-notes&quot;&gt;My notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;general-rules-to-setting-up-teams&quot;&gt;General rules to setting up teams&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conway’s law - that designs will reflect communication paths still applies, so set up your teams to reflect the architecture you want. Teams should be small, stable and long lived - limit responsibilities and stick to Dunbar’s number for those a person can trust deeply (up to 15) to limit cognitive load so you set them up for success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;team-types-to-choose-from&quot;&gt;Team types to choose from&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors specify 4 types:
Stream aligned (ie business stream), which delivers change across said stream.
Enabling, which supports stream aligned teams, often bridging a capability gap - eg. a team of automation coaches.
Complicated sub-system, which could be a team looking after a system that would otherwise take up a lot of time/cognitive load, so taking it off a stream aligned team’s plate for effectiveness and/or efficiency.
Platform - provides internal services to a stream aligned team in order to reduce cognitive load. Allows stream align teams to focus and is an effective way at standardising the platform or tools the teams are using. Important that this is self service, otherwise you’re just creating more dependencies.
What’s crucial is that teams working in each of the types understand and abide by the expected behaviours detailed in the book, so that there’s clarity in when and how they interact with other teams. This saves a lot of headache.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you split up an existing system? As the saying goes, “there are many ways to skin a cat”, and many options for splitting a system and creating teams are listed -  however by business domain is preferred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-teams-can-interact&quot;&gt;How teams can interact&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 3 patterns identified.
Collaboration - working closely with the other team for a period of time.
X-as-a-service, does what it says on the tin - providing a clearly defined service with low interaction.
Facilitation - helping another team develop a capability or achieve a certain goal.
The authors state it’s possible for the interaction mode to change over time. For example, developing a service may need initial collaboration to understand the client team’s needs. The main thing to bear in mind here is limiting interaction to only what’s necessary so that you minimise the cognitive load on team members.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="book" /><category term="teams" /><category term="org-design" /><summary type="html">Recommendation: 7.5/10 The authors have pulled together a lot of wisdom to create some simple, easy to use patterns for team design. It provides many examples, diagrams and case studies which makes them “real”. The central points are simple (that’s the point), so the book could be a lot shorter but I’d certainly recommend it to anyone setting up teams and I’m sure I’ll refer back to it.</summary></entry></feed>