<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://kaufie.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://kaufie.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-10-20T18:23:22+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/feed.xml</id><subtitle>Sasha Kaufmann's profile website and article archive.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The path of least resistance</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/the-path-of-least-resistance" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The path of least resistance" /><published>2021-10-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-10-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/the-path-of-least-resistance</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/the-path-of-least-resistance">&lt;p&gt;Productivity apps draw me in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re new toys to play with, and there’s always the possibility of improving my workflow. But when it comes to tasks on a day to day basis I always seem to return to the notepad next to my desk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not some smartly laid out and pristine notebook, just whatever blank book I have to scribble into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My system is simple. If something I’ve jotted down has an action for me, it has a check box next to it. At the start and end of each day I scan the last couple of pages to remind myself of what’s outstanding. Ideally I’ll have got to an action by the time it falls a couple of pages back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consequence of this is that if I haven’t done something by the time I’m a few pages ahead, it’s binned. This is a good thing! Clearly it wasn’t that important, and since the book is right in front of me all day and I review what’s there regularly, I naturally see anything not getting done. If it’s important enough to warrent more focus I’ll keep it at the front of the list by noting it again. Otherwise I’ll either leave it or cross it out completely. I don’t really care much about sizing, but it’s easy to tell when something’s too big and will be hanging around too long. If it’s going to take more than a day I’ll generally break it into smaller actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep returning to this system because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s the fastest way by far to note something that needs doing. Especially the small things. 0 clicks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leads to action on those small things, because if they don’t get done soon they won’t get done at all. It’s a forcing function.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It keeps the big things at front of mind and encourages me to break them down to make progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The constraints in my system are an enabler. If I used A3 instead of A5 pages, I wouldn’t be as focussed, more work would build up and it’d take longer to go through it. Physically only being able to see a couple of pages at a time creates focus and the effort of flicking back means that well, you don’t. It also means I get a lot done, because if I leave things, it’ll take more effort to keep on top of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still use a couple of different apps for goals, notes and other stuff, but they’ll never be as available as my scratchpad. The process of gravitating towards the path of least resistance like this is natural. There’s a subconscious cost/benefit analysis going on that moves you towards the most efficient route, as long as it’s still effective. That’s why when designing any process or way of working, don’t fight the path of least resistance, find it. It’s the most effective way to get to your goal.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="improvement" /><category term="life" /><category term="productivity" /><category term="work" /><summary type="html">Don't fight it, find it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/article-assets/tasks-list.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/article-assets/tasks-list.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ordinary Men - Reserve Police Battalion 101 and the Final Solution in Poland by Christopher Browning</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/ordinary-men-by-christopher-browning" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ordinary Men - Reserve Police Battalion 101 and the Final Solution in Poland by Christopher Browning" /><published>2021-10-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-10-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/ordinary-men-by-christopher-browning</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/ordinary-men-by-christopher-browning">&lt;p&gt;It was hard but everyone should read this. Browning discusses many factors that influenced a unit of average middle-aged Germans in becoming cold-blooded murderers of tens of thousands of Jews; obedience to authority, conformity, self justifications and dehumanisation among others. His point is that in certain situations ordinary men are capable of horrific acts that are unthinkable in other circumstances. Each man had a choice and is responsible for his actions, but it’s a chilling reflection on what ‘ordinary’ men are capable of.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="history" /><category term="non-fiction" /><category term="WW2" /><summary type="html">It was hard but everyone should read this. Browning discusses many factors that influenced a unit of average middle-aged Germans in becoming cold-blooded murderers of tens of thousands of Jews; obedience to authority, conformity, self justifications and dehumanisation among others. His point is that in certain situations ordinary men are capable of horrific acts that are unthinkable in other circumstances. Each man had a choice and is responsible for his actions, but it’s a chilling reflection on what ‘ordinary’ men are capable of.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-assets/book-ordinary-men.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-assets/book-ordinary-men.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Infectious energy</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/infectious-energy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Infectious energy" /><published>2021-10-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-10-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/infectious-energy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/infectious-energy">&lt;p&gt;I noticed something about one of the swimming instructors as I sat in the observation area at the leisure centre. Initially I looked over because he was talking loudly. But it wasn’t just that; the way he was interacting with the class was full of energy. It was infectious. Even his interactions with the parents seemed energetic. He looked like he loved his job and what he was doing seemed to matter. You want to be around someone like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Energy, enthusiasm and positivity start a chain reaction. They rub off on others, who then affect others. Negative energy is more like a vacuum. It doesn’t spread in quite the same way, it just slows momentum like friction on a rolling stone. The government bureaucrat who treats people as an inconvenience, the colleague who is always complaining. It’s what the hippies called good or bad vibes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can create energy or take it away. I don’t think that anyone really wants to take it away. It’s the situation they’re in. If you can’t get motivated or excited about what you’re doing, that’s a good tell that you’re in the wrong job. If you’re in an unhappy place, work to change it or move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create infectious energy, or keep looking.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="life" /><category term="life" /><category term="happiness" /><summary type="html">Positive energy creates a chain reaction.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/article-assets/infectious-energy.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/article-assets/infectious-energy.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Alive by Piers Paul Read</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/alive-by-piers-paul-read" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alive by Piers Paul Read" /><published>2021-06-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-06-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/alive-by-piers-paul-read</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/alive-by-piers-paul-read">&lt;p&gt;What a story. The famous 1972 case of a plane carrying the Uruguayan rugby team coming down in the Andes. The harsh experiences of the group and the choices they had to make in order to survive are superbly told. There’s camaraderie and cannibalism; zombie apocalypse tv shows have nothing on this.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="survival" /><category term="non-fiction" /><category term="mountaineering" /><category term="cannibalism" /><category term="latin-america" /><summary type="html">What a story. The famous 1972 case of a plane carrying the Uruguayan rugby team coming down in the Andes. The harsh experiences of the group and the choices they had to make in order to survive are superbly told. There’s camaraderie and cannibalism; zombie apocalypse tv shows have nothing on this.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-assets/book-alive.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-assets/book-alive.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How the Scots Invented the Modern World by Arthur L. Herman</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/how-the-scots-invented-the-modern-world-by-Arthur-L-Herman" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How the Scots Invented the Modern World by Arthur L. Herman" /><published>2021-06-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-06-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/how-the-scots-invented-the-modern-world-by-Arthur-L-Herman</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/how-the-scots-invented-the-modern-world-by-Arthur-L-Herman">&lt;p&gt;Scotland’s impact on philosophy, religion, history, science, technology and culture has been remarkable. This book charts the transformation of a poor nation to a shaper of the modern world.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got the book recommendation from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlie_Munger&quot;&gt;Charlie Munger&lt;/a&gt;’s almanack - one of his favourites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;influence&quot;&gt;Influence:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Legal system.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Education.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;History and society.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Capitalism.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Changes to Christianity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Steam engines.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Architecture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evolutionary theory.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;North America and the Commonwealth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;International time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;American industrialists.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Novelists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="history" /><category term="Scotland" /><category term="philosophy" /><category term="culture" /><category term="religion" /><summary type="html">Scotland’s impact on philosophy, religion, history, science, technology and culture has been remarkable. This book charts the transformation of a poor nation to a shaper of the modern world.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-assets/book-scots.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-assets/book-scots.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Accelerate - Building and Scaling High Performing Technology Organisations by Nicole Forsgren, Jez Humble, Gene Kim</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/accelerate-building-and-scaling-high-performing-technology-organisations-by-forsgren-humble-kim" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Accelerate - Building and Scaling High Performing Technology Organisations by Nicole Forsgren, Jez Humble, Gene Kim" /><published>2021-05-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-05-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/accelerate-building-and-scaling-high-performing-technology-organisations-by-forsgren-humble-kim</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/accelerate-building-and-scaling-high-performing-technology-organisations-by-forsgren-humble-kim">&lt;p&gt;A spin-off from the State of DevOps surveys. This book presents the findings of their research in the form of capabilities that correlate to or predict performance in software organisations. A good high level overview of what will likely make your organisation better performing, but I found it a bit repetitive and the parts on how they carried out the survey were dull.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Common traps
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Top down mandate to adopt Agile.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Thinking it’s one size fits all.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Not focussing on measurement or the right things to measure.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Leadership behaviour not changing.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Treating transformation like a program instead of creating a learning organisation.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;24 capabilities that drive improvement in software performance, split into 5 categories.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Measuring software delivery performance
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Lead time&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deployment frequency&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mean Time to Restore (MTTR)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Change Fail Percentage&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maturity models are not the appropriate tool or mindset to have. Instead focus on a capabilities model of measurement.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The best organisations never call themselves “mature” as they are never done. Capabilities continually improve and progress - forever.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Capabilities can be chosen from to suit organisational needs rather than a one size fits all maturity model.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Capability models focus on key outcomes and how the capabilities drive improvement in these.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unplanned work is described in The Visible Ops Handbook as the difference between “paying attention to the low fuel warning light on an automobile versus running out of gas on the highway”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h1 id=&quot;continuous-delivery&quot;&gt;Continuous delivery&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Version control
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;eg. GutHub or Subversion for all production artefacts.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deployment automation&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Continuous integration
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Code is regularly checked in and each check-in triggers tests to discover serious regressions, which devs fix immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Trunk-based development
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Developing off trunk/master rather than long lived feature branches. Max 3 active branches in a repository. Branches with short lifetimes, less than a day before being merged into master, rarely or never having code freezes.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Test automation
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;That’s reliable - confident that failures indicate a real defect.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Developers primarily create and maintain acceptance tests and they can easily reproduce and fix them on their development workstations.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Test data management&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Shift left on security
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Design, demos, test automation (security features are tested as part of the automated test suite) - in a way that doesn’t slow down the development process&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Giving developers the means to build security in rather than Infosec doing security reviews.
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Easier and avoids rework.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Infosec teams don’t have the capacity to do security reviews when deployments are frequent.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Continuous delivery (CD)
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The system is kept in a deployable state over working on new features.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Build quality in
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;W. Edwards Deming stated “Cease dependence on inspection to achieve quality. Eliminate the need for inspection on a mass basis by building quality into the product in the first place”.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Detect and fix issues quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Work in small batches
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;‘even though working in small chunks adds some overhead, it reaps enormous rewards by allowing us to avoid work that delivers zero or negative value for our organisations’.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Computers perform repetitive tasks; people solve problems.
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Such as regression testing and software deployments - simplify and automate.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Relentlessly pursue continuous improvement.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Everyone is responsible.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Foundations
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Comprehensive configuration management&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Continuous integration (CI)&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Continuous testing
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Automated unit and acceptance tests should be run against every commit to version control - fast feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Testers should be performing exploratory testing continuously against the latest builds to come out of CI.&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Requires a significant investment in test and deployment automation combined with relentless work to simplify architecture on an ongoing basis to ensure that this automation isn’t prohibitively expensive to create and maintain.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Leads to
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;High levels of software delivery performance (lead time, deploy frequency, time to restore service).&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Lower change fail rates.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;A generative, performance oriented culture.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Lower levels of deployment pain.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Reduced team burnout.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h1 id=&quot;architecture&quot;&gt;Architecture&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Loosely coupled architecture
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Correlates to better performance, especially with scaling.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“We can do most of our testing without requiring an integrated environment”.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“We can deploy or release our application independently of other applications/services it depends on”.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Empowered teams
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Without depending on other teams or systems.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Giving them a choice of tools.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Notes
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Low performers were found to be using or integrating with custom software provided by another company - this is why stuff should be brought in-house.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h1 id=&quot;product-and-process&quot;&gt;Product and process&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Customer feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Value stream.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Working in small batches.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Team experimentation.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h1 id=&quot;lean-management-and-monitoring&quot;&gt;Lean management and monitoring&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Change approval processes
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;keep it light.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Monitoring
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;across application and infrastructure to inform business decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Proactive notification
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;of system health through monitoring. Preemptively detect and mitigate problems.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;WIP limits&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Visualising work&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;notes
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Burnout
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Physical, mental or emotional exhaustion caused by overwork or stress but more than overworked or stressed. Makes things we once loved about our work feel insignificant and dull. Feeling of helplessness - correlated with pathological cultures and unproductive, wasteful work.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;avert by
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;fostering a respectful, supportive work environment that emphisises learning from failures rather than blaming.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;communicating a strong sense of purpose.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;investing in employee development.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;asking employees what is preventing them from achieving their objectives and then fixing those things.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;giving employees time, space, and resources to experiment and learn.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;giving employees authority to make decisions that affect their work and their jobs, particularly in areas where they are responsible for their outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Six organisational risk factors that predict burnout (Leiter and Maslash 2008)
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Work overload: job demands exceed human limits.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Lack of control: inability to influence decisions that affect your job.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Insufficient rewards: insufficient financial, institutional or social rewards.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Breakdown of community: unsupportive workplace environment.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Absence of fairness: lack of fairness in decision making processes.&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Value conflicts: mismatch in organisational values and the individual’s values.&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Employee satisfaction
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;“whilst this may seem like a simplistic measure, research has shown that NPS correlates to company growth in many industries (Reichheld 2003). Similar to company NPS, employee NPS (eNPS) is used to measure employee loyalty.” p104&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Transformational Leadership
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;means leaders inspiring and motivating followers to achieve higher performance by appealing to their values and sense of purpose, facilitating wide-scale organisational change.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;they found it was highly correlated with eNPS.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;5 traits from from Rafferty and Griffin 2004
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Vision
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                      &lt;li&gt;Has a clear understanding of where the organisation is going and where it should be in five years.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Inspirational communication
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                      &lt;li&gt;Communicates in a way that inspires and motivates, even in an uncertain or challenging environment.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Intellectual stimulation
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                      &lt;li&gt;Challenges followers to think about problems in new ways.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Supportive leadership
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                      &lt;li&gt;Demonstrates care and consideration of followers personal needs and feelings.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Personal recognition
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                      &lt;li&gt;Praises and acknowledges achievement of goals and improvements in work quality; personally compliments others when they do outstanding work.&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h1 id=&quot;cultural&quot;&gt;Cultural&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Westrum organisational culture
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pathological&lt;/strong&gt;
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bureaucratic&lt;/strong&gt;
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Power oriented
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Rule oriented
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                      &lt;li&gt;Performance oriented&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Low cooperation
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Modest cooperation
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                      &lt;li&gt;High cooperation&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Messengers “shot”
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Messengers neglected
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                      &lt;li&gt;Messengers trained&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Responsibilities shirked
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Narrow responsibilities
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                      &lt;li&gt;Risks are shared&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Bridging discouraged
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Bridging tolerated
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                      &lt;li&gt;Bridging encouraged&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Failure leads to scapegoating
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Failure leads to justice
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                      &lt;li&gt;Failure leads to inquiry&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Novelty crushed
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Novelty leads to problems
                    &lt;ul&gt;
                      &lt;li&gt;Novelty implemented&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Supporting learning&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Collaboration among teams&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Job satisfaction&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Transformational leadership&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Notes
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Bureaucracy isn’t necessarily bad. Formulated by bureaucrats who are experts in their field, the rules would impose efficient structures and processes while guaranteeing fairness and eliminating arbitrariness.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;In a research project Google discovered that who is on a team matters less than how the team members interact, structure their work, and view their contributions.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Human error should be the &lt;strong&gt;start&lt;/strong&gt; of an investigation. Our goal is to discover how to improve information flow so that people have better and more timely information and better tools to prevent catastrophic failure whilst following apparently mundane operations.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The research shows that lean management, along with a set of other technical practices known collectively as continuous delivery do in fact impact culture and change the Westrum organisational culture.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Many agile adoptions often treat technical practices as secondary compared to the management and team practices that so many frameworks emphasise. Our research shows that technical practices play a vital role in achieving these outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="organisations" /><category term="software" /><category term="lean" /><category term="DevOps" /><summary type="html">A spin-off from the State of DevOps surveys. This book presents the findings of their research in the form of capabilities that correlate to or predict performance in software organisations. A good high level overview of what will likely make your organisation better performing, but I found it a bit repetitive and the parts on how they carried out the survey were dull.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-assets/book-accelerate.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-assets/book-accelerate.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Agent Zigzag by Ben Macintyre</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/agent-zigzag-by-ben-macntyre" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Agent Zigzag by Ben Macintyre" /><published>2021-05-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-05-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/agent-zigzag-by-ben-macntyre</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/agent-zigzag-by-ben-macntyre">&lt;p&gt;The true story of one of Britain’s most notorious double agents, Eddie Chapman. A smooth criminal, prisoner, agent of German Abwehr and finally a British double agent. The lines between all his roles blurred and espionage gave him the same rush as crime. He may have been the kind of man who would look you in the eye as he picked your pocket, but what’s clear is that he did Britain a great service at a great deal of personal risk. A colourful character and a story so wild that you couldn’t have made it up; as with Macintyre’s other books I enjoyed every minute of it.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="spy" /><category term="espionage" /><category term="ww2" /><summary type="html">The true story of one of Britain’s most notorious double agents, Eddie Chapman. A smooth criminal, prisoner, agent of German Abwehr and finally a British double agent. The lines between all his roles blurred and espionage gave him the same rush as crime. He may have been the kind of man who would look you in the eye as he picked your pocket, but what’s clear is that he did Britain a great service at a great deal of personal risk. A colourful character and a story so wild that you couldn’t have made it up; as with Macintyre’s other books I enjoyed every minute of it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-assets/book-zigzag.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-assets/book-zigzag.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Working Backwards by Colin Bryar and Bill Carr</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/working-backwards-by-Colin-Bryar-and-Bill-Carr" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Working Backwards by Colin Bryar and Bill Carr" /><published>2021-04-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-04-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/working-backwards-by-Colin-Bryar-and-Bill-Carr</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/working-backwards-by-Colin-Bryar-and-Bill-Carr">&lt;p&gt;Always interesting to get insider insight into the big successful companies. Colin and Bill were at Amazon practically from the start and had front row seats. I’d heard about a bunch of Amazon’s practices so it’s interesting to read the detail and what problems they solved for Amazon. Not a ground-breaking book on ways of working, but with enough insights and background to make it worth recommending.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;amazons-leadership-principles&quot;&gt;Amazons leadership principles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Customer Obsession&lt;/b&gt;: Leaders start with the customer and work backwards. They work vigorously to earn and keep customer trust. Although leaders pay attention to competitors, they &lt;i&gt;obsess&lt;/i&gt; over customers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ownership&lt;/b&gt;: Leaders are owners. They think long term and don’t sacrifice long-term value for short-term results. They act on behalf of the entire company, beyond just their own team. They never say “that’s not my job.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Invent and Simplify&lt;/b&gt;: Leaders expect and require innovation and invention from their teams and always find ways to simplify. They are externally aware, look for new ideas from everywhere, and are not limited by “not invented here.” As we do new things, we accept that we may be misunderstood for long periods of time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Are Right, A Lot&lt;/b&gt;: Leaders are right a lot. They have strong business judgment and good instincts. They seek diverse perspectives and work to disconfirm their beliefs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hire and Develop the Best&lt;/b&gt;: Leaders raise the performance bar with every hire and promotion. They recognise exceptional talent, and willingly move them throughout the organisation. Leaders develop leaders and take seriously their role in coaching others. We work on behalf of our people to invent mechanisms for development like Career Choice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Insist on the Highest Standards&lt;/b&gt;: Leaders have relentlessly high standards—many people may think these standards are unreasonably high. Leaders are continually raising the bar and driving their teams to deliver high-quality products, services, and processes. Leaders ensure that defects do not get sent down the line and that problems are fixed so they stay fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Think Big&lt;/b&gt;: Thinking small is a self-fulfilling prophecy. Leaders create and communicate a bold direction that inspires results. They think differently and look around corners for ways to serve customers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bias for Action&lt;/b&gt;: Speed matters in business. Many decisions and actions are reversible and do not need extensive study. We value calculated risk taking.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Frugality&lt;/b&gt;: Accomplish more with less. Constraints breed resourcefulness, self-sufficiency and invention. There are no extra points for growing headcount, budget size, or fixed expense.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Learn and Be Curious&lt;/b&gt;: Leaders are never done learning and always seek to improve themselves. They are curious about new possibilities and act to explore them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Earn Trust&lt;/b&gt;: Leaders listen attentively, speak candidly, and treat others respectfully. They are vocally self-critical, even when doing so is awkward or embarrassing. Leaders do not believe their or their team’s body odour smells of perfume. They benchmark themselves and their teams against the best.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dive Deep&lt;/b&gt;: Leaders operate at all levels, stay connected to the details, audit frequently, and are sceptical when metrics and anecdote differ. No task is beneath them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Have Backbone&lt;/b&gt;; Disagree and Commit: Leaders are obligated to respectfully challenge decisions when they disagree, even when doing so is uncomfortable or exhausting. Leaders have conviction and are tenacious. They do not compromise for the sake of social cohesion. Once a decision is determined, they commit wholly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Deliver Results&lt;/b&gt;: Leaders focus on the key inputs for their business and deliver them with the right quality and in a timely fashion. Despite setbacks, they rise to the occasion and never settle.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;The magic lives in the moments when the principles are put into practice. Adding, subtracting, and modifying your principles in response to change or deeper understanding is a sign that you’re probably doing things right.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;They need to be embedded into the companies core processes, hiring, performance management, planning, operating cadence, and career development.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mechanisms&quot;&gt;Mechanisms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reinforce the principles and translate them into action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;annual-planning&quot;&gt;Annual planning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 to 8 weeks of intensive work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each group develops a granular operating plan to achieve the overarching goals.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assessment of past performance, including goals achieved, goals missed, and lessons learned.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Key initiatives for the following year.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A detailed income statement.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Requests (and justifications) for resources, which may include things like new hires, marketing spend, equipment, and other fixed assets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;s-team-goals-svps-and-jeff-drs&quot;&gt;S-Team goals (SVPs and Jeff DRs)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The S-Team selects what it considers the key goals, from the teams initiatives and goals- S-Team goals. These denote priority. Mostly input metrics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They make them SMART.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sufficiently aggressive that it’s only expected to attain 3/4 of them during the year.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each undergoes quarterly review. Leaders go through the detail!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;compensation&quot;&gt;Compensation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highly equity based in order to drive long term thinking and avoid short term goals and departmental achievements at the expense of the company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hiring&quot;&gt;Hiring&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watch for urgency bias, group think, confirmation bias, personal bias.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;According to Sequoia capital, the average start-up in Silicon Valley spends 990 hours to hire 12 software engineers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brent Gleeson, a leadership coach and Navy Seal combat veteran, writes, &lt;i&gt;“organisational culture comes about in one of two ways. It’s either decisively defined, nurtured and protected from the inception of the organisation: or – more typically – it comes about haphazardly as a collective sum of the beliefs, experiences and behaviours of those on the team. Either way, you will have a culture. For better or worse.“&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-bar-raiser&quot;&gt;The bar raiser&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Job description.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resume review.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phone screen.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In-house interview.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Written feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Debrief/hiring meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reference check.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Offer through onboarding.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The bar raiser is a role. Someone specifically trained to lift the standard, train other interviewers and with veto rights.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;single-threaded-leadership&quot;&gt;Single-threaded leadership&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;System designed to support rapid innovation. A single person and encumbered by competing responsibilities, owns a single major initiative and heads up a separable, largely autonomous team to deliver its goals.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The book describes a dependency as something one team needs but can’t supply for itself.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New Project Initiatives NPI was a review, approval and ranking process for Amazons Global projects.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“The best way to fail at inventing something is by making it somebody’s part time job.“ Amazons SVP of devices, Dave Limp.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amazons approach to morale was to attract world-class talent and create an environment in which they had maximum latitude to invent and build things to delight customers – and you can’t do that if every quarter some faceless process like MPI smites your best ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;two-pizza-teams&quot;&gt;Two pizza teams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be small. No more than 10 people. They later came to the realisation that the major predictor of team success wasn’t whether it was small but it was whether it had a leader that had the appropriate skills authority and experience to staff and manager team whose sole focus was to get the job done. This is what they coined into single threaded leaders.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be autonomous no need to coordinate with other teams to get work done; the switch to micro services removed the shackles that had prevented the Amazon software teams for moving fast, and enabled them to transition to smaller autonomous teams.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be evaluated by well defined “fitness function“.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be monitored in real time.  A team’s real-time score on its fitness function would be displayed on the dashboard next to all other two pizza teams scores. This was later scrapped, it just didn’t work; instead the underlying input metrics were used.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be the business owner. Own and be responsible for all aspects of its area focus including design, technology, and business results.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be led by a multi disciplined top-flight leader. They couldn’t find enough top-flight leaders so went with a matrix organisation model where each team member has a solid line reporting relationship to functional manager and a dotted line reporting relationship to there to pizza manager.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be self funding.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be approved in advance by the S team.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each needs a purpose, boundaries of ownership, and metrics. Had a charter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two pizza teams works best in product development. It did not work as well in retail, legal, HR, and other areas because those areas did not suffer from the tangled dependencies that had hampered Amazon product development.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Separable, single threaded teams have fewer organisational dependencies than conventional teams. As a former Amazon VP aptly observed, a good rule of thumb to see if a team has sufficient autonomy is deployment-can the team build and rollout the changes without coupling, coordination, and approvals from other teams? If the answer is no, then one solution is to carve out a small piece of functionality that can be autonomous and repeat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;communicating&quot;&gt;Communicating&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The six pager
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Used to describe, review or propose just about any type of idea, process or business.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Distributed at the start of the meeting and read for the first 20 minutes. Once everyone is ready, conversation begins.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Example for a quarterly report: Intro, tenets, accomplishments, misses, proposals for next period, headcount, P&amp;amp;L, FAQ, appendices.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The PR/FAQ
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Linked to the working backwards process.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Resist the temptation to start by saying orally “let me walk you through the document”. It’s a waste of time.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Go around the room for feedback. Someone needs to take notes of the insuring discussion, as those comments will be part the output of the narrative process. Jeff Bezos consistently provides unique insights to narratives. He assumes each sentence he reads is wrong until he can prove otherwise. He is challenging the content of the sentence, not the motive of the writer.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A key part of working backwards. The press release portion is a few paragraphs always less than one page. The frequently asked questions should be five pages or less. There are no wards fixed pages or more words. The goal isn’t to explain all the excellent work you’ve done but rather to share the distilled thinking that has come from the work.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;PR
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Heading&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Subheading describing the customer of the product and what they will gain from it.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Summary paragraph&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Problem paragraph&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Solution paragraph&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Quotes and getting started&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Working backwards
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Start with the desired customer experience.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;metrics&quot;&gt;Metrics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manage your inputs, not your outputs
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;leading and lagging indicators.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The flywheel: input metrics lead to output metrics and back again.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Better customer experience leads to more traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;More traffic leads to more sellers seeking those buyers.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;More sellers lead to wider selection.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wider selection enhances customer experience, completing the circle.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The cycle drives growth, which intern lowest cost structure.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Lower costs lead to low prices, improving customer experience and the flywheel spins faster.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identify the correct, controllable input metrics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Example given of Amazon identifying new detail pages as input metrics, but leads to the wrong output- increased inventory costs rather than additional sales.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;failures&quot;&gt;Failures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fire phone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amazon Unbox-  evolved into Prime Video.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amazon Auctions and zShops developed into Amazon Marketplace.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amazon are patient. They think long term. If they believe in the customer need and they will stick at it for 5-7 years whilst most companies give up after only a couple.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Working Backwards process demands that Amazon exercise new muscles, never mind how uncomfortable and awkward feeling those first steps might be.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Over a long march to building Amazon Studios to business, we proved a powerful lesson: it takes exceptionally patient and I’m wavering leadership to persevere through the prolonged process of building a new business and navigating through transformative times in an established industry within entrenched  interests.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In digital Amazon had to venture out to different areas of the value chain in order to compete as opposed to its focus in physical retail. The three areas mapped out are content creation, aggregation, content consumption. Kindle for books. Fire devices and Amazon Studios for movies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;actions-to-take&quot;&gt;Actions to take:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ban PowerPoint, use 6 pagers with PR/FAQs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Establish the bar-raiser hiring process.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus on controllable input metrics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move to an organisational structure that accommodates autonomous teams with single threaded leaders.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Revise the compensation structure for leaders.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Articulate the core elements of the company culture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Define a set of leadership principles.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Depict your flywheel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="business" /><summary type="html">Always interesting to get insider insight into the big successful companies. Colin and Bill were at Amazon practically from the start and had front row seats. I’d heard about a bunch of Amazon’s practices so it’s interesting to read the detail and what problems they solved for Amazon. Not a ground-breaking book on ways of working, but with enough insights and background to make it worth recommending.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-assets/working-backwards.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-assets/working-backwards.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Red Notice by Bill Bowder</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/red-notice-by-bill-bowder" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Red Notice by Bill Bowder" /><published>2021-04-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/red-notice-by-bill-bowder</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/red-notice-by-bill-bowder">&lt;p&gt;An incredible telling of greed and corruption in Russia on a massive scale, all the way to the top. Bower’s book reads like a thriller but the shocking fact is that it’s true. The bravery of the individuals in exposing this is admirable and it’s hard not to be moved by the resolve of Sergei Magnitsky and the ultimate price he paid; his life. What’s in this book needs to be known.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vast Russian privatizations post communism.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vouchers issued to citizens, bought up in exchanges and used to purchase shares of Russian companies at very low rates (how he starts to make money with his hedge fund).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Many state companies valued way below comparative companies inside and outside Russia. Easily calculable value discrepancies based on assets alone, for example barrels of oil. Massive opportunity for those that could spot this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prison yard attitude in Russia. Show no weakness more important than rationality. Especially for an oligarch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1998 Russia goes into financial meltdown - his fund looses 90% from 1b to 100m.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quotes
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“Seventy years of communism had destroyed the work ethic of an entire nation. Millions of Russians had been sent to the gulags for showing the slightest hint of personal initiative. The Soviets severely penalized independent thinkers, so the natural self-preservation reaction was to do as little as possible and hope that nobody would notice you.”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“The less people know about how sausages and laws are made, the better they sleep at night.”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“After Khodorkovsky was found guilty, most of Russia’s oligarchs went one by one to Putin and said, ‘Vladimir Vladimirovich, what can I do to make sure I won’t end up sitting in a cage?’ I wasn’t there, so I’m only speculating, but I imagine Putin’s response was something like this: ‘Fifty per cent.”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="politics" /><category term="russia" /><category term="thriller" /><summary type="html">An incredible telling of greed and corruption in Russia on a massive scale, all the way to the top. Bower’s book reads like a thriller but the shocking fact is that it’s true. The bravery of the individuals in exposing this is admirable and it’s hard not to be moved by the resolve of Sergei Magnitsky and the ultimate price he paid; his life. What’s in this book needs to be known.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-assets/book-red-notice.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-assets/book-red-notice.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Theory of Constraints</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/theory-of-constraints" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Theory of Constraints" /><published>2021-04-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-04-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/theory-of-constraints</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/theory-of-constraints">&lt;p&gt;The Goal by Eliyahu Goldratt is one of my favourite business books. It’s very readable and I’d highly recommend getting it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TOC is a methodology for identifying the most important constraint standing in the way of achieving a goal (aka bottleneck); then systematically improving that constraint until it is no longer the limiting factor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-five-focussing-steps&quot;&gt;The five focussing steps&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identify the system’s constraint(s).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decide how to exploit the system’s constraint(s).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Subordinate everything else to the above decision(s).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alleviate the system’s constraint(s).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Warning! If in the previous steps a constraint has been broken, go back to step 1, but do not allow inertia to cause a system’s constraint. In other words, don’t stop!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-thinking-process---steps-for-getting-buy-in-for-initiating-improvements&quot;&gt;The thinking process - steps for getting buy-in for initiating improvements.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gain agreement on the problem&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gain agreement on the direction for a solution&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gain agreement that the solution solves the problem&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agree to overcome any potential negative ramifications&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agree to overcome any obstacles to implementation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="complexity" /><summary type="html">Methodology for systematic improvement.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/resources-assets/toc.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/resources-assets/toc.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>