<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://kaufie.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://kaufie.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-10-21T21:03:12+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/feed.xml</id><subtitle>Sasha Kaufmann's profile website and article archive.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Bold decisions, reversible</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/bold-decisions-reversible" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bold decisions, reversible" /><published>2020-10-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-10-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/bold-decisions-reversible</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/bold-decisions-reversible">&lt;p&gt;Learning how to identify decisions that can be made quickly and making them decisively can make a huge difference in your personal and business life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t rush some decisions. Most people rightly wouldn’t buy a house on the spur of the moment. Likewise in business many decisions have huge implications and take time to fully consider. The problem is that sometimes we go too far; we slow ourselves down by failing to recognise the decisions that can be made quickly. We miss out on a first mover advantage, the learning from doing and any benefit we’d be getting from the change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeff Bezos frames decisions as either “one way doors” that require careful deliberation and consultation or “two way doors”; decisions that can be reversed. Most fall into the second category. Saying that he’s been wildly successful following the model is something of an understatement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A decision that pays off will make an enormous difference, but even the aggregation of small experiments builds up to something significant. In contrast, arduous processes and cycles that consume time and resources cost a fortune and land you with the cost of delay in carrying out a change as well the loss of any benefit from the knowledge a failed experiment imparts. There’s time for fast decision making, and there’s time for careful consideration; the advantage is in knowing which to utilise in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In business a simple effort vs reward matrix can be used to decide what to focus on. They typically look like the one below. Low effort, high reward activities are no brainers, cherish these. If something requires a lot of effort but pays off well then that’s usually next in priority. Low effort and low reward activities are left to do only if there’s time to spare. High effort low reward should be left to the suckers, forget it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lead-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/Effort_Reward.png&quot; alt=&quot;Effort vs reward matrix&quot; style=&quot;max-width:100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another dimension that we need to consider is potential upside (positive) vs downside (negative). Whilst the former is essentially the reward axis, there is no representation of the potential downside on the diagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High potential upside, limited potential downside means you can proceed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High potential upside and downside means you should proceed with caution. In the most extreme circumstance you could destroy your business and/or reputation - at which point too much damage has been done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can think about effort vs reversibility in the same way and equally we need to consider potential upside and downside. An effort vs reversibility matrix allows the separation of things you need to be cautious about from things that you should just get on with. Framing decisions in this way provides a rule of thumb for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how much information to collect;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the level of consensus you need to build before implementing a change;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how long to wait before doing it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lead-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/Effort_Reversible.png&quot; alt=&quot;Effort vs reward matrix&quot; style=&quot;max-width:100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For highly reversible, low effort changes: a hunch is enough to warrant just getting on with it. Spend the minimum viable time on gathering information and building consensus. The kind of changes you tend to see here are new practices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highly reversible, high effort changes need more consideration because of the opportunity cost of the invested effort. A strong hypothesis will be needed. New policies or significant changes to a delivery approach are examples of what you might find here.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not easily reversible, low effort changes should be approached with high caution. There’s a tendency for the ease at which the decision can be made to influence rash or careless decision makers into doing lasting damage to a company or wasting resources. An example here would be poor hiring. A hire can be made at the drop of a hat, but if it turns out badly then the effort in recruitment, the time of the people they’ve met and the onboarding has been wasted and will need to be repeated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Less reversible, high effort changes require extreme caution. Think of a company deciding on a new internal accounting system. Clearly high effort to implement and difficult to back out of.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In practice I’ve used this approach to make decisions quickly which on the surface may have seemed reckless. If the changes hadn’t worked it would have been relatively easy to reverse. As an example, working in telecoms I had to respond to my team growing overnight to 18 people as we merged with another. Using Scrum the team size was far from ideal (cognitive load and the number of communication paths). We could have done nothing and trundled along. We didn’t spend weeks building consensus with stakeholders, running through process diagrams or debating every possible scenario. Almost instantaneously we decided (1) to go fully remote and (2) to work as two sub-teams with a couple of light touch processes to keep in sync. The changes happened within a week (which in a large corporate is almost instantaneous) and with the result of moving quickly there was no loss of momentum on the work in progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you start looking at decisions as either reversible or irreversible it becomes easier to be someone who makes things happen. You’ll know it when you have to dig a bit deeper to find patience with people that don’t move as fast. If something is easily reversible, you just decide and move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When something is reversible, it’s a lot easier to be bold.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="agile" /><category term="decisions" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="agility" /><category term="agile" /><summary type="html">Make decisions quickly and with confidence.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/effort_reversibility.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/effort_reversibility.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The First 90 Days by Michael Watkins</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/the-first-90-days-by-michael-watkins" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The First 90 Days by Michael Watkins" /><published>2020-09-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/the-first-90-days-by-michael-watkins</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/the-first-90-days-by-michael-watkins">&lt;p&gt;Essential reading if you’re about to start a new job in a leadership role; whether you’ve been promoted or joined a new company. The book is well structured and provides clear strategies for approaching the new challenge and setting yourself up for success. Every time I change roles, I re-read this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-notes&quot;&gt;My notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is packed with useful information. I really recommend buying a copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The root causes of transition failure lie in a pernicious interaction between the situation, with its opportunities and pitfalls, and the individual, with his or her strengths and vulnerabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are systematic methods that leaders can employ to both lessen the likelihood of failure and reach the breakeven point faster.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The goal is to &lt;strong&gt;build momentum by creating virtuous cycles that build credibility and by avoiding getting caught in vicious cycles that damage credibility.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-promote-yourself&quot;&gt;1. Promote yourself&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t assume what has made you successful at this point will continue to do so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-accelerate-your-learning&quot;&gt;2. Accelerate your learning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Climb the learning curve as fast as possible. Markets, products, technologies, systems, structures, culture and politics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Getting acquainted with a new organisation can feel like drinking from a fire hose”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be systematic and focussed about deciding what you need to learn and how you will learn it efficiently.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Planning to learn means figuring out in advance what the important questions are an how you can best answer them.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Baseline question: how did we get to this point?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Start by generating questions about the &lt;strong&gt;past&lt;/strong&gt;, questions about the &lt;strong&gt;present&lt;/strong&gt; and questions about the &lt;strong&gt;future&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An &lt;strong&gt;actionable insight&lt;/strong&gt; is knowledge that enables you to make better decisions earlier and so helps you reach the break even point in personal value sooner.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Extract actionable insights from the mass of information available to you.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Efficient - identify the best sources of insight and figure out how to extract maximum insight with the least possible outlay of time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a virtuous cycle of information gathering, analysing, hypothesising and testing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What do you most need to learn?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions about the past&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance&lt;/strong&gt;
      - How has this organisation performed in the past? How do people in the organisation think it has performed?
      - How were goals set? Were they insufficiently or overly ambitious?
      - Were internal or external benchmarks used?
      - What measures were employed? What behaviours did they encourage or discourage?
      - What happened if goals were not met?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Root causes&lt;/strong&gt;
      - If performance has been good, why has this been the case?
      - What have been the relative contributions of the organisation’s strategy, its structure, its technical capabilities, its culture and its politics?
      - If performance has been poor, why has this been the case? Do the primary issues reside in the organisation’s strategy? Its structure? Its technical capabilities? Its culture? Its politics?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;History of change&lt;/strong&gt;
      - What efforts have been made to change the org?
      - Who has been instrumental in shaping it?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the present&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vision and strategy&lt;/strong&gt;
      - What is the stated vision and strategy of the org?
      - Is it really pursuing that strategy? If no, why not? If so, is the strategy going to take the org where it needs to go?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People&lt;/strong&gt;
      - Who is capable and who isn’t?
      - Who can be trusted and who can’t?
      - Who has influence and why?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Processes&lt;/strong&gt;
      - What are the key processes in the org?
      - Are they performing acceptably in terms of quality, reliability and timeliness? If not, why not?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Land mines&lt;/strong&gt;
      - What lurking surprises could detonate and push you off track?
      - What potentially damaging cultural or political missteps must you avoid making?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early wins&lt;/strong&gt;
      - In what areas (people, relationships, processes, or products) can you achieve some early wins?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions about the future&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenges and opportunities&lt;/strong&gt;
      - In what areas is the business most likely to face stiff challenges in the coming year? What can be done now to prepare for them?
      - What are the most promising unexploited opportunities? What would need to happen to realise their potential?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barriers and resources&lt;/strong&gt;
      - What are the most formidable barriers to making needed changes? Technical? Cultural? Political?
      - Are there islands of excellence or other high quality resources that you can leverage?
      - What new capabilities need to be developed or acquired?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Culture&lt;/strong&gt;
      - Which elements of the culture should be preserved?
      - Which need to change?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of information:&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Customers&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Distributors&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Suppliers&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Outside analysts&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Frontline R&amp;amp;D and Operations&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sales and Purchasing&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Staff&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Integrators&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Natural historians&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pick up ‘Soft information’ by talking to people.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask direct reports the same 5 questions
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What are the biggest challenges the org is facing or will face in the future?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Why is the org facing or going to face these challenges?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What are the most promising unexploited opportunities for growth?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What would need to happen for the org to exploit the potential of these opportunities?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you were me, what would you focus attention on?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How people answer can tell you a lot about your new team and its politics.&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Who answers directly? Who is evasive and prone to going on tangents? Who takes responsibility and who points fingers? Who has a broad view of the business and who seems stuck in a silo.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating a learning plan&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;p50-52 provides a learning plan template. The above is what you want to learn, this is how you will learn it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning about culture&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Symbols are signs that distinguish one culture from another. Including logos or styles of dress.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Norms are shared social rules that guide behaviour. What get encouraged or rewarded? What elicits scorn or dispproval.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Assumptions are often unarticulated beliefs that underpin social systems. What truths does everyone take for granted?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;There are organisational, professional and geographic culture perspectives that often intersect.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-match-strategy-to-situation&quot;&gt;3. Match strategy to situation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Diagnosis before developing an action plan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identify which transition type your situation is:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Start up&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Turnaround&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Realignment&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sustaining success&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What you do depends on this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When clear on the situation you’ll face 3 fundamental early choices.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;How much emphasis will you place on learning as opposed to doing?
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Realignment and sustaining success - more learning. Startup or turnaround - more doing.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;How much emphasis will you place of offence as opposed to defence?
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Realignment or startup are offence. Sustaining or turnaround are defence.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What should you do to get some early wins?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-secure-early-wins&quot;&gt;4. Secure early wins&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;These build credibility and create momentum. They create virtuous cycles. Leverage the energy you’re putting in to create a sense that good things are happening.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the first few weeks identify opportunities to build credibility. In the first 90 days you need to identify ways to create value, improve business results and get to the breakeven point more rapidly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Common traps:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Failing to focus&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Not taking the business situation into account&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Not adjusting for the culture&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Failing to get wins that matter to your boss&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Letting your means undermine your ends
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;eg. being seen as manipulative or underhanded&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each wave of change consists of:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Learning&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Designing the changes&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Building support&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Implimenting the changes&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Observing results&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The point is to define your goals so you can lead with a distinct endpoint in mind.&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A-item priorities - should follow naturally from core problems.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Behaviour changes. Lack of:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Focus&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Discipline&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Innovation&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Teamwork&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Sense of urgency&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;At this stage your objective is to build personal credibility.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Craft a few messages tailored to your key audiences
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Focus on who you are, the values and goals you represent, your style and how you plan to conduct business.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Remove minor but persistent irritants:
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Redundant meetings&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Shorten excessively long ones&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Improve physical space problems&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-negotiate-success&quot;&gt;5. Negotiate success&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Figure out how to build a productive relationship with your new boss and manage their expectations.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Carefully plan critical conversations about:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Situation&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Expectation&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Style&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Resources&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Personal development&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developing and gaining consensus on your 90 day plan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fundamentals on building a productive relationship:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Don’t trash the past&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Don’t stay away&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Don’t surprise your boss&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Don’t approach your boss only with problems&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Don’t run down your checklist&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Don’t try to change the boss&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Do take 100 percent responsibility for making the relationship work&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Do clarify mutual expectations early and often&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Do negotiate timelines for diagnosis and action planning&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Do aim for early wins in areas important to the boss&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Do pursue good marks from those whose opinions your boss respects&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Plan for 5 conversations:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Situational diagnosis conversations - you seek to understand how your new boss understands the situation&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The expectations conversation&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The style conversations&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The resources conversation&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The personal development conversation&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Identify untouchables.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Educate your boss - get realistic expectations.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Underpromise and overdeliver.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Plan the conversations (p.120).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-achieve-alignment&quot;&gt;6. Achieve alignment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Org architect: figure out if the orgs strategy is sound, bring its structure into alignment with its strategy and develop the systems and skill bases necessary to realise strategic intent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 areas of org architecture need to work together:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Strategy&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Structure&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Systems&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Skills&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Culture&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identify misalignments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Common traps:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Trying to restructure your way out of deeper problems&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Creating structures that are too complex&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Automating problem processes&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Making changes for change’s sake&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Overestimating your group’s capacity to absorb strategic shifts&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting started:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Start with strategy&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Look at supporting structure, systems and skills.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Decide how and when you will introduce the new strategy&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Reshape structure, systems and skills simultaneously&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Close the loop&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Crafting strategy:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Customers&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Capital&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Capabilities&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Commitments&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shape your groups structure:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Units&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Decision rights&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Performance management and rewards systems&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Reporting relationships and information sharing mechanisms&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Initiating cultural change:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Change performance measures and incentives&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Set up pilot projects&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bring in new people&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Promote collective learning&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Engage in collective visioning&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-build-your-team&quot;&gt;7. Build your team&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select the right people for the right positions - critical for success.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoid common traps:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Keeping the existing team too long
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Rule of thumb: by the end of your first 90 days decide who shall remain and go. But end of 6 months should have been communicated to key stakeholders.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Not repairing the airplane - ie doing nothing&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Not working organisational alignment and team restructuring issues in parallel&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Not holding onto the good people&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Undertaking team building before the core team is in place:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Tempting to launch team-building activities such as joint problem solving, brainstorming and visioning right away…but poses a danger, strengthens the bond of the group.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Making implementation dependent decisions too early&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Trying to do it all yourself - get support from a good HR person&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assessing your existing team:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Competence&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Judgement&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Energy&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Focus&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Relationships&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Trust&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assign each team member the following categories:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Keep in place&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Keep and develop&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Move to another position&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Observe for a while&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Replace (low priority)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Replace (high priority)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Your direct reports will form lasting impressions of you based on how you manage this part of your job.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aligning goals, incentives and measures:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Push tools:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Incentives&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Reporting system&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Planning processes&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Procedures&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Mission statement&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pull tools:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Shared vision&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Teamwork&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decision making:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Unilateral (most leader control)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Consult-and-decide&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Build consensus&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Unanimous (least leader control)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To avoid confusion, consider explaining to direct reports what you’re using and why. Strive to run a fair process. Even if they don’t agree, they’ll support if they feel 1) that their views have been heard and taken seriously and 2) that you have given a plausible rationale for why you made the call you did&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Charade consensus building for a decision already made doesn’t fool anyone&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-create-coalitions&quot;&gt;8. Create coalitions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identify whose support is essential for your success, and figure out how to line them up on your side.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A common mistake is for leaders to focus too much on the vertical dimension of influence (bosses and DRs) and not enough on the horizontal dimension - peers and external constituencies.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Discipline yourself to invest in building relationship capital with people you anticipate needing to work with later.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identify key players. Consider creating priority relationship lists for direct reports.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Notice to whom people go for advice and insight.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sources of power:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Expertise&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Access to information&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Status&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Control of resources, such as budgets and rewards&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Personal loyalty
    - You’ll notice &lt;strong&gt;power coalitions&lt;/strong&gt;.
    - Draw an influence map - p.190
    - Appeal to core values - loyalty, commitment and contribution, individual worth and dignity, integrity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;9-keep-your-balance&quot;&gt;9. Keep your balance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The right advice and council network is indispensable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watch out for:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Riding off in all directions&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Undefended boundaries&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Brittleness&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Isolation&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Biased judgement&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Work avoidance. Need to take the bull by the horns&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Going over the top&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The 3 pillars of self-efficacy:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Adopting success strategies&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Enforcing personal disciplines:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Plan to plan&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Judiciously defer commitment&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Set aside time for hard work&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Go to the balcony - look from a high level&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Focus on process&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Check in with yourself&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Guidelines for self reflection p.215 - questions to ask yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-expedite-everyone&quot;&gt;10. Expedite everyone&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop high quality leaders
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Succession planning&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="book" /><category term="non-fiction" /><category term="careers" /><summary type="html">Essential reading if you’re about to start a new job in a leadership role; whether you’ve been promoted or joined a new company. The book is well structured and provides clear strategies for approaching the new challenge and setting yourself up for success. Every time I change roles, I re-read this book.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/first-90.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/first-90.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Don’t go there by Svetlana Oss</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/dont-go-there-by-svetlana-oss" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Don’t go there by Svetlana Oss" /><published>2020-09-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/dont-go-there-by-svetlana-oss</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/dont-go-there-by-svetlana-oss">&lt;p&gt;In 1959 nine university students were found dead in the Russian Ural mountains in mysterious circumstances. They had been on a mountaineering trip; their tent was ripped open and the bodies were found not far. Nobody knows with certainty what happened, at least not anyone who’s willing to come forward with the details. This is what’s known as “The Dyatlov Pass Incident”. Svetlana introduces us to the students, outlining their steps and the details of the macabre discovery; along the way photos and excerpts from journal entries bring this to life. We get a critique of various theories; was it an avalanche, military test, espionage, a UFO (meteor or celestial body) or an act of local tribes? Eventually this concludes with a rationale of the most likely explanation. I found the book engaging and although it’s made clear early on that there isn’t a definitive answer I was satisfied by the end that the author’s conclusion has firm grounding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No notes here, to avoid giving away the conclusion. :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="notes" /><category term="book" /><category term="non-fiction" /><category term="mystery" /><summary type="html">In 1959 nine university students were found dead in the Russian Ural mountains in mysterious circumstances. They had been on a mountaineering trip; their tent was ripped open and the bodies were found not far. Nobody knows with certainty what happened, at least not anyone who’s willing to come forward with the details. This is what’s known as “The Dyatlov Pass Incident”. Svetlana introduces us to the students, outlining their steps and the details of the macabre discovery; along the way photos and excerpts from journal entries bring this to life. We get a critique of various theories; was it an avalanche, military test, espionage, a UFO (meteor or celestial body) or an act of local tribes? Eventually this concludes with a rationale of the most likely explanation. I found the book engaging and although it’s made clear early on that there isn’t a definitive answer I was satisfied by the end that the author’s conclusion has firm grounding.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://kaufie.com/book-dont-go-there.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://kaufie.com/book-dont-go-there.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 6 - Learn</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/learn" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 6 - Learn" /><published>2020-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/learn</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/learn">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/communicate&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (Chapter 5: Communicate)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;learn&quot;&gt;Learn&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Release date TBC.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Learn.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 3 - Orient</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/forecasting" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 3 - Orient" /><published>2020-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/forecasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/forecasting">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/applying-approach-to-context&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (Applying Approach to Context)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;forecasting&quot;&gt;Forecasting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In business, we can’t predict the future - but that doesn’t stop everyone trying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;management-need-forecasts&quot;&gt;Management need forecasts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several important reasons why management need to forecast when options will be carried out and outcomes achieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shareholders want to know when they can expect a return on investment. The business will need to show an investor that the investment is worth pursuing over other opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Businesses need to know when money will start coming in:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To establish how long staff can be paid, among other fixed costs. Flows must be managed to avoid falling into financial trouble.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To know when funds will be available for other work, initiatives, products etc.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To make decisions on whether to ‘stick, twist, or fold’ on certain initiatives. If it becomes clear that the outcome isn’t worth the outlay, and the investment is better elsewhere then the sooner that decision is made the better.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst there is no getting away from the need, it’s critical to maintain an understanding that a forecast is a snapshot in time. What we’re working on may become irrelevant. It may need to change. Forecasting should be completely separate from target setting. It should be the act of providing information and probabilities to support decisions. If a forecast becomes a commitment it means that management have misunderstood the term, have integrated it with target setting, and have lost focus on the outcome in favour of the option being worked on. Use a forecast to decide, not to chastise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-do-we-forecast&quot;&gt;How do we forecast?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A forecast is what we expect to happen given what we know right now. Its most useful when it’s provided as a range and with a probability. A probabilistic forecast. Think of a weather forecast - knowing the probability of rain helps you prepare. This is as opposed to a deterministic forecast which simply points to an exact number. The more ‘known unknowns’ and ‘unknown unknowns’, the less accurate a forecast will be by definition - there’s too much left out of it. If you’re working in a Simple context, then clearly you can follow a plan, along a timeline, and have a good idea of when something will be delivered - and even the likely result - a deterministic forecast would be OK. Even this, though, could be scuppered if say, a global pandemic breaks out during the delivery. When the context becomes more Complicated, it can still follow a plan, however there will be more moving parts and therefore a greater chance of unexpected problems. In Complex contexts the future is highly uncertain and we’re being a lot more honest with ourselves if we start using ranges and probabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re working off a plan to deliver something you’ve delivered many times over, then you can provide an estimate of how long it will take based on the past experience. It took us 2 months to build X, so with the same conditions it’d take us 2 months to build another one. In other circumstances you’ll need to use data on past performance in delivery as a predictor of future delivery. This is your input. It’s crucial for management to be aware that past results can provide an indicator of future performance, but there are no guarantees that the future will play out in the same way. Unforeseen events in the business environment, the global economy and the climate can render a forecast completely irrelevant. Nassim Taleb has written extensively with regards to what he called &lt;i&gt;“Black Swan”&lt;/i&gt; events. If you were to use past performance of the economy as a predictor of the future performance, then in 2008 you would have been caught out. Delivery performance, at least in terms of past output can and should be used to forecast future output (because it’s all we’ve got). But always be open to the possibility that the future may bring something that renders previous data irrelevant. That’s why we need to build in contingency, buffers and spare capacity. This is about building resilience. Efficiency is good up to a point, however it makes you susceptible to shocks relating to events that fall outside of your expectations. Taleb deals with the effects of efficiency causing fragility his subsequent book, &lt;i&gt;Antifragile[1]&lt;/i&gt;. Optimising for efficiency removes the ability to absorb shocks. Contrast the human body’s capacity to adapt, heal and often benefit from shocks (eg. fasting), with traffic systems that are designed to a certain threshold and buckle when capacity over and above is needed. If you operate the M25 motorway at capacity, it goes no-where. Both the smooth flow of work and resistance require spare capacity; the relationship to forecasting of delivery is that the more optimised an organisation is for efficiency, the more fragile our operations and forecasts are to unforeseen events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In delivery our forecasts usually look to say when an option will be complete (that is, an output created, or an action carried out). Below you can see some of the typical ways that forecasting is done in delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;time-based-forecasting---only-for-simple-contexts&quot;&gt;Time based forecasting - only for Simple contexts&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, work items are given time estimates by people that know exactly how long the job takes. They’ve done it, it’s a known quantity and it’s suitable for traditional waterfall project management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Forecast = Critical path&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach only works if the estimates are accurate. For this to be true:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the person has had to done the work, or very similar work before.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the integration of the work done by different individuals and teams is simple, it has been done before.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the individuals doing the work and the work itself are only affected by predictable external factors. They factor these into their estimates, along with some buffer - even in Simple contexts curveballs happen. They are still subject to external factors, like illness, climate, economy etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most work in large organisations will sit outside of these criteria. Even if work has been done before, the way it integrates with other work and with other teams will often be untested. That’s why most large projects or initiatives are destined to be late and over-budget. In fact, the bigger the project the more likely it is to be over budget due to the increasing complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following forms of forecasting are based on business cadence, that is, using proxies for quantities of past work to forecast when another quantity will be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;velocity2-based-forecasting&quot;&gt;Velocity[2] based forecasting&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve already discussed the fact that Management shouldn’t use Story Points as a measure of progress since they’re too far removed from verifiable value. The more complex the context, the more unlikely it is that teams will consistently get the sizing in the right ballpark, the less reliable the forecast. But when they do achieve a good level of consistency and get the measure of how much they can do within a time period (velocity) then they can use the information to forecast when future work might be completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Deterministic forecast = (Remaining number of story points/Average Velocity)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of forecast will provide a single number - whether of sprints or a delivery date. This can quite easily be misinterpreted by management as a commitment. There’s no indication about how probable it is that it’ll be achieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we’ve discussed, since we should have delivery data, a better way to forecast is to provide a range and a probability. What’s the point of showing the deterministic forecast? I’ve done this because in some situations it may be appropriate; you may need some ‘back of the napkin’ calculations done in a hurry. You may see others doing it. It’s useful to know the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create a probabilistic forecast, you perform what’s known as a Monte Carlo simulation. Plugging in the previous velocities, the simulation will run 10,000 tests based on the data we’ve input and provide a histogram of all its results. This gives us our possibilities and the relevant probabilities. As an example, now instead of giving one date, we can say that there’s an 80 percent chance that the option will be finished by mid- July. Not only does this provide richer data, it also clearly implies that this is not a certainty. Whilst you may wish you could have an exact date, knowing the reality is much more helpful in decision making. Plenty of exact dates have been given, costly preparations made, and the dates missed. Acknowledge the uncertainty and plan for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach to forecasting hinges on the Story Points being a proxy for the lead time on work. In environments where the lead time is affected by handovers and significant wait time it will not produce a forecast worth using. How you fix this is by creating teams that can deliver end to end, which will provide greater consistency and predictability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;throughput-based-forecasting&quot;&gt;Throughput based forecasting&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This type of forecasting uses the number of items completed over a given time period (throughput). Many organisations use User Stories. I class them as a type of option. No matter what you call them, as long as there’s a relatively even distribution of sizes, throughput does provide a relatively good way to forecast future work. Again, we can forecast in this way both deterministically and probabilistically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Deterministic forecast = (Number of stories remaining / Throughput)&lt;/i&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the probabilistic forecast again you plug in the throughput data gathered over a time period and run the Monte Carlo simulation. The histogram will provide the range and probabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any type of forecast is based on past data or information. If inaccurate data is used, or the conditions change, then the forecast is likely to be much less accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I will leave you with a quote from organisational theorist Russel Ackoff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“A good deal of the corporate planning I have observed is like a ritual rain dance; it has no effect on the weather that follows, but those who engage in it think it does. Moreover, it seems to me that much of the advice and instruction related to corporate planning is directed at improving the dancing, not the weather.”[3]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use forecasts, set up a stable environment and system which will allow for some level of consistency. In doing so you will gain a much greater level of predictability. However create resilience in your organisation to ensure that any shocks are absorbed when they come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;forecasting-1&quot;&gt;FORECASTING&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Good&lt;/b&gt; - more of this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using past and current data and information to make a decision.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Separate from target setting. The forecast should indicate if you’re on track to meet the target, but not be the target.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applying the forecasting approach based on the context.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Probabilistic forecasting provides richer information and reflects reality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Bad&lt;/b&gt; - can be misused or produce negative results&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ignoring whether the domain is Simple, Complicated or Complex.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deterministic forecasting misleads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Ugly&lt;/b&gt; - bad practice in most organisational contexts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Holding teams and individuals to the forecast as if it were a commitment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Treating the forecast as a target.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[1] Taleb, Nassim Nicholas, and Nassim Nicholas Taleb. Antifragile: Things That Gain from Disorder. Incerto, Nassim Nicholas Taleb[…]. London: Penguin Books, 2013.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[2] Velocity is a term used for average number of story points “banked” by completing features over a regular time boxed cadence.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[3] Ackoff, Russell Lincoln. Creating the Corporate Future: Plan or Be Planned For. New York: Wiley, 1981. p. ix&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/respond&quot;&gt;next page (Organisational Ability: Respond) &amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Forecasting - predicting the future based on limited data..</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 5 - Communicate</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/communicate" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 5 - Communicate" /><published>2020-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/communicate</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/communicate">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/respond&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (Chapter 4: Respond)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;communicate&quot;&gt;Communicate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Release date TBC.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Communicate.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 4 - Respond</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/respond" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 4 - Respond" /><published>2020-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/respond</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/respond">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/forecasting&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (forecasting)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respond&quot;&gt;Respond&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Release date TBC.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Respond.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 2 - What to measure</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/what-to-measure" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 2 - What to measure" /><published>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/what-to-measure</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/what-to-measure">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/options-and-outcomes&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (CHAPTER 1 - Options and Outcomes)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-should-we-measure&quot;&gt;What should we measure?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Measurement is fabulous. Unless you’re busy measuring what’s easy to measure as opposed to what’s important.”[1]&lt;br /&gt;
 	&lt;i&gt;- Seth Godin (Author and entrepreneur)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the previous chapter we saw the difference between leading and lagging indicators, and what can happen if you measure something that’s only loosely aligned to your overall goals. You’d be surprised at how many leaders use other people’s metrics to assess how things are going, even when they provide little information on whether business results are being achieved or values acted upon. I’ve witnessed managers obsessing over teams’ velocity&lt;i&gt;[2]&lt;/i&gt; whilst remaining ignorant of whether it bore any relation to the business outcomes (it didn’t). But, it’s easy to measure and other teams use it, so they latched onto it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, similar organisations may be looking to achieve the same thing, and in those cases metrics may be alike. But that’s the wrong place to start. A measurement should provide information that helps you decide what to do next. It needs to take you in the direction of your goals and values. The weaker the relationship between what you’re measuring and what you actually want to achieve, the less useful that information is. Using it to decide on what to do next could mean setting off on the wrong path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is for organisations taking on progressive values, including but not limited to those shared by the Agile movement. If you’re moving in that direction, then you’ll need build the following organisation abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ability to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;ORIENT&lt;/b&gt;. Have a clear view of progress towards outcomes, so that measures can be taken to support teams to correct or change course.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;RESPOND&lt;/b&gt;. React and adapt to changing requirements, so that a firm can better compete in a complex and changing environment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;COMMUNICATE&lt;/b&gt;. Creating an environment where individuals value one another and can be open, so that problems are exposed early and the creativity and potential of people can be leveraged.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;LEARN&lt;/b&gt;. To cultivate a culture of reflection and continuous improvement throughout the organisation. Across people, process and product.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building and improving these abilities isn’t easy but it will set you up for the best possible chance of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[1] Godin, Seth. ‘Measuring without Measuring’. &lt;a href=&quot;https://seths.blog/2013/06/measuring-without-measuring/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Seth’s Blog (blog), 1 June 2013&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[2] Velocity is a metric used by some Scrum teams: the number of ‘story points’ completed within a sprint. More on this later.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/use-cases-for-metrics&quot;&gt;next page (Use Cases for Metrics) &amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Chapter 2 looks at what to measure in your organisation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 2 - What to measure</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/use-cases-for-metrics" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 2 - What to measure" /><published>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/use-cases-for-metrics</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/use-cases-for-metrics">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/what-to-measure&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (What Should we Measure?)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-cases-for-metrics&quot;&gt;Use cases for metrics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a summary of what we should measure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Common needs of managers in organisations:&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;We will look at how to:&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Ability to:&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;I want to know if we’re on track, so that I can take measures to alter our course. Correct, pivot or ditch.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Measure progress and forecast.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Orient - Chapter 3&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;I want to know and improve our ability to respond to change so that we can more quickly and effectively adapt to changing markets.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Measure and improve our agility.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Respond - Chapter 4&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;I want to increase our openness and transparency internally so that problems are exposed early and we can leverage the creativity and potential of our people.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Measure and improve openness.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Communicate - Chapter 5&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;I want to know we are evolving; improving what we are doing.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Measure and improve the culture of learning and continuous improvement.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Learn - Chapter 6&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We’ll be exploring each of these individually in detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/good-bad-ugly&quot;&gt;next page (The Good, the Bad and the Ugly) &amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Chapter 2 looks at what to measure in your organisation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CHAPTER 3 - Orient</title><link href="https://kaufie.com/understanding-context" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHAPTER 3 - Orient" /><published>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://kaufie.com/understanding%20context</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kaufie.com/understanding-context">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/orient&quot;&gt;&amp;lt; previous page (Orient)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;understanding-context&quot;&gt;Understanding context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How you deliver, and how you measure progress depends on the level of complexity of the domain you’re working in. Like the well known saying; “Horses for courses” - you need to assess the approach depending on the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In their paper &lt;i&gt;“A Leader’s Framework for Decision Making”&lt;/i&gt; David Snowden and Mary Boone introduce Cynefin[1] and the five contexts; simple, complicated, complex, chaotic and disorder. For the purposes of this book, we’re interested in the contrast between the simple, the complicated and the complex in guiding our decisions on delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;b&gt;Simple&lt;/b&gt; context is stable and predictable. This is the domain of best practice - we know what works and generally there’s one clear way of doing it. Leaders should assess the facts of the situation, categorise the work and identify the best practice that fits. An off the shelf delivery plan can be followed with accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;b&gt;Complicated&lt;/b&gt; context is the &lt;i&gt;“domain of experts”&lt;/i&gt;. Here there tend to be multiple right answers. The cause and effect relationship is clear but not to everyone, which is why this domain has specialists who may advise on differing good practice. For this reason after assessing facts, analysis is needed in order to find a solution. A good way to picture the complicated context is as a machine. A driver may notice a problem, but it would take a mechanic to diagnose it. Although not straightforward for the average driver, there are manuals documenting every inch of the car  and the mechanic should be able to take it apart and put it back together. In delivery, with the right expertise complicated work follows a plan, but the more components there are, the greater need there is for regular integration to ensure the end result will work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;b&gt;Complex&lt;/b&gt; context is &lt;i&gt;“emergent”&lt;/i&gt;. There are no known answers. We need to probe - run some experiments - try some approaches, sense the impact these have made, and respond based on what we’ve learned. It requires patience and toleration of failure so that the right approach emerges, which leads to the results. For the contrast between complex and complicated, view the complex as more like an ecosystem. Changes in climate or the removal of one part of an ecosystem can have big, hard to predict knock on effects. We’ll see that more often organisations are situated in the complex context. A plan to take us to the outcome cannot exist in this context as by definition, the right way will need to be discovered with a test and learn approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contexts border upon each other, and problems occur when a mis-categorisation leads to the wrong approach. An expert may apply their good practice on a complex context that requires a more iterative, trial and error process. This can lead to massive waste and failure to achieve the goal. We cannot accurately predict the result of our actions when dealing with the Complex, which is why we must test and learn. The Agile and Business consultancy industry is full of well meaning individuals with &lt;i&gt;“man with a hammer syndrome”[2]&lt;/i&gt; when the same solution (usually an off the shelf scaling framework) is applied to every problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[1] Snowden, D. J., and M.E. Boone. ‘A Leader’s Framework for Decision Making’. Harvard Business Review 85, no. 11 (2007): 68–76.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[2] “..it is tempting, if the only tool you have is a hammer, to treat everything as if it were a nail.” - Abraham Maslow in The Psychology of Science: A Reconnaissance (1966)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/applying-approach-to-context&quot;&gt;next page (Applying Approach to Context) &amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sash</name></author><category term="organisational-abilities" /><category term="measurement" /><summary type="html">Developing the organisational ability to Orient.</summary></entry></feed>